<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jb:JustificationBook xmlns:jb="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/jb" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
    <jb:Title>Justification Book</jb:Title>
    <jb:BudgetYear>2013</jb:BudgetYear>
    <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
    <jb:SubmissionDate>2012-02</jb:SubmissionDate>
    <jb:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Technical Information Center</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
    <jb:AppropriationCode>0400</jb:AppropriationCode>
    <jb:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</jb:AppropriationName>
    <jb:CoverPage/>
    <jb:ExternalDocuments>
        <jb:UserR1Doc>
            <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit R-1</jb:Title>
            <jb:FileName>DTIC R-1 2012.pdf</jb:FileName>
        </jb:UserR1Doc>
    </jb:ExternalDocuments>
    <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        <jb:ForceEvenPages>true</jb:ForceEvenPages>
        <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>
        <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>
        <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>
        <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>
    </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
    <r2:R2ExhibitList xmlns:r2="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/r2" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
        <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElement>
                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0605801KA</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Defense Technical Information Center</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                <r2:R1LineItemNumber>158</r2:R1LineItemNumber>
                <r2:BudgetYear>2013</r2:BudgetYear>
                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                <r2:SubmissionDate>2012-02</r2:SubmissionDate>
                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Technical Information Center</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>6</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>RDT&amp;E Management Support</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                    <r2:PriorYear>57.790</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>56.269</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>55.454</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>55.454</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>54.232</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>53.793</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>52.623</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>53.520</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Defense Technical Information Center (DTIC) is the hub of DoD Scientific and Technical Information interchanges, empowering innovators with greater efficiency, effectiveness, and agility by accelerating the delivery of warfighting technology.  Located at Fort Belvoir, Virginia, DTIC leverages DoD’s substantial investment in scientific and technical research and development by facilitating the transfer of scientific, technical and program information throughout the national defense community.  The DTIC program generates a significant return on investment within the Department, as DTIC products and services represent a force multiplier within the S&amp;T community.  Employing efficient information organization, discovery, and delivery processes, DTIC reduces research costs and supports effective acquisition decision-making throughout the Department, and ultimately improves the technological superiority of the American warfighter. DTIC develops and maintains centralized information systems that collect, process, retrieve, and disseminate scientific and technical (S&amp;T) information. By combining advanced knowledge management techniques with new information technologies, DTIC serves as the Department's agile information provider, delivering innovative discovery, collaboration and analysis products and services that support DoD program managers, acquisition professionals, warfighters, scientists, and engineers, as well as other government agencies, US allies, and DoD’s academic and private sector partners.  With a modest funding level, DTIC serves as an efficiency enabler, providing products and services in support of federal-wide collaboration, facilitating the elimination of redundant research efforts and reducing the traditional reliance on conferences and travel as a means of connecting with professional colleagues.
The DTIC mission is tied specifically to warfighting technologies, investments, and expenditures.  With efficiencies being demanded of DoD, DTIC saves the Department money by bringing technology to bear to improve communication across DoD, between the DoD Labs and the COCOMs, and between Industry and DoD.   DTIC increases the return on investment of DoD’s research dollars, encouraging reuse of existing data.   DTIC supports researchers and developers who create the technologies that support the warfighter’s mission and saves lives. 
Recent innovative products and services include:
- “DoDTechSpace Limited and Classified Collaboration Tools” – These collaboration tools are similar to LinkedIn and FaceBook. The limited-access site will facilitate collaboration between Defense Laboratories, the Services, COCOM S&amp;T Advisors/Staffs and the DoD Research and Engineering (R&amp;E) Community. The classified site will enhance the COCOM Capability Gap Analysis process, which is specifically focused on Science and Technology Integrated Priority Lists (STIPLs). This will also enable the DoD R&amp;E community to openly discuss capability gaps and reach out to the broad community for Proposed Solutions/Mitigation Strategies.  Both the limited-access and classified DoDTechSpace will be enhanced through the ability to locate experts, post questions for discussion and explore the DTIC collections for relevant emerging candidate programs.
- “DoDTechipedia Limited and Classified Wikis” - The limited-access wiki supports collaborative research and knowledge sharing within the DoD and throughout the Federal research and acquisitions communities. Launched October 1, 2008, DoDTechipedia annually serves over 600,000 page views to registered users. The classified wiki also supports capability gap discussions in a more restricted environment.  The DoDTechipedia Limited Wiki has been featured on the White House Innovations Gallery and was selected for the 2009 Government Computer News Outstanding Information Technology Award.  DTIC is moving this DoD R&amp;E information entry point into a highly collaborative tool focused on communities of interest.
- “DTIC Online Access Controlled and Classified Interfaces” – These Access Controlled and Classified versions of the DTIC Online customer interfaces serve as the gateway to provide users one-stop access to research and engineering information, budget analysis tools, science and technology strategic planning documents, and advanced searching capabilities.
- “Aristotle” – Implemented in production at DTIC, and developed by Air Force Research Laboratory (AFRL), Aristotle is a limited access relationship discovery tool; it provides users with the ability to discover where current research is being conducted, review completed project outcomes, and identify subject matter experts.  Aristotle is an additional tool in the DoDTechipedia Suite of Services.  Aristotle has been featured on the White House Innovations Gallery.

Approximately 30,000 eligible individuals, representing hundreds of organizations (military, federal, industry, and academia), are registered to access DTIC’s information. DTIC's public and access controlled Websites average 32 million page requests per month. DTIC develops and hosts over 70 Websites, collaboration tools and other applications for DoD Component organizations including the Joint Chiefs of Staff, Assistant Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering (ASD(R&amp;E)), Defense Logistics Agency (DLA), several Combatant Commands (COCOMs), and the Federal Voting Assistance Program. The Information Analysis Center (IAC) Program Office at DTIC provides core funding, management and oversight for 10 IACs. The IACs are chartered by DoD to collect, analyze, and disseminate worldwide scientific and technical information in specialized fields such as information assurance, chemical/biological defense, and weapons systems technology. IACs support the acquisition community, prevent unnecessary duplication of research and promote standardization of research methods and processes.  The IAC funding level represents the Department’s approved customer cost sharing methodology in accordance with the Economy Act and DoD regulations.
This Program Element (PE) supports DTIC mission operations, to include four core integrated functions:  Research Support &amp; Library Repository, Web Services &amp; Hosting, Collaboration, and Information Analysis Centers (IACs).  Mission funding provides for salaries and benefits of government civilian personnel assigned to DTIC; training, professional development, and travel for DTIC personnel; facility-related requirements; support agreements for Defense Finance and Accounting Service (DFAS) financial activities and Human Resource (HR) services, Defense Information Services Agency (DISA) communications support; annual maintenance and licensing requirements; supplies, equipment, Hardware/Software; and support contracts for Information Technology services, Defense Agencies Initiative (DAI) system integration, and Chief Financial Officer (CFO) Act compliance efforts.  In addition, this PE provides funding in support of the Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) and Small Business Technology Transfer (STTR) programs, in accordance with Public Law No: 111-251 (Small Business Reauthorization Act) and Small Business Technology Transfer Program Reauthorization Act.  Within the PE, an annual set-aside contribution totaling approximately $400 Thousand is provided to the Department's Commercialization Pilot Program, as directed by the Department's Office of Small Business Programs (OSBP).
</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>61.054</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>56.269</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>56.015</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>56.015</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>57.790</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>56.269</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>55.454</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>55.454</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                        <r2:PriorYear>-3.264</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>-0.561</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-0.561</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>Congressional Directed Reductions</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>-2.500</r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>DoD Initiatives</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>-3.115</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-3.115</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>Program Changes</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>2.500</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>2.500</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>Other Program Changes</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>-0.764</r2:PriorYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>-0.019</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-0.019</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>Economic Adjustments</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.073</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.073</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                    </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                    <r2:SummaryExplanation>Specific changes to the FY 2013 program (net reduction of $0.561 Million) are outlined below:

DoD Initiatives:   - $3.115 Million decrease of FY 2013 budget authority in compliance with the Department’s efforts to reduce programs.  The reduction reflects a reshaping of planned contract support activities in areas such as Information Technology (IT) services, maintenance, etc.; streamlining of Support Agreement facility and contracting services; expanded utilization of new collaborative technologies, tools and distance training/learning; and new processes supporting the dissemination of Scientific and Technical information.

Program Changes:  $2.500 Million in support of the Department’s Discovery, Analysis, and Collaboration Support Tools.  This change to the program supports integration efforts and the development and implementation of additional features for the DoDTechipedia Suite of Services on both NIPRNET and SIPRNET.  Specifically, this effort includes:  enhancing a single user profile across DTIC products and features; enabling access by non-DoD Federal workforce to DTIC collections via the Personal Identification Verification (PIV) card; building out of WebServices interfaces to support federation across the DTIC collaboration tools and collections, and allowing DTIC users to access other DoD and non-DoD resources and tools.  This effort will expand DTIC's user community by reducing the level of subject matter domain expertise needed to rapidly identify and act on relevant data and expand the material accessible, thus opening DTIC collections more broadly among technology customers, to include Warfighters, Combatant Commands, Acquisition, and Logistics communities, and technology providers within the Science and Technology (S&amp;T) and Research, Development, Test and Evaluation (RDT&amp;E) communities.

Other Program Changes:  -$0.019 Million of reductions to travel, printing and reproduction accounts within the program.

Economic Adjustments:  $0.073 Million in funding change reflects revised economic assumptions based on anticipated inflation rates associated with both pay and non-pay accounts.
</r2:SummaryExplanation>
                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:ProjectList>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Defense Technical Information Center</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:PriorYear>48.499</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>49.216</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>48.401</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>48.401</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>47.179</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>46.740</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>45.570</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>46.467</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>As the leader of the DoD’s scientific and technical information (STINFO) program, DTIC has the responsibility to develop, coordinate and enable a strong STINFO program for the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering (ASD(R&amp;E)) and the DoD Scientific &amp; Technical (S&amp;T) enterprise.  In its role as the DoD STINFO Manager, DTIC sets and enables policy for scientific and technical information exchanges for the research and engineering community.  DTIC’s aim is to maximize the availability and use of technical information and products resulting from Defense-funded technical activities while ensuring restrictions in national security, export control, and intellectual property rights are safeguarded.
It is DoD policy to establish and maintain a coordinated and comprehensive program to document the results and outcome of DoD-sponsored and performed research and engineering (R&amp;E) and studies, and to provide access to those efforts in an effective manner, in order to make efficient use of the investment that taxpayers have previously made in R&amp;E.  In the 21st Century, supporting the S&amp;T and RDT&amp;E communities requires that DTIC integrate, more than ever, our collections with databases, information links, utilizing the latest information technology, whether in-house or outside of our Department, regardless of the source. DTIC, as the central repository for the DoD-funded current and completed research, brings efficiencies to the Department as users can gather information from many sources with one search.  DTIC’s customers, from the individual researcher to the acquisition professional, can quickly fuse information into the most complete picture needed in a matter of minutes to hours; not days to months.  DTIC accomplishes its mission to provide critical scientific, technical and related program information by performing the activities described in the three core integrated functions below:

1.  RESEARCH SUPPORT AND LIBRARY REPOSITORY.  This activity represents a world-class library with exceptional librarians capable of providing targeted research quickly.  DTIC offers the STI community an authoritative source of information, including protecting the material according to its dissemination limitations.  DTIC is the information repository from which new technologies arise.  DTIC’s repository allows DoD to reuse the research in which it already invested its money, leveraging prior research to maximize R&amp;D dollars.   DTIC’s data also provides identification of how DoD R&amp;D dollars were invested and the resulting outcomes. 
Working with classification/declassification experts across the DoD, the U.S. Government and affiliates, DTIC obtains the latest document classification and dissemination information. DTIC leads the DoD in the implementation of a new marking/protection scheme for unclassified sensitive information, now called Controlled Unclassified Information (CUI), and is exploring how these changes will affect all of our automated validation and registration systems.

2.  COLLABORATION.  DTIC is at the center of the Research &amp; Engineering hub, connecting users, data and subject matter experts in meaningful ways.  As the DoD S&amp;T information hub, DTIC provides the technology and tools to promote collaboration, integration and innovation--in real time--among the entire DoD enterprise and its partners.  Through DTIC's collaborative tools, the Department entrusts DTIC to forge critical linkages, or paths, between and amongst the various Service Laboratories, COCOMs, Federally Funded Research and Development Centers (FFRDCs), Industry/Academia, connecting diverse communities of interest to the critical research data maintained in the Department's designated Science &amp; Technology repository.  The value of scientific research lies not only in the knowledge it adds, but also in the ideas it leads to when shared.  Access to information enables creative and new technologies, methods and approaches to researchers in government and business, alike.  DTIC’s collaborative yet secure technologies assist researchers by connecting them with others and permitting them to tap into networks similar to those seen in social media.  By sharing knowledge more quickly, easily and securely, the DoD community can accelerate innovation in technologies which will benefit the warfighter.  Recognizing that information technology and information usage demands continually evolve, DTIC works within DoD and industry to leverage existing tools and pilot new capabilities and approaches to improve information discovery, analysis, and collaboration--connecting teams and people across the enterprise. To avoid duplication of efforts and increase information sharing, DTIC partners with DoD and other federal government organizations to provide federated access to information resources and tools. As relevant research and engineering and S&amp;T information is stored at organizations across the Department, DTIC will expand its collections, virtually, by helping users leverage remote collections. DTIC will work to federate access to users through identity management agreements, or by exploiting remote collections through search crawlers, abstracts, links, and other references.  Traditionally, the R&amp;E community has worked in small geographically clustered teams and then shared information broadly through publishing reports on completed work. Internet technologies have changed the paradigm. Web 2.0 collaboration and professional networking technologies bring scientific investigation and research and development to an inflection point. Small geographically collocated teams, with limited resources and unique perspectives, will combine with other teams around the globe, bringing a diversity of perspectives and experiences to bear on problems to develop new solutions quickly and with increased innovation. Collaboration tools have the additional opportunity for the solution provider to fully engage the warfighter and decision makers; allowing those working on the solution to connect with those presenting the challenge/problem.  In partnership with ASD(R&amp;E) Communities of Interest, such as Modeling &amp; Simulation; Rapid Prototyping; High Performance Computing; Basic Research &amp; laboratory programs; and Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics (STEM); to name a few; DTIC continues to enhance our collaborative suite of services, complementing our core repositories with advanced search to empower users in the Defense community to quickly recognize where resources are being applied, expertise exists, the state of the art happens, and most importantly, the art of the possible, as decision makers at all levels work to field solutions to near-, mid- and long-term warfighter needs.

3.  WEB SERVICES AND SITE HOSTING.  Within this activity, DTIC develops customized information solutions and hosts applications that support DoD Components. The jointly developed information collection, collaboration and analysis projects facilitate components’ goals to improve DoD acquisition decision-making, increase collaborative research and development efforts, facilitate business processes, and provide improved support for the warfighter. DTIC hosts over 70 public, limited and classified web-based information systems for DoD Components.  Customers include such organizations as: Joint Chief of Staff (JCS), Assistant Secretary of Defense for Research &amp; Engineering (ASD(R&amp;E)), Office of the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) (OUSD(C)), and the Combatant Commands.  Notable web-hosting development efforts include the Federal Voter Assistance Program (FVAP), providing voter access to U.S. citizens across the world; the OSD-Comptroller’s R-2 application, a Department-wide effort to standardize appropriated budget information for submission to Congress; and Science Mathematics and Research for Transformation (SMART) Scholarship for Service Program, providing scholarships to colleges and universities in an effort to recruit, develop and retain the next generation of personnel in the science, mathematics and research fields for the Department of Defense.
</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Technical Information Center</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>48.499</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>- In coordination with ASD(R&amp;E), DTIC designed a new Independent Research and Development (IR&amp;D) data entry portal and database, DefenseInnovationMarketplace.mil, as part of the Department’s Better Buying Power Initiative.  The IR&amp;D site will give the DoD greater visibility of Industry’s IR&amp;D investments and work performed.
- In coordination with ASD(R&amp;E), DTIC designed a new Unified Research and Engineering Database (URED) and data entry portal.  The goal of the URED is to provide a unified data collection, reporting and analysis process for ongoing R&amp;E activities and combine past R&amp;E and Research Summary databases and reports.  This effort will provide DoD with a view of currently funded R&amp;E projects performed by in-house DoD, contractors or grantees, and the facilities in the DoD Laboratories that perform the work.  This information is essential to the management the DoD research budget. The database will reduce the number of data calls by allowing the field to submit data on continuous basis as the research progresses, saving overhead to the DoD Laboratories.
- Obtained, created metadata for, and placed online the outputs of DoD funded R&amp;E information.  Ensured each item was available to the widest audience compatible with its dissemination limitations.  Available and findable data on R&amp;E is essential to enhance new research, and avoid duplication of research.
- Implemented web-based interface for the Electronic Document Management System (EDMS), the workflow system to create metadata and store completed the output of DoD funded R&amp;E information.  Good metadata creation allows searchers to target data better and permits implementation of analysis and semantic search tools.  An added benefit to the new workflow system is the streamlining of document processing steps.
- Developed a reporting and analysis visualization tool to allow for the review of ongoing Research and Engineering (R&amp;E) efforts, budget trends, demographic and sustainment trends within the Department of Defense (DoD).
- Implemented digitization on demand of legacy research documents, placing them online.  These documents are requested by DTIC users; placing them online allows older research to be used for new applications.
- Converted over 200,000 documents via Optical Character Recognition so that they could be fully indexed online.  In addition, Personally Identifiable Information (PII) was removed from the documents.
- Added over 30,000 new Scientific and Technical Information reports to the DTIC collection.  Continued to identify and acquire government information collections for dissemination and preservation in the DTIC technical report collection.
- Made Security Classification Guide Index available online, enabling the DoD community current security marking levels for specific topics.
- Updated DoD Scientific and Technical Information (STI) Program (STIP) Instructions in collaboration with DoD agencies and services.  Provided advice and guidance to DoD activities on policy interpretation and implementation.
- Served as an active member of interagency and public/private S&amp;T information organizations, which share best practices and technologies, including areas such as intellectual property rights, use of metadata, distribution limitations and content management.
- Increased outreach to Combatant Commands, providing research of access controlled and classified resources and offering customized training and reference support for military exercises.
- Deployed DoDTechSpace, a Facebook™-like capability on the SIPRNET to serve as the gateway to all DTIC online products and services to enhance COCOM collaboration, communication and effectiveness with the greater DoD S&amp;T Community.  Provided training and content for DoDTechSpace and Aristotle to promote collaboration and information sharing among the Science and Technology (S&amp;T) community.
- Continued to facilitate OSD Comptroller capabilities to automate the budget submission process utilizing Extensible Markup Language (XML) capabilities.
- Continued to improve search features to allow all DTIC customers to better search the DTIC collection repository at lower cost to the taxpayer.
- Continued to improve user registration tools, enhancing ease of access.  Continued efforts to implement appliance search engines, as well as the initiation of full-text search capabilities of Technical Reports.
- Investigated key technologies for connecting with mobile end-users.
- Participated in DoD Controlled Unclassified Information (CUI) working groups and prepared for the implementation of the new government-wide CUI markings.
- Continued implementation and integration of Defense Agencies Initiative (DAI) system upgrades, functional enhancements, software updates, and business process changes throughout both the DTIC enterprise and partnering organizations.
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>49.216</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>- Implement additional features and content to the IR&amp;D site, Defense Innovation Marketplace.   Initiate first annual data call to industry on IR&amp;D investments. Place data online for DoD Program Managers and Program Executive Offices to use.
- Initiate first annual data call for the Unified R&amp;E Database (URED), a continuous reporting tool.  Create an online database for use by OSD, Program Managers, scientists and engineers.
- Design a new database combining the DTIC Technical Reports database with the IAC-generated Total Electronic Migration Systems (TEMS) database.
- Develop and launch DoDTechSpace gateway to all DTIC online products and services to provide access to and capability for registered users to update central profile.
- Continue to improve user registration tools, enhancing ease of access for not only DoD staff, but also federal government employees and their contractors.
- Update DoD Scientific and Technical Information (STI) Program (STIP) Instructions in collaboration with DoD agencies and services.  Provide advice and guidance to DoD activities on policy interpretation and implementation.
- Increase outreach to Combatant Commands, providing research of access controlled and classified resources and offering customized training and reference support for military exercises.
- Continue to implement business intelligence tools for budget analysis for OSD Comptroller.
- Expand outreach to new customer segments within ASD(R&amp;E), DoD Laboratories, acquisition functions, industry, and the broader RDT&amp;E community.
- Coordinate access to DoD S&amp;T information and collaborative tools for users with approved mobile devices.
- Prepare for the implementation of the new government-wide Controlled Unclassified Information (CUI) markings.
- Continue implementation and integration of Defense Agencies Initiative (DAI) system upgrades, functional enhancements, software updates, and business process changes throughout both the DTIC enterprise and partnering organizations.
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>48.401</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>48.401</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>- Continue critical enhancements on DoDTechSpace gateway to provide central, federated search capabilities across all DTIC online products and services to include Technical Reports database, DoDTechipedia, URED, Independent Research and Development (IR&amp;D), etc.
 -- This developmental effort will leverage and optimize available technology as a means to combine and merge information resources from multiple sources, connecting and linking disparate databases to create innovative and useful information products for DTIC users.
 -- When complete, these efforts will result in the synthesis and visualization of key technical information for DTIC stakeholders, offering user communities real-time decision support content within a single representation:  a complete, interconnected picture of relevant technical reports, budgetary and program information, Laboratory and industry subject matter experts, Science &amp; Technology Integrated Priority Lists (STIPLs), all tied together with agile open search and collaboration capabilities.
- Implement additional features and content to the IR&amp;D site, Defense Innovation Marketplace.  Add new sources of data, such as small business information, to Defense Innovation Marketplace site, so DoD can examine the state of industry R&amp;D in one federated search.  Create search interface for both industry metrics and for program offices to learn about industry R&amp;D for planning where DoD should target expenditures.  Initiate first annual data call to industry on IR&amp;D investments.  Place data online for DoD Program Managers and Program Executive Offices to use.
- Expand the Unified R&amp;E Database (URED) as a continuous data call collection tool.  Enhance the online database for use by OSD, Program Managers, scientists and engineers.
- Continue to expand the capabilities of the reporting and analysis visualization tool for the unclassified/limited user community and implement a reporting and analysis visualization tool for the classified user community.
- Update DoD Scientific and Technical Information (STI) Program (STIP) Instructions in collaboration with DoD agencies and services.  Provide advice and guidance to DoD activities on policy interpretation and implementation.
- Continue outreach to Combatant Commands, providing research of access controlled and classified resources and offering customized training and reference support for military exercises.
- Continue to implement business Intelligence tools for budget analysis for OSD Comptroller.
- Begin a pilot program to implement the new government-wide Controlled Unclassified Information (CUI) markings, which will impact the creation, handling, and storage of all unclassified sensitive information.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>Research Support and Library Repository
1) Total Scientific and Technical Information (STI) Collected (Technical Reports (TRs), Unified R&amp;E Database (URED), Independent Research and Development (IR&amp;D), and TEMS (Total Electronic Migration System)
2) Total STI Disseminated (TRs, Digitization Requests, IR&amp;D Usage, National Defense Industrial Association (NDIA), TEMS downloads, and IAC Web Inquiries)
3) Total Records in four databases (TR, URED, IR&amp;D, and TEMS)

Collaboration
1) New Registered Users
2) Total Active Users

Web Services and Site Hosting
1) Web Page Requests and Total Requests for each sponsored site
2) Total Web Page Requests by customer hosted sites
</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>002</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Information Analysis Centers</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:PriorYear>9.291</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>7.053</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.053</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.053</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>7.053</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>7.053</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>7.053</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>7.053</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>DoD Information Analysis Centers (IACs) serve as a vital resource in providing timely, relevant information directly to users when and where it is needed.  IACs serve as a bridge between the Warfighter and the Acquisition/Research community, providing essential technical analysis and data support to a diverse customer base, to include the Combatant Commands, the Office of the Secretary of Defense, Defense Agencies, and the Military Services.  IACs actively partner and collaborate with Defense Research &amp; Engineering focus groups and communities of interest in areas of specialized fields or specific technologies.  IACs, established under DoD Instruction 3200.14, create and maintain comprehensive knowledge analysis centers that include historical, technical, scientific, and other data and information collected worldwide.  They are staffed with scientists, engineers and information specialists to provide research and analysis to customers with diverse, complex and challenging requirements.  IAC operations directly support the warfighter, and play an ongoing and critical role in solving key COCOM operational issues such as cyber security, IED defeat and helicopter survivability.  The IAC Program Management Office at DTIC performs contract acquisition, management, and operational support for IAC contract operations and the technical information that is generated as a result of research and studies conducted.  In a time of shrinking budgets and increasing responsibility, IACs are a valuable resource for accessing Scientific and Technical Information culled from efforts to solve new and historic challenges.
Direct IAC customer support activities, such as Technical Area Task (TAT) order processing, Basic Center Operations (BCO) support, Defense Finance and Accounting Service (DFAS) activities, contracting/acquisition related activities, etc., are funded in part through partnerships with the Defense Research &amp; Engineering community and the annual collection of customer reimbursements for shared direct costs, in accordance with the IAC Reimbursable Review Board (IRRB) recommendations, with OSD-COMPT and Office of General Counsel concurrence.  This represents the maximum cost-sharing with IAC customers allowable, per guidance from the OSD Office of General Counsel.  Annual IAC efforts and accomplishments are dependent on the level of participation and collaboration by the R&amp;E community at large.
</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Information Analysis Centers</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>9.291</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>- Contributed to OASD(R&amp;E)’s four imperatives, while enhancing IAC partnership with OASD(R&amp;E) on areas of common interest through participation in focus groups, communities of interest, and other Reliance 21 initiatives.
- Provided information and analytical support to Cyber Security and Advanced Materials Communities of Interest (COI); engaged Advanced Materials COI members in governance process for Advanced Materials IAC
- Provided administrative oversight and operational management of DTIC-sponsored IACs.
- Refined business processes, improving efficiency within the Program and maximizing value-per-dollar for our customers by providing innovative approaches, streamlined processes and alignment with new policies
- Provided basic core contract operations for DoD IACs to collect, analyze, synthesize and disseminate worldwide Scientific and Technical Information (STI) in support of DoD's critical technologies and the warfighter.
- Responded to over 7,100 technical inquiries and provided in-depth S&amp;T analysis; created and provided over 7.5 million STI results via IAC websites; captured over 41,000 STI  products from new/on-going analysis tasks; and supported the exchange of information among members of the operational and technical communities.
  -- For example, authored a first-of-its-kind DoD energy handbook for facility managers to assess and evaluate options for strategies to achieve targets for energy efficiency and use of alternative sources 
- Established presence on social media, including 22-week Armed with Science blog initiative, leading to a radio interview and participation on a panel addressing the use of social media to support mission objectives across DoD
- Exceeded metrics goals in all 15 key performance areas.
- Codified and begin executing acquisition strategy for Basic Center Operations contracts for the entire scope of the IAC Program, as well as new scope areas of emerging importance to the Department.
- Established and began executing acquisition strategy for Homeland Defense and Defense Systems Indefinite Delivery Indefinite Quantity Multiple Award Contracts (IDIQ MAC) for Technical Area Tasks (TATs).
- Managed and supported TATs ordered by the DoD and non-DoD customers, including all 10 Combatant Commands; provided program strategy and ensured alignment with Department goals/direction.
- Provided mechanism for operational users to leverage existing information to solve new and historic challenges (for example, IACs provided recommendations to optimize maintenance for Mine Resistant Ambush Protected vehicles that, if fully implemented, will enable a cost avoidance of over $7 billion over the life of the systems).
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>7.053</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>- Provide administrative oversight and basic core contract operations for DoD IACs to collect, analyze, synthesize and disseminate worldwide Scientific and Technical Information (STI) in support of DoD's critical technologies and the warfighter. 
- Provide in-depth analysis services and create STI products, in response to anticipated and real-time needs of the operational and technical community.
- Respond to technical inquiries and provide in-depth S&amp;T analysis; create and provide STI results via IAC websites; capture STI products from new/on-going analysis tasks; and support the exchange of information among members of the operational and technical communities.
- Continue executing acquisition strategy for Basic Center Operations contracts for the entire scope of the IAC Program, as well as new scope areas of emerging importance to the Department.
- Award Cyber Security IAC contract.
- Gain PEO approval of acquisition strategy for Homeland Defense TAT IDIQ.
- Release Request For Proposals for Homeland Defense IDIQ for TATs.
- Manage and support TATs ordered by the DoD and non-DoD customers, including all 10 Combatant Commands; provide program strategy and ensure alignment with Department goals/direction.
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>7.053</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>7.053</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>- Provide administrative oversight and basic core contract operations for DoD IACs to collect, analyze, synthesize and disseminate worldwide Scientific and Technical Information (STI) in support of DoD's critical technologies and the warfighter. 
- Respond to technical inquiries and provide in-depth S&amp;T analysis; create and provide STI results via IAC websites; capture STI products from new/on-going analysis tasks; and support the exchange of information among members of the operational and technical communities.
- Continue executing acquisition strategy for Basic Center Operations contracts for the IAC Program.
- Award contracts for Homeland Defense and Defense Systems IACs.
- Complete transition to new IAC Program contract structure utilizing Indefinite Delivery Indefinite Quantity Multiple Award contracts.
- Manage and support TATs ordered by the DoD and non-DoD customers, including all 10 Combatant Commands; provide program strategy and ensure alignment with Department goals/direction.
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>Information Analysis Centers:  Number of IAC technical inquiries.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                </r2:ProjectList>
            </r2:ProgramElement>
        </r2:R2Exhibit>
    </r2:R2ExhibitList>
</jb:JustificationBook>