<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jb:JustificationBook xmlns:jb="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/jb" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
    <jb:Title>Justification Book</jb:Title>
    <jb:BudgetYear>2015</jb:BudgetYear>
    <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
    <jb:SubmissionDate>2014-03</jb:SubmissionDate>
    <jb:ServiceAgencyName>DoD Human Resources Activity</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
    <jb:AppropriationCode>0400</jb:AppropriationCode>
    <jb:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</jb:AppropriationName>
    <jb:CoverPage/>
    <jb:ExternalDocuments>
        <jb:UserR1Doc>
            <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit R-1</jb:Title>
            <jb:FileName>DHRA RDT&amp;E R-1C1.pdf</jb:FileName>
        </jb:UserR1Doc>
    </jb:ExternalDocuments>
    <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>
        <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>
        <jb:GenerateP1>true</jb:GenerateP1>
        <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>
        <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>
        <jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>true</jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>
    </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
    <r2:R2ExhibitList xmlns:r2="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/r2" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
        <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElement>
                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0603769SE</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Distributed Learning Advanced Technology Development (ADL)</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                <r2:R1LineNumber>64</r2:R1LineNumber>
                <r2:BudgetYear>2015</r2:BudgetYear>
                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                <r2:SubmissionDate>2014-03</r2:SubmissionDate>
                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>DoD Human Resources Activity</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>3</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Advanced Technology Development (ATD)</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                    <r2:AllPriorYears>27.048</r2:AllPriorYears>
                    <r2:PriorYear>10.956</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>12.116</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>10.692</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>10.692</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>10.808</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>10.900</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>10.897</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>11.063</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>Established by Executive Order, with policy oversight by the Office of the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense/Readiness (Training Readiness and Strategy), this program leverages emerging learning technologies to provide cost effective training and education to employees and Service members of the Federal Government.  

The mission of the ADL Initiative is to provide access to the highest-quality education, training, and performance aiding tailored to individual needs and delivered cost-effectively. The ADL Initiative is a DoD program responsible for research and development of distributed and networked learning technologies, to include: online courseware, training games, virtual worlds, and mobile technology.  ADL developed the Sharable Content Object Reference Model (SCORM, the de facto industry and internationally accepted standard for e-learning interoperability.  It is mandated for all Department of Defense (DoD) agencies through DoD Instruction 1322.26.  The ADL initiative, working with ADL Partnership Co-Labs and the NATO community, has reduced costs and increased interoperability and sharing of distributed learning content, enabling discovery, retrieval, and reuse.  Online course completions in DoD increased to 20.4 million in FY12, and will likely increase in the future. The ADL Initiative enables the migration of distributed learning content to multiple hardware platforms and software applications using the SCORM standard.  The ADL Initiative is working in collaboration with the Services, other government agencies, industry, and our international partners to develop the next generation learning architecture that will be platform agnostic and enable the use of new software applications, including mentoring, social media and experiential learning. The research project for the future is Project Aristotle.  The first phase is to develop a Personal Assistant for Learning (PAL), a ubiquitous, 24/7 advanced concept research effort that will provide an untethered, tailored training and learning capability that will adapt to fit the learner’s specific strengths and weaknesses, learning style, and level of proficiency. As we look to the future, the PAL will become more sophisticated, intelligent and comprehensive.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>12.195</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>12.116</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>12.090</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>12.090</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>10.956</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>12.116</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>10.692</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>10.692</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                        <r2:PriorYear>-1.239</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>-1.398</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-1.398</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                        <r2:CongressionalDirectedReductions>
                            <r2:PriorYear>-1.239</r2:PriorYear>
                        </r2:CongressionalDirectedReductions>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>Other Program Adjustments</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>-1.398</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-1.398</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                    </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                    <r2:SummaryExplanation>In FY 2013, reduction was due to sequestration.  

In FY 2015, reduction was due to Budget Control Act and other program adjustments.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:ProjectList>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>Project 1</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Advanced Distributed Learning</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>27.048</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>10.956</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>12.116</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>10.692</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>10.692</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>10.808</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>10.900</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>10.897</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>11.063</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>Established by Executive Order, with policy oversight by the Office of the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense/Readiness (Training Readiness and Strategy), this program leverages emerging learning technologies to provide cost effective training and education to employees and Service members of the Federal Government.  

The mission of the ADL Initiative is to provide access to the highest-quality education, training, and performance aiding tailored to individual needs and delivered cost-effectively. The ADL Initiative is a DoD program responsible for research and development of distributed and networked learning technologies, to include: online courseware, training games, virtual worlds, and mobile technology.  ADL developed the Sharable Content Object Reference Model (SCORM, the de facto industry and internationally accepted standard for e-learning interoperability.  It is mandated for all Department of Defense (DoD) agencies through DoD Instruction 1322.26.  The ADL initiative, working with ADL Partnership Co-Labs and the NATO community, has reduced costs and increased interoperability and sharing of distributed learning content, enabling discovery, retrieval, and reuse.  Online course completions in DoD increased to 20.4 million in FY12, and will likely increase in the future. The ADL Initiative enables the migration of distributed learning content to multiple hardware platforms and software applications using the SCORM standard.  The ADL Initiative is working in collaboration with the Services, other government agencies, industry, and our international partners to develop the next generation learning architecture that will be platform agnostic and enable the use of new software applications, including mentoring, social media and experiential learning. The research project for the future is Project Aristotle.  The first phase is to develop a Personal Assistant for Learning (PAL), a ubiquitous, 24/7 advanced concept research effort that will provide an untethered, tailored training and learning capability that will adapt to fit the learner’s specific strengths and weaknesses, learning style, and level of proficiency. As we look to the future, the PAL will become more sophisticated, intelligent and comprehensive.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Advanced Distributed Learning</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>Established by Executive Order, with policy oversight by the Office of the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense/Readiness (Training Readiness and Strategy), this program leverages emerging learning technologies to provide cost effective training and education to employees and Service members of the Federal Government.</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>10.956</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>• Published multiple research articles in leading professional journals on the best practices and effectiveness of online learning compared to classroom training;
• Began work on solving challenges associated with developing a PAL capability, a 24/7, non-intrusive ubiquitous, advanced concept research effort that will provide an untethered, tailored training and learning capability that will adapt to fit the learner’s specific strengths and weaknesses, learning style, and level of proficiency.
• Researched new learning technologies for possible integration into DoD educational and training programs to include the assessment and tracking of experiential training &amp; education activities;
• Researched structured learning content schemas and transformation technologies to modularize content, enhance semantic understanding, and improve the prospects for reuse;
• Tested advanced instructional methods using intelligent tutors for training;
• Established advanced concept research and prototypes for the Next Generation SCORM standard.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>12.116</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>• Research new learning technologies for possible integration into DoD educational and training programs to include innovative methodologies and approaches to using Social Networking for solving problems in collaborative, disparate environments;
• Demonstrate the application of the spacing effect using current mobile technologies to reinforce learning and improve long-term retention.
• Continue to test advanced instructional methods for intelligent tutors for training;
• Integrate proven concepts from FY13 research into the PAL capability and move to more intelligence-based concepts;
• Update policies, plans, and programs to support Distributed Learning Content (DLC) programs, standardization, identification, and distribution of best practices and guidelines for learning, training, and job performance aids that accommodate today’s networked learning environment;
• Support the White House educational initiatives as the DoD representative to the Learning Registry and Federal Game Guild;
• Continue work with the DoD training community for the purpose of sharing of DLC (metrics, best practices, etc.), standardization of common terminology and best practices for developing and implementing efficient and effective DL technologies across DoD;
• Collaborate with the Services, other government agencies, industry, and our international partners to develop next generation learning architecture, the Training and Learning Architecture (TLA);
• Continue to refine, in collaboration with Military Services and other government agencies to share DLC and 3D models used for immersive learning experiences;
• Collaborate with the other Federal Agencies to share descriptive metadata about learning resources and usage information about how those resources are being used;
• Participate and influence as Co-chair of the International Training &amp; Education Development (IT&amp;ED), NATO Task Group to increase the standardization and reuse of training.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>10.692</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>10.692</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>• Continue to influence industry and academia through publication of research articles in leading professional journals on the integration of emerging learning technologies to enhance training;
• Deliver a prototype for Project Aristotle for possible integration into DoD educational and training programs. 
• Expand research into the following areas: persistent, open independent Learner Models with reasoning capability that incorporate new methods of machine learning; common sense reasoning; cognitive modeling; artificial intelligence; the use of intelligent systems designed to increase both cognitive adaptability and emotional resiliency; and domain independent intelligent system design.
• Deliver a prototype of an instructional intelligent tutor for training;
• Develop the next iteration of the Training &amp; Learning architecture for the next generation learning environment.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Not Required.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>In FY2015, ADL will:
1.  Deliver the next version of the Experience API, which is the first component of the new Training &amp; Learning Architecture.
2  Continue research and integration of the PAL application of Project Aristotle.
3.  Continue to influence key Service and international ADL meetings and conferences reference the discovery, sharing and delivery of interoperable training content; 
4.  Promote the sharing of data among DoD, other Federal Agencies and state and local education departments throughout the U.S., by making educational resources discoverable and retrievable and also through the open source initiative.  
5.  Prototype an Intelligent Tutor with the intent to determine the utilization of this technology across DoD and as a step toward the more comprehensive PAL. Metrics include, but are not limited to; Scalability, Generalizability, and Affordability.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                </r2:ProjectList>
            </r2:ProgramElement>
        </r2:R2Exhibit>
        <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElement>
                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0605021SE</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Homeland Security Presidential Directive (HSPD-12) Initiative</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                <r2:R1LineNumber>123</r2:R1LineNumber>
                <r2:BudgetYear>2015</r2:BudgetYear>
                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                <r2:SubmissionDate>2014-03</r2:SubmissionDate>
                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>DoD Human Resources Activity</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>5</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>System Development &amp; Demonstration (SDD)</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                    <r2:AllPriorYears>0.756</r2:AllPriorYears>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.326</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.386</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.286</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.286</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.100</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.100</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.393</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.298</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Department of Defense Human Resources Activity (DHRA) is a DoD-wide Field Activity chartered to support the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness (USD (P&amp;R)).  HSPD-12 requires rapid electronic authentication for all Government employees, uniformed individuals and contractors. The Defense Enrollment and Eligibility System will provide Enterprise capability for the cardholder data repository, common Access interface to multiple types of Access control hardware, common Access software, the ability to control Access to multiple facilities through one authoritative data source, and provide the standards and data to/form and power efficient gates. Implement Enterprise Access control data for the DoD while providing standards and reducing redundancy. RDT&amp;E funding will be expended to develop the secure interfaces necessary to work with the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) and first responders for Enterprise authentication. Many systems support different aspects of electronic authentication across the Department. RDT&amp;E will allow for the pursuit of a potential solution that will interface disparate applications/systems. This will increase Government efficiency by rapidly verifying electronically the identity of an individual and can be used by many applications, reduce identity fraud, protect privacy by limiting information stored, and increase privacy processes to maintain Access controls, thereby facilitating identification of first responders</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.387</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.386</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.386</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.386</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.326</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.386</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.286</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.286</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                        <r2:PriorYear>-0.061</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>-0.100</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-0.100</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                        <r2:CongressionalDirectedReductions>
                            <r2:PriorYear>-0.061</r2:PriorYear>
                        </r2:CongressionalDirectedReductions>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>Other Program Adjustments</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>-0.100</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-0.100</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                    </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                    <r2:SummaryExplanation>FY 2013 reduction was due to sequestration.

FY 2015 due to Base Control Act and other program adjustments.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:ProjectList>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>Project 1</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Defense Enrollment Eligibility Reporting System</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>0.756</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.326</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.386</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.286</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.286</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.100</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.100</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.393</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.298</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Department of Defense Human Resources Activity (DHRA) is a DoD-wide Field Activity chartered to support the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness (USD (P&amp;R)). HSPD-12 requires rapid electronic authentication for all Government employees, uniformed individuals and contractors. The Defense Enrollment and Eligibility System will provide Enterprise capability for the cardholder data repository, common Access interface to multiple types of Access control hardware, common Access software, the ability to control Access to multiple facilities through one authoritative data source, and provide the standards and data to/form and power efficient gates. Implement Enterprise Access control data for the DoD while providing standards and reducing redundancy. RDT&amp;E funding will be expended to develop the secure interfaces necessary to work with the FBI and first responders for Enterprise authentication. Many systems support different aspects of electronic authentication across the Department. RDT&amp;E will allow for the pursuit of a potential solution that will interface disparate applications/systems. This will increase Government efficiency by rapidly verifying electronically the identity of an individual and can be used by many applications, reduce identity fraud, protect
privacy by limiting information stored, and increase privacy processes to maintain Access controls, thereby facilitating identification of first responders.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Defense Enrollment Eligibility Reporting System/HSPD-12</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>The Department of Defense Human Resources Activity (DHRA) is a DoD-wide Field Activity chartered to support the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness (USD (P&amp;R)). HSPD-12 requires rapid electronic authentication for all Government employees, uniformed individuals and contractors.</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>0.326</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Continue research and development of:
• Providing security personnel notices on persons of interest attempting to Access facilities and increased personnel protection
and policy compliance
• Providing immediate authentication of emergency essential personnel
• Providing an interface among disparate applications/systems across the DoD</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>0.386</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Continue research and development of:
• Providing security personnel notices on persons of interest attempting to Access facilities and increased personnel protection
and policy compliance
• Providing immediate authentication of emergency essential personnel</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>0.286</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>0.286</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>• Mechanisms for the interoperability of federal Personal Identification Verification-Interoperable (PIV-I) credentials to facilitate electronic verification and facility access determinations.
• Integration of authoritative external data sources into the electronic access determination process to improve total assurance and fitness of requesting individual.
• Risk model for the incorporation of mechanisms to support PIV-I credentials for electronic verification and access.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Existing contract vehicles in place/GSA for COTS.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>None</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:R3Exhibit>
                            <r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                                <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                    <r2:Name>Test and Evaluation</r2:Name>
                                    <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>Homeland Personnel Security Directive (HSPD-12) Initiative</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:ContractMethod>C</r2:ContractMethod>
                                            <r2:ContractType>IDIQ</r2:ContractType>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>Gulf Coast Enterprise</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Pensacola, FL</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:TotalPreviousYears>0.756</r2:TotalPreviousYears>
                                                <r2:PriorYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.326</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2013-12</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:PriorYear>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.386</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2014-12</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.286</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.286</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2015-12</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                                <r2:TargetValue>Continuing</r2:TargetValue>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                    </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                            </r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                        </r2:R3Exhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                </r2:ProjectList>
            </r2:ProgramElement>
        </r2:R2Exhibit>
        <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElement>
                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0605803SE</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>R&amp;D in Support of DOD Enlistment, Testing and Evaluation</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                <r2:R1LineNumber>162</r2:R1LineNumber>
                <r2:BudgetYear>2015</r2:BudgetYear>
                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                <r2:SubmissionDate>2014-03</r2:SubmissionDate>
                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>DoD Human Resources Activity</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>6</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>RDT&amp;E Management Support</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                    <r2:AllPriorYears>87.456</r2:AllPriorYears>
                    <r2:PriorYear>16.329</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>6.908</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>8.452</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>8.452</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>7.584</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>6.073</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>5.388</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>7.680</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Department of Defense Human Resources Activity (DHRA) is a DoD-wide Field Activity chartered to support the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness (USD (P&amp;R)).  This PE includes application of R&amp;D to expedite prototype development and mission support efforts to sustain and/or modernize operations required for general RDT&amp;E.

Project 1:  DoD Enlistment Processing and Testing. The project administers testing programs, which enable the Armed Services to select highly qualified military recruits. The DoD uses a single test, the Armed Services Vocational Aptitude Battery (ASVAB), to determine eligibility of military applicants and to report recruit quality data to Congress. High quality recruits are obtained from administering the ASVAB annually to approximately 600,000 applicants for Military Service as part of the DoD Enlistment Testing program, and to 1 million students in the DoD Student Testing program. Each Service also uses ASVAB test forms developed in this program as part of their in-service testing programs. New ASVAB test forms and related support materials are implemented approximately every four years. This allows DoD to make measurement improvements as well as decrease the likelihood of test compromise. Ongoing RDT&amp;E efforts include development and evaluation of procedures which (1) reduce or eliminate threats to the validity of the ASVAB test scores generated; (2) improve the efficiency of the test development, calibration, and validation process; and (3) improve selection and classification decisions made by each Service through more effective use of test score information. In addition, periodic assessments are required to provide DoD manpower planners and Congress with information on aptitude trends in the population from which recruits are drawn.

Project 2:   Federal Voting Assistance Program.  Phase I of Internet Voting Competition Challenge:  In the first phase submissions will focus on defining security, reliability, usability, and accountability requirements for internet voting systems. Submissions will be open to the public, and will be open to public critique. FVAP will review those submissions and critiques, and then consolidate them into a single set of requirements for Phase II. 

o  Phase II of Internet Voting Competition Challenge:  In this phase, submission will provide high level designs and detailed hardware and software architectures, along with procedures necessary for secure operation. Submissions will be sufficiently detailed so that a reasonably skilled information technologist could implement the system to allow for broader peer review.  However, many details such as user interfaces and database layouts will be likely be undefined. As with the first phase, submissions will be open for critique. In this phase critiques will focus on identifying areas where designs do not meet the requirements defined in the first phase. The result may be modification of architectures to incorporate ideas from several teams. At the conclusion of this phase, the Department will narrow down the set of acceptable architectures. 

o  RDT&amp;E funding for the internet voting program is discontinued in FY 2014 until the Election Assistance Commission (EAC) and the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) have established the measurements and standards against which internet voting can be evaluated.  

Project 3:The Defense Civilian Personnel Advisory Service (DCPAS), a DHRA component, manages and operates a number of major DoD programs, including the Defense Civilian Personnel Data System (DCPDS). DCPDS is the Department's enterprise civilian human resources information system. It ensures a coherent, standardized, and cost-effective system for the entire Department. DCPDS is built using a commercial off-the-shelf product customized for Federal and Defense requirements. The system is web-enabled and provides flexibility to respond to changes in the Department's civilian human resources (HR) operational requirements.

DCPDS supports HR operations and improved business processes with continuous implementation of improved technology, meeting cost, schedule, and performance goals.  Network and system operations span worldwide, with 24/7 operations that support 19 Regional Service Centers and over 300 Customer Support Units.  DCPDS will complete its upgrade to the Hewlett Packard Blade architecture for all database servers in 2014. Economic analyses have validated the original estimate of approximately $200M annual savings. The current focus of DCPDS is the expansion of these efficiencies through the consolidation of DCPDS operations to a single data center, where DCPDS enterprise operations and all DoD customer regional operations will be located at the Lockheed Martin Denver Data Center by October 2014.  (Army and Air Force will relocate in FY14 to complete DCPDS Consolidation.)

Other DCPAS programs supporting the civilian workforce include minimizing involuntary separations, assisting laid-off workers, maintaining workforce balance, and reducing the costs of DoD's workers and  unemployment compensation. DHRA/DCPAS supports the development, issuance and maintenance of uniform DoD-wide civilian personnel policy; provides program guidance and technical interpretation for both appropriated and non-appropriated funded civilian HR programs ; manages DoD's Civilian Assistance and Re-Employment (CARE) program, including the Priority Placement Program (PPP); investigates and mediates discrimination complaints; conducts grievance investigations; and manages the operation of the enterprise civilian HR information system, DCPDS. These programs are supported by an aggressive data automation program, to include a communications capability, computing equipment, and an automation software link to standardize these divergent functions. These funds continue to support these processes.

Project 4: :  Defense Manpower Data Center (DMDC) acts as the authoritative source for identity and personnel information for the DoD Net Centric Enterprise Computing vision of the Department of Defense’s Global Information Grid (GIG 2.0). Based on the Defense Enrollment Eligibility Reporting System (DEERS) identities, DMDC provides the key attribute service for the Department of Defense (DoD) Identity and Access Management (IdAM) Capability. The Enterprise Identity Attribute Service (EIAS) supports IdAM through the distribution of DoD person and personnel attributes to applications and services in a controlled, consistent, and secure manner to support ABAC decisions. The controlled, authoritative information provided via EIAS can be used to confirm an individual’s identity, affiliation to the DoD, clearance, pay grade/rank, organization and occupation series for an authorization decision. A key attribute for decision makers is organization. The Global Force Management Data Initiative (GFM_DI) provides the  organization unique identifiers (OUID) in the EIAS payload. To meet the DoD demand for the OUID, DMDC working with J8 and the Service/Agencies has to 1) establish the linkage between a person (EDI_PI) and the OUID, 2) provide the OUID attribute in the EIAS payload for access decisions, and 3) standardize the organizational attributes required to make access decisions

Project 5: The Neo Tracking System (NTS) / Emergency Tracking Accountability System (ETAS) is a certified and accredited DoD automated system that accounts for, and sustains visibility of noncombatant evacuees during a NEO under the authority of DODD 1000.25, DoD Personnel Identity Protection (PIP) Program. NTS is currently being used in the USAFRICOM, USCENTCOM, USEUCOM, USSOUTHCOM, and USPACOM Area of Responsibility. The ETAS component is the CONUS domestic version of NTS and is for use by USNORTHCOM during disasters in the CONUS whether natural, accidental, or acts of terrorism. The primary purpose of the NTS/ETAS is to provide individual accountability of the evacuee by creating and maintaining a database of evacuees assembled during an evacuation operation and subsequently tracking the evacuees' movement throughout the evacuation process.

Project 6: The Synchronized Pre-deployment and Operational Tracker Enterprise Suite (SPOT-ES) is the Department of Defense (DoD) system of record for accountability and visibility of contracts and contractor personnel authorized to operate in a contingency operation.  SPOT-ES provides web based tracking and visibility into contract services, personnel and equipment locations; provides a common operational picture for Combatant Commanders; enhances the analytical tools to accurately plan for the quantity of contracted support required for future contingency operations; and collects accurate data for the Office of Management and Budget-directed quarterly census of all contractors supporting contingency operations.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>16.364</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>6.908</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>6.195</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>6.195</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>16.329</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>6.908</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>8.452</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>8.452</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                        <r2:PriorYear>-0.035</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>2.257</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>2.257</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                        <r2:Reprogrammings>
                            <r2:PriorYear>-0.035</r2:PriorYear>
                        </r2:Reprogrammings>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>Other Program Adjustments</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>2.257</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>2.257</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                    </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:ProjectList>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>Project 1</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>DoD Enlistment Processing &amp; Testing</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>4.112</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>1.054</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.376</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>1.945</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>1.945</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>2.185</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>1.986</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>1.849</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>1.861</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The primary mission of DoD Enlistment Processing and Testing is to test and implement more accurate methods of assessing aptitudes required for military enlistment, success in training, and performance on the job. Also, it includes implementing methods that are useful in the identification of persons with the high aptitudes required by today’s smaller and technically more demanding military.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>DoD Enlistment Processing &amp; Testing</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>DoD Enlistment Processing &amp; Testing</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>1.054</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>DoD Enlistment Testing Program (ETP):
• Finalize and implement new procedures for test development of ASVAB Items
• Continue research on revisions to ASVAB content
DoD Student Testing Program (STP):
• Continue to evaluate the use of internet-based CAT-ASVAB in the CEP</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>0.376</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>DoD Enlistment Testing Program (ETP):
• Continue research on revisions to ASVAB content

DoD Student Testing Program (STP):
• Evaluate methods to convert all STP to CAT
• Continue to evaluate the use of internet-based CAT-ASVAB in the CEP</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>1.945</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>1.945</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>• Continue the research effort on new measures/new content that could potentially be added to the ASVAB
•Continue development of new ASVAB test items in accordance with revised procedures
NOTE.  Plans for FY2013, FY2014, and FY2015 are severely adversely impacted due to reduced funds during these years.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>NOT REQUIRED.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>Each project contained within this program contains specific metrics to determine progress towards completion.  Metrics for all include completed and documented analysis provided by the performer. The completion date for that analysis varies with each project. In addition, to that analysis, each effort contains a roadmap addressing the best use of the findings throughout the department. If the results of the analysis show benefit to the Department, those findings are included in policy, doctrine, tactics and procedures.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>Project 2</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Federal Voting Assistance Program</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>66.321</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>9.657</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Federal Voting Assistance Program (FVAP) exists to:
o  Assist military personnel, their dependents, and overseas Americans exercise their right to vote so that they have an equal opportunity with the general population to have their vote counted;
o  Assist the States in complying with relevant federal laws, and advise them on ways to best comply with those laws; and 
o  Advocate on behalf of military and overseas voters, identifying impediments to their ability to exercise their right to vote, and proposing methods to overcome those impediments.

Given the inherent uncertainties in deploying an internet voting system five to seven years from now, the Department requires substantial flexibility in shifting two-year RDT&amp; funds over different fiscal years, and in accelerating or decelerating execution rates, dependent upon the results of the intermediate programs which support future steps in the overall effort.  For example, in August 2011, during a working group meeting with computer technology scientists and representatives of EAC and NIST, the idea of conducting iterative public competitions of internet voting systems, akin to a weapon system “fly-off,” was adopted, and which provides the Department potential significant cost and time savings in deploying an internet voting system.  But its discovery near the end of FY2011 also makes it very difficult to fit such program development into the rigid requirements of the budget cycle and the even more rigid requirements of State election cycles.

Congressional mandates also charge the Election Assistance Commission (EAC) (and through the Technical Guideline Development Committee, the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST)), with developing guidelines for the Department on such electronic absentee voting systems.  FVAP, EAC and NIST are jointly developing these guidelines, supported by full public engagement with the computer science, military and overseas voting advocacy, and voting system development communities.  This public outreach is crucial to designing electronic absentee voting systems which will be accepted as providing the same level of ballot access, security, privacy, and accountability as the current absentee voting systems provided military and overseas voters.  

Original FY 2013 FVAP budget estimates assumed a 2012 or 2014 deployment of the electronic absentee voting system demonstration project.  However, system and guideline development does not support demonstration project deployment prior to 2016 or 2018.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Federal Voting Assistance Program</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>Federal Voting Assistance Program Funding will support the development of online tools to provide Voter Assistance Officer (VAO) training and to develop a dynamic public web-site to facilitate internet-based voter registration, ballot delivery and voting system for use in the first general election after the release of guidelines. FVAP will conduct a variety of research, analysis, evaluation, test and support functions with the intent of supporting Wounded Warrior, disabled military members, military members, their dependents and overseas civilian voters to register and vote successfully with a minimum amount of effort.</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>9.657</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Given the agile planning and deployment flexibilities required in as dynamic a RDT&amp;E environment as internet voting, the FY 2013 execution plan will be significantly influenced by the results of the FY2011 and FY2012 research, development, and evaluation results.  However, current plans are to initiate the first two phases of the internet voting demonstration competition challenge:

o  Phase I of Internet Voting Competition Challenge:  In the first phase submissions will focus on defining security, reliability, usability, and accountability requirements for internet voting systems. Submissions will be open to the public, and will be open to public critique. FVAP will review those submissions and critiques, and then consolidate them into a single set of requirements for Phase II. 

o  Phase II of Internet Voting Competition Challenge:  In this phase, submission will provide high level designs and detailed hardware and software architectures, along with procedures necessary for secure operation. Submissions will be sufficiently detailed so that a reasonably skilled information technologist could implement the system to allow for broader peer review.  However, many details such as user interfaces and database layouts will be likely be undefined. As with the first phase, submissions will be open for critique. In this phase critiques will focus on identifying areas where designs do not meet the requirements defined in the first phase. The result may be modification of architectures to incorporate ideas from several teams. At the conclusion of this phase, the Department will narrow down the set of acceptable architectures. 

o  Conformance Testing to EAC Pilot Program Requirements for Kiosk Systems Used in a 2014 Election: To support the testing of internet voting systems from monitored kiosk test platform (where the ballots of record are printed out and delivered to jurisdictions like other absentee ballots, but the same ballot is delivered electronically to the election jurisdiction for comparison to the paper ballot of record), the Department will test conformance of selected systems to the EAC Pilot Program Testing Requirements.  

FY 2014 plans, as stated above, plans for RDT&amp;E funding beyond FY 2013 depend on the NIST and EAC establishing the measurements for standards against which internet voting can be evaluated.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>NOT REQUIRED</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>The project is the development , testing and deployment of an internet-based  voter registration, ballot delivery and voting system that integrates the requirements of the electronic absentee voting guidelines.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>Project 3</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Human Resources Automation Enhancements</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>15.627</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>1.312</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>2.832</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>4.976</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>4.976</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>4.354</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>3.476</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>2.664</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>4.509</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>Civilian HR automation enhancements planned for FY 2013 and FY 2014 are focused on software development to support the Department’s civilian workforce, including  a performance management system; development of an employee competency assessment capability and EEO investigations case management; and  the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) mandates for HR Line of Business (LoB), electronic Official Personnel Folder, and Retirement Systems Modernization implementation. DoD is one of five designated Shared Service Centers in the federal  government focused on providing standard services across agency lines, gaining potential significant business and cost-saving benefits. DoD is considered a leader in this initiative.  DCPDS is the Department’s enterprise civilian HR system that has provided the savings originally projected in the achievement of full operational capability in 2002 and which has continued to operate as the DoD system serving over 800,000 employee records. Additional initiatives to sustain the Department’s lead in automated systems include expansion of employee self service functionality, and support for data warehouse improvements, engineering plans for consolidation and migration to a federal data center, an employee-manager portal, and information assurance initiatives to comply with DoD-mandated DMZ requirements.  DCPDS enhancements will support the Department’s focus on the further consolidation of civilian HR operations to a single operational site, with linkage to Component operations worldwide.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Human Resources Automation Enhancements</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>1.312</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Phase III of DMZ extension was completed to comply with DoD mandated DMZ extension requirements for all systems, and enhancements were developed to comply with legislative, federal-wide and DoD requirements.  Interfaces were  modified between DCPDS and external systems.  Development initiatives included a DCPDS data dictionary (phase I), research into data warehouse expansion altneratives, initial employee/manager portal, and establishment of a web services capaibility.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>2.832</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>FY 2014 plans include continued enhancements to comply with information assurance requirements, including DMZ extension requirements; DCPDS and other HR systems development to ensure compliance with legislative, OPM and OMB mandates; system enhancements and interfaces to support HR LoB initiatives.  Development of virtualization, cloud computing, data mobility and availability to the user will support the Defense Joint Information Enterprise initiative and combined HR system operations at a single data center under the Department’s Data Center Consolidation initiative and the Federal Data Center Consolidation initiative.  Continued enhancement of portal, warehouse and Web services will be developed.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>4.976</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>4.976</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Information assurance requirements for compliance with IA mandates, including further DMZ extension requirements; integration of functionality to comply with legislative mandates; development and prototyping of Advanced Benefits to support self-service initiatives for civilian employee access and use; data mart expansion to facilitate user access to data; and additional  development of features for portal, warehouse, cloud computing, virtualization and Web services will continue.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>N/A</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>N/A</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>Project 4</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Global Force Mgmt Data Initiative</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>1.396</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.608</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>Defense Manpower Data Center (DMDC) acts as the authoritative source for identity and personnel information for the DoD Net Centric Enterprise Computing vision of the Department of Defense’s Global Information Grid (GIG 2.0). Based on the DEERS identities, DMDC provides the key attribute service for the Department of Defense (DoD) Identity and Access Management (IdAM) Capability. The Enterprise Identity Attribute Service (EIAS) supports IdAM through the distribution of DoD person and personnel attributes to applications and services in a controlled, consistent, and secure manner to support ABAC decisions. The controlled, authoritative information provided via EIAS can be used to confirm an individual’s identity, affiliation to the DoD, clearance, pay grade/rank, organization and occupation series for an authorization decision. A key attribute for decision makers is organization. The Global Force Management Data Initiative (GFM_DI) provides the unique organization identifier (OUID) in the EIAS payload. To meet the DoD demand for the OUID, DMDC working with J8 and the Service/Agencies has to 1) establish the linkage between a person (EDI_PI) and the OUID, 2) provide the OUID attribute in the EIAS payload for access decisions, and 3) standardize the organizational attributes required to make access decisions.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Global Force Mgmt Data Initiative (GFMDI)</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>N/A</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>0.608</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>• Continue to establish a web service between DEERS and Component’s personnel Systems to support the EDIPI to SSN links
• Continue to facilitate Component’s ability to expose their Organizational Hierarchies for usage by the IdAM community
• Continue to standardize the web services to support an Enterprise organization attribute service for DoD which promotes Secure Data Access</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Existing contract vehicles in place/GSA for COTS.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>N/A</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>Project 5</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>NEO Tracking System</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.761</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.761</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.531</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.531</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.618</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Neo Tracking System (NTS) / Electronic Tracking Accountability System (ETAS) is a certified and accredited DoD automated system that accounts for, and sustains visibility of noncombatant evacuees during a NEO under the authority of DODD 1000.25, DoD Personnel Identity Protection (PIP) Program. NTS is currently being used in the USAFRICOM, USCENTCOM, USEUCOM, USSOUTHCOM, and USPACOM AORs. The ETAS component is the CONUS domestic version of NTS and is for use by USNORTHCOM during disasters in the CONUS whether natural, accidental, or acts of terrorism. The primary purpose of the NTS/ETAS is to provide individual accountability of the evacuee by creating and maintaining a database of evacuees assembled during an evacuation operation and subsequently tracking the evacuees’ movement through the evacuation process.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>NEO Tracking System (NTS)</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>0.761</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>• Convert the NTS program to a mobile application package that can be run on tablets and smart phones
• Streamline the distribution of NTS images, reducing not only the costs associated with the creation of an image, but also the time associated with receiving the image in the field</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>0.761</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>• Upgrade system software and hardware drivers for Windows 7, 64-bit compatibility
• Continue hardware implementation
• Automate distribution of system updates</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>0.531</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>0.531</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>• Continue with hardware implementations
• Continue with automation distribution of system updates</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Existing contract vehicles in place/GSA for COTS.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>N/A</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>Project 6</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Synchronized Pre-deployment &amp; Operational Tracker Enterprise Suite</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>2.937</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>2.939</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>1.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>1.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.427</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.611</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.875</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>1.310</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Synchronized Pre-deployment and Operational Tracker Enterprise Suite (SPOT-ES) is the Department of Defense (DoD) system of record for accountability and visibility of contracts and contractor personnel authorized to operate in a contingency operation.  SPOT-ES provides web based tracking and visibility into contract services, personnel and equipment locations; provides a common operational picture for Combatant Commanders; enhances the analytical tools to accurately plan for the quantity of contracted support required for future contingency operations; and collects accurate data for the OMB-directed quarterly census of all contractors supporting contingency operations.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>The Synchronized Pre-deployment and Operational Tracker</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>2.937</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>• Continue to be the system of record for accountability and
visibility of contracts and contractor personnel in support of the CENTCOM
Area of Responsibility and other contingencies around the world.  
• Continue to provide the only DoS, DoD, and USAID sanctioned
Letter of Authorization (LOA) which provides the Government Furnished
Services to contractor personnel.  
• Provide the information on contractor personnel supporting Iraq
and Afghanistan to the Office of the Secretary of Defense for reports to
Congress.
• Provide the number of contractor personnel and contract
capability to Combatant Commands for operational planning purposes and to
aid in their decision making processes.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>2.939</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>• Continue to be the system of record for accountability and visibility of contracts and contractor personnel in support of the CENTCOM Area of Responsibility and other contingencies around the world.
• Continue to provide the only DoS, DoD, and USAID sanctioned Letter of Authorization (LOA) which provides the Government Furnished Services to contractor personnel.
• Provide the information on contractor personnel supporting Iraq and Afghanistan to the Office of the Secretary of Defense for reports to Congress.
• Provide the number of contractor personnel and contract capability to Combatant Commands for operational planning purposes and to aid in their decision making processes.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>1.000</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>1.000</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>• Continue to be the system of record for accountability and visibility of contracts and contractor personnel in support of the CENTCOM Area of Responsibility and other contingencies around the world.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>N/A</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                </r2:ProjectList>
            </r2:ProgramElement>
        </r2:R2Exhibit>
    </r2:R2ExhibitList>
</jb:JustificationBook>