<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jb:MasterJustificationBook xmlns:jb="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/jb" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
    <jb:BudgetYear>2016</jb:BudgetYear>
    <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
    <jb:SubmissionDate>2015-02</jb:SubmissionDate>
    <jb:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Technical Information Center</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
    <jb:CoverPage/>
    <jb:ExternalDocuments>
        <jb:UserR1Doc>
            <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit R-1</jb:Title>
            <jb:FileName>DTIC PB2016 R-1.pdf</jb:FileName>
        </jb:UserR1Doc>
    </jb:ExternalDocuments>
    <jb:TableOfContents>
        <jb:TocItemList>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 1</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Missile Defense Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 2</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Office of the Secretary Of Defense</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 3</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Chemical and Biological Defense Program</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 4</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Contract Management Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>DoD Human Resources Activity</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Information Systems Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Logistics Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Security Cooperation Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Security Service</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Technical Information Center</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Threat Reduction Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>The Joint Staff</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>United States Special Operations Command</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Washington Headquarters Service</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Operational Test and Evaluation, Defense</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Geospatial Intelligence Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>(see NIP and MIP Justification Books)</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Intelligence Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>(see NIP and MIP Justification Books)</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>National Security Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>(see NIP and MIP Justification Books)</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
        </jb:TocItemList>
    </jb:TableOfContents>
    <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        <jb:GenerateP1m>true</jb:GenerateP1m>
        <jb:ForceEvenPages>true</jb:ForceEvenPages>
    </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
    <jb:JustificationBookGroupList>
        <jb:JustificationBookGroup>
            <jb:JustificationBookInfoList>
                <jb:JustificationBookInfo>
                    <jb:BookDescription>Defense Technical Information Center</jb:BookDescription>
                    <jb:BookLabel>Volume</jb:BookLabel>
                    <jb:BookNumber>5</jb:BookNumber>
                    <jb:JustificationBook targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
                        <jb:Title>Justification Book</jb:Title>
                        <jb:BudgetYear>2016</jb:BudgetYear>
                        <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
                        <jb:SubmissionDate>2015-02</jb:SubmissionDate>
                        <jb:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Technical Information Center</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
                        <jb:AppropriationCode>0400</jb:AppropriationCode>
                        <jb:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</jb:AppropriationName>
                        <jb:CoverPage/>
                        <jb:ExternalDocuments>
                            <jb:UserR1Doc>
                                <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit R-1</jb:Title>
                                <jb:FileName>DTIC PB2016 R-1.pdf</jb:FileName>
                            </jb:UserR1Doc>
                        </jb:ExternalDocuments>
                        <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
                            <jb:ForceEvenPages>true</jb:ForceEvenPages>
                            <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>
                            <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>
                            <jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>true</jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>
                        </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
                        <r2:R2ExhibitList xmlns:r2="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/r2" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
                            <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
                                <r2:ProgramElement>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0605801KA</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Defense Technical Information Center</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                                    <r2:R1LineNumber>160</r2:R1LineNumber>
                                    <r2:BudgetYear>2016</r2:BudgetYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                                    <r2:SubmissionDate>2015-02</r2:SubmissionDate>
                                    <r2:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Technical Information Center</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                                    <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                                    <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                                    <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>6</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                                    <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>RDT&amp;E Management Support</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>56.024</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>50.789</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>51.775</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>51.775</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>50.410</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>50.016</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>51.257</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>52.035</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                    </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Defense Technical Information Center’s (DTIC) unique mission is to provide rapid, accurate, and reliable access to essential research, development, test, and evaluation (RDT&amp;E) information, supporting all DoD users.  DTIC, a DoD Field Activity, is the DoD’s singular executive agent and designated source for DoD-funded scientific, technical, engineering, and industry-related information.  Over the past several years, DTIC has evolved to an information delivery house, that through use of the internet, can deliver technical information nearly instantaneously to all DoD users.  DTIC also operates DoD Information Analysis Centers (IACs) focused on Defense Systems, Cyber Security and Information Systems, and Homeland Defense and Security.  DTIC captures, preserves, protects, shares research and development (R&amp;D) information assets, and encourages collaboration to connect user communities.  DTIC seeks to provide a department level mapping of R&amp;D activity.  This activity and its results advance research by providing researchers, warfighters, research and engineering (R&amp;E) management, and decision makers with insight into current and past research conducted, highlighting progress made and by whom, and, just as important, where research leads to dead ends.  As new capability needs are identified, technical challenges arise--rather than starting anew--work can pick up from the point of most recent results.  Through the preservation and sharing of the results of billions of dollars of past DoD investment, DTIC increases the return on past investments and accelerates current efforts.  Through its collaboration tools and outreach to the R&amp;E community, DTIC works to connect researchers across the lab enterprise, to include research and engineering, warfighters and DoD’s industry partners.  DTIC operations focus on five key areas:

1) Document and preserve what works, what has promise (for reuse and additional investments).
2) Provide results that identify dead-ends that do not merit additional investment (avoid waste).
3) Facilitate and encourage engagement among cross-cutting communities of interest (bring together experts across the acquisition enterprise to meet warfighter needs).
4) Present overarching picture of research investment that enables decision-makers to link multiple efforts with integrated capabilities (employ resources to highest priority efforts and coordinate efforts across Services).
5) Protect intellectual property (IP) and industry proprietary data assets entrusted to DTIC’s stewardship (protect information access).

DTIC recognizes the need to accomplish its mission while increasing the value of the services and products we provide in an environment of Department-wide budget reductions.  DTIC has reduced its physical footprint, civilian personnel and contract support; restructured the IAC program; and continues to consolidate its data center.  At the same time, DTIC has taken on additional programs, to include its new role in leading the Department in efforts to provide public access to DoD-funded journal articles and research data and increased outreach to industry through the Defense Innovation Marketplace.

DTIC continues to ensure its activities are efficient and effective, meet users’ expectations, and employ industry best practices and standards, while protecting from cyber threats.  DoD’s $120 Billion annual investment in research, development and procurement, support current and future capabilities.  The results of these efforts are a national asset that DTIC must preserve for reuse across the acquisition enterprise.  Approximately 23 percent of the four million records in DTIC’s information holdings are sensitive DoD only, federal government only and industry proprietary.  DTIC is the only enterprise source for both publicly accessible and DoD sensitive material in a single location.

DTIC’s Information Analysis Center (IAC) Program Office provides core funding, management and oversight of its three IACs.  The IACs are chartered by DoD to collect, analyze, and disseminate worldwide scientific and technical information in specialized fields.  The IAC program just completed a multi-year restructuring from ten IACs to the current three, reducing customer costs and incorporating new DoD technical interest areas.  The new structure will focus on three technology groupings, to include Cyber Security and Information Systems, Homeland Defense and Security, and Defense Systems.  As part of the Department’s Better Buying Power initiative, new multi-award contracts have been put into place, improving competition, small-business presence, and reducing government costs.  The restructured IAC Program will improve affordability, productivity, and standardization within defense acquisition programs.  Providing the acquisition enterprise access to thousands of industry subject matter experts, DTIC’s IACs perform nearly $2.0 Billion of customer funded research and prototyping support annually.  The results of the work are a rich source of material in DTIC’s information asset collections and are available to users across the Department (and other federal agencies, e.g., Department of Energy, Department of Homeland Security).  

This Program Element (PE) supports DTIC mission operations.  DTIC focuses on core mission, and buys space, human resources (HR), financial management, contracting, IT security and communications, and civilian payroll services from expert and efficient DoD providers:  funding provides for salaries and benefits of government civilian personnel assigned to DTIC; training, professional development, and travel for DTIC personnel; support agreements for Defense Logistics Agency (DLA) facility-related services; Defense Finance and Accounting Service (DFAS) financial activities and HR services; Defense Information Services Agency (DISA) communications and IT security services; annual maintenance and licensing requirements; supplies, equipment, hardware/software; and support contracts for information technology services, Defense Agencies Initiative (DAI) system integration, and Chief Financial Officer (CFO) Act compliance efforts in concert with the Department’s Financial Improvement and Audit Readiness (FIAR) program.  In addition, this PE provides funding in support of the Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) and Small Business Technology Transfer (STTR) programs, in accordance with Public Law 111-251 (Small Business Reauthorization Act) and Small Business Technology Transfer Program Reauthorization Act. Within the PE, an annual set-aside contribution totaling approximately $400,000 is provided to the DoD's Commercialization Pilot Program, as directed by the Department's Office of Small Business Programs (OSBP).</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                                    <r2:ChangeSummary>
                                        <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>56.024</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>50.789</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>48.194</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>48.194</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>56.024</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>50.789</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>51.775</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>51.775</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.581</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.581</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                        <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                                            <r2:CongressionalGeneralReductions>
                                                <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                            </r2:CongressionalGeneralReductions>
                                            <r2:CongressionalDirectedReductions>
                                                <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                            </r2:CongressionalDirectedReductions>
                                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                                                <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                                    <r2:Title>Program Changes</r2:Title>
                                                    <r2:Funding>
                                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.581</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.581</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    </r2:Funding>
                                                </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                                        </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                                        <r2:SummaryExplanation>Specific changes to the FY 2016 program (net increase of $0.986 Million from the FY 2015 funding level; $3.581 Million from the previous PB Base) are outlined below:

FY 2016 Program Change:  The funding increase eliminates a one year dip in DTIC funding, leveling FY 2016 with FY 2015 and 2017 programs.  This change represents a departmental restoration of DTIC mission funding.  The FY 2016 funding increase directly provides for the following efforts:

- The Department’s activities associated with the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) and Office of Management and Budget (OMB) requirements for public access and open digital data for research efforts.  OSTP policy requires increased public access to the results of federally funded scientific research, including peer reviewed journal articles and digitally formatted scientific data.  The Defense Technical Information Center (DTIC) is the lead agency for DoD’s implementation and compliance.  

- On-going DTIC activities--that would otherwise be suspended--needed for DTIC to meet DoD information technology security and identity management requirements, as well as efforts to expand content available to warfighters and other DTIC users on secured networks.  

Public Access:  The Department’s efforts associated with public access and open digital data provides for a broader collection of technical data, improving access and availability for both DoD and public users.  The scope of the public access initiative expands beyond DTIC’s current mission areas (Budget Activities 6.1 to 6.3) to cover all research performed in the Department.  This government-wide effort encourages further reuse of technical data, and is expected to drive innovation, efficiencies and cost savings to users.  Additional funding in support of the public access &amp; digital data initiative will provide for the following activities:

- DTIC will increase its public access services (services that had been slated for curtailment as a result of previous budget reductions), enhance our research in progress summary database, collect and store manuscripts of peer reviewed journal articles, and develop tools to link public users to journal articles and relevant digital data.

- It is critical for DTIC to bolster its IT systems and infrastructure supporting the central repository for scientific and technical data.  New automated processes will allow for efficient processing and placing of up to 40,000 additional journal articles online per year, a tenfold increase over the current volume, providing access to DoD and public users.

- Establish a compliance system and process linking DoD resources to research, enabling DITC to track and collect all results generated from grants, contracts and in-house work, to include work published in peer-reviewed journal articles.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
                                    </r2:ChangeSummary>
                                    <r2:ProjectList>
                                        <r2:Project>
                                            <r2:ProjectNumber>001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                                            <r2:ProjectTitle>Defense Technical Information Center</r2:ProjectTitle>
                                            <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                                            <r2:ProjectFunding>
                                                <r2:PriorYear>48.971</r2:PriorYear>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>45.041</r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>46.027</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>46.027</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearTwo>44.662</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearThree>44.268</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearFour>45.509</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearFive>46.287</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:ProjectFunding>
                                            <r2:R2aExhibit>
                                                <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>DTIC is responsible for developing, coordinating and enabling a strong scientific and technical information (STINFO) program for the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering (ASD(R&amp;E)) and the DoD scientific &amp; technical (S&amp;T) enterprise.  In this role, DTIC sets policy for scientific and technical information (STI) exchanges for the research and engineering (R&amp;E) community.  DTIC’s aim is to maximize the availability and use of technical information and products resulting from Defense-funded technical activities while ensuring restrictions to safeguard national security, export control, and intellectual property rights.

Recognizing the common elements across budget justification documents, progress reports, completed work reports, studies, and journal articles, DTIC is mapping relationships to enable users to access the life cycle of research projects from planning to final results.  DTIC employs technology to verify and validate information submitted and improve user confidence in DoD research documentation.

DTIC is leading the Department’s efforts to implement public access to published journal articles, and digital data from research funded by taxpayers.  In this role, DTIC is actively working with partners across the Services, components, other federal agencies and publishers.  Consistent with the Administration’s (Office of Management and Budget) emphasis for open standards and machine readable formats, DTIC initiated the transition from paper and Portable Document Format (PDF) based information to WebService Extensible Markup Language (XML) standard data submission and machine readable delivery.  DTIC partnered with the OSD Comptroller to collect investment account budget justification documentation in XML and embed this XML in PDF for justification books delivered to Congress.  DTIC employed this same technology in collecting S&amp;T progress reports from the Services and Agencies, and Independent Research and Development (IR&amp;D) data from industry.  DTIC is planning the migration of completed technical reports collection to the same open standards – machine readable formats.

Through the use of commercial search technology, DTIC provides an industry leading search capability that links its knowledge of the DoD domain and metadata to support both text searches and data mining.  DTIC continually works to enable additional features within our search capabilities and from commercial partners to improve information discovery and relevance.

With the September 2014 full operating capability (FOC) release of the commercial product based R&amp;E Gateway, DTIC provides the means to connect 60,000+ members in the acquisition enterprise (DoD Labs, Federally Funded Research and Development Centers (FFRDCs), Program Executive Offices, Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics (AT&amp;L) and Combatant Commands (CCMD)).  In an access controlled environment all of DTIC’s unclassified assets, tools and community interaction capabilities foster innovation, competition and identification of solutions.  DoD conducts research at its 60+ labs, in the FFRDC’s, DTIC’s Information Analysis Centers (IACs), through contracts and grants, and across over a dozen distinct priority area communities of interest; this work is available through the R&amp;E Gateway.

To protect information, DTIC maintains a database of registered users; in addition, DTIC utilizes commercial software and follows DoD Identity Management Standards, providing Common Access Card (CAC) users instant authenticated access.  DTIC is working with the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to give users more control of their online profile and extend immediate access to federal government employees and contractors holding valid credentials. 

Focus on User Communities and Distribution Points:  DTIC supports user communities on the network where they work, NIPRNET, SIPRNET and Internet, and uniquely provides access controls within unclassified and classified material to protect intellectual property in our search, distribution, and collaboration tools.

- DoD’s Acquisition Enterprise:  As a Field Activity to ASD(R&amp;E)/AT&amp;L, DTIC’s priority is the acquisition enterprise, hosting information assets and tools on the NIPRNET (the primary network for the community).
- Warfighter:  Improving coordination between the acquisition enterprise and warfighter communities, DTIC hosts a subset of information assets and tools on the SIPRNET.  DTIC is working to expand the availability of S&amp;T information, to include Independent Research and Development (IR&amp;D), on the SIPRNET.
- Industry and Academia via Internet:  Engaging industry outside the NIPRNET “firewall” to support Better Buying Power initiatives and encourage the introduction of innovation, DTIC hosts unclassified “public” information and tools accessible to all users on the Internet.  The Public Access initiative adds importance to the public distribution point, to encourage technology transfer of basic and public research to the private sector, and to give an economic boost to small businesses that can use that data to provide new applications to consumers.

Summary.  DTIC protects and preserves DoD’s multi-billion dollar investment in research, which empowers the acquisition enterprise through innovative tools, information systems, and decision support capabilities.  The benefits can be enormous; each 1 percent increase in reuse of S&amp;T, elimination of inefficient redundancy and increased community interaction, results in a more capable military and gives the DoD the opportunity to redirect >$100 Million.  DTIC is uniquely positioned to support and unleash the value of DoD’s R&amp;D portfolio.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                                    <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                        <r2:Title>Defense Technical Information Center</r2:Title>
                                                        <r2:Accomplishment>
                                                            <r2:PriorYear>
                                                                <r2:Funding>48.971</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>- As the DoD lead, managed and implemented the primary objectives associated with public access to publications and digital data.
-- Developed and finalized implementation plan for Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) and methodology for policy changes.
-- Implemented a pilot through Department of Energy to establish an interface to the publishers’ database for access to DoD-funded publications, a first step for public access.
- Expanded and developed community support, search and analytic capability of DoD Research and Engineering (R&amp;E) Gateway; successfully completed several major enhancements. 
-- Improved analytic and collaborative capabilities.
-- Added group spaces for Air Force A8, Reliance 21, as well as other Communities of Interest (COI) and agencies.
-- Initiated the upgrade of the classified version to the same underlying commercial software version as the unclassified, improving user access in the warfighting community.
- Operated and enhanced the Defense Innovation Marketplace, a key component of the Better Buying Power 2.0 initiative.
-- Developed and fostered communities of interest (COIs) with the Services, to include C4ISR (C2, ISR, CyberSpace), Nuclear Weapons Enterprise, and Aero Enterprise.
-- Increased access controls protecting industry proprietary data.
- Conducted the annual Unified Research and Engineering Database (URED) data call ultimately resulting in adding or updating over 6,600 records detailing DoD research in progress.
-- Deployed a new search tool to URED, thereby exposing over 28,000 URED records to the user community in a more usable, efficient format.
- Deployed the International Agreements Database (IADB) consisting of over 3,400 searchable international agreements from all three services
-- Launched in a partnership with the DoD International Cooperation (IC) office and available to all DoD users, IADB creates the capability to research existing partnerships and focuses on agreements supporting current and  future planning for international collaboration.
- Partnered with the Defense Logistics Agency (DLA) to begin the replacement of a 20+ year old library content management system.  Leveraging existing technologies, the new system will support DoD imperatives to increase public access, cyber security, and data consolidation. 
- Built a proof of concept for a master data repository (MDR), an infrastructure design to move all DTIC collections to one common repository to enable more efficient search and analysis.
- Achieved DoD audit readiness milestones and requirements.
- Put in place the procurement for the data center IT hardware and software refresh to ensure effectiveness and efficiency with updated technology to service S&amp;T information for DTIC internal and external customers.  
- Aligned with the DoD Joint Information Environment (JIE) initiative for the Federal Data Center Consolidation Initiatives (FDCCI) by reducing the physical footprint of servers and maximizing virtualization for the DTIC systems and applications that services all of the DoD, industry partners, and academia users.</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:PriorYear>
                                                        </r2:Accomplishment>
                                                        <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                            <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                <r2:Funding>45.041</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>- Manage and implement the primary objectives associated with public access to publications and digital data.
-- Work with the Defense Basic Research Advisory Group (DBRAG) to initiate policy changes for phase I, intramural basic research projects.
-- Explore and identify a monitoring and compliance mechanism; add public access compliance fields to Unified Research and Engineering Database (URED).
-- Identify a catalog/locator to track data set locations, and identify potential DoD digital repositories for storage.
-- Complete the interface pilot program in partnership with Department of Energy to provide access to DoD-funded publications.
- Bolster capabilities of the DoD Research and Engineering (R&amp;E) Gateway based on specific user requirements and usage. 
-- Engage defense communities and their subject matter experts; work with partners to expand user-provided content and research materials to benefit the DoD mission.
-- Promote information sharing and secure collaboration among the 17 DoD science and technology (S&amp;T) communities of interest (COIs) by assisting them with DTIC’s collaborative tools.
-- Expand technical and budget content available on SIPRNET version.
- Evolve and improve Defense Innovation Marketplace capabilities in alignment with the Department’s Better Buying Power 2.0/3.0 initiative, enabling acquisitions experts to include industry-sponsored research in their buying plans.
-- Capture industry’s classified Independent Research and Development (IR&amp;D) and move search collection to the SIPRNET environment.
-- Employ the Marketplace for virtual Technical Information Meetings with industry in communities of interest areas.
- Deploy new Unified Research and Engineering Database (URED) capabilities for the user community.
-- Develop advanced search and visualization capabilities to support both improved data quality and better decision making across the Department.
-- Modify and enhance DoD research summaries to capture information related to public access of journal articles and digital data.
- Expand the searchable International Agreements Database (IADB) for DoD users by integrating international agreements from Defense Threat Reduction Agency (DTRA), Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) and Missile Defense Agency (MDA).
- Implement Initial Operating Capability (IOC) for the new DTIC unclassified content management system in the DoD-hosted cloud.  
-- Determine a solution to securely transfer data between the unclassified and classified content management systems.
- Acquire a solution and initiate implementation of consolidated DTIC data collections into one common storage infrastructure (the Master Data Repository) for increased analysis capabilities across the suite of collections.
- Strengthen access controls to the DoD Research and Engineering (R&amp;E) Gateway and other DTIC provided tools with the introduction of smart-card login for eligible users within the federal government and defense industry.
- Meet DoD’s audit readiness milestones and requirements.
- Begin the planning and implementation of data center migration to a DoD-CIO approved facility and/or cloud service.  Transition public-facing DTIC websites into the commercial cloud.
- Implement the data center IT hardware and software refresh, reducing the both the physical footprint and related support costs, while improving system security and reliability.   
- Align with DoD initiative for the Federal Data Center Consolidation Initiatives (FDCCI) to maximize the virtualization of DTIC systems and applications and how to best support DoD, industry partners, and academia users.</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                <r2:Funding>46.027</r2:Funding>
                                                            </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                <r2:Funding>46.027</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>- Support DoD’s public access effort; implement Phase I, intramural basic research, including compliance tracking and enforcement for public access, and the policy development process for contracts and grants.
-- Implement a catalog/locator to track data set locations.
-- Process journal articles, and look into hosting smaller data sets in support of intramural research.
-- Begin pilot projects for voluntary submission of contract and grant published articles and data sets.
- Evaluate metrics, usage patterns and new user requirements to determine and implement more advanced, integrated capabilities for the DoD Research and Engineering (R&amp;E) Gateway collaboration, search and analytics on the NIPRNET and SIPRNET.
-- Expand outreach to the DTIC user community and DoD science and technology (S&amp;T) communities of interest (COIs) by offering onsite briefings, demonstrations and training for the R&amp;E Gateway search and collaborative tools.
- Expand Defense Innovation Marketplace search and analytic capabilities in alignment with the Department’s Better Buying Power 3.0 initiative; add small business research information.
-- Employ the Marketplace for virtual Technical Information Meetings with industry in communities of interest areas.
- Offer enhanced Unified Research and Engineering Database (URED) capabilities and training for the user community, to include advanced search and visualization functionalities to support better decision making across the Department.
- Implement a reporting and dashboard capability in the International Agreements Database (IADB).
- Implement Full Operating Capability (FOC) of DTIC standard library content management system in the DoD-hosted cloud; implement a classified version.
-- Consolidate report collection into a DTIC standard input solution, reducing the footprint of multiple technologies and driving efficiencies and cost avoidance.
- Implement Full Operating Capability of the Master Data Repository (MDR) solution to consolidate DTIC data collections into one common storage infrastructure for increased analysis and visualization capabilities across the suite of collections.
-- Implement a classified version of the MDR.
-- Expand the collections available to DTIC users with an advanced, integrated search on both the NIPRNET and SIPRNET.
- Collaborate with the DoD Intelligence community on policy and planning for the implementation of the new Controlled Unclassified Information (CUI) federal marking regulations.
- Meet DoD’s audit readiness milestones and requirements.
- Align with DoD Joint Information Environment (JIE) initiative for the Federal Data Center Consolidation Initiatives (FDCCI) by maximizing the virtualization of DTIC systems and applications that services all of the DoD, industry partners, and academia users.
- Plan and implement the data center migration to a DoD-CIO approved cloud service provider, based on final guidance from the Department.</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                        </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                    </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                                <r2:PerformanceMetrics>Community Interaction
1) New Registered Users:  13,580

2) Total Unique NIPRNET Users:  23,952

Research Support and Library Repository
1) Scientific and technical information (STI) collected (NIPRNET):  77,391  

2) Total STI disseminated, to include competed work reports, work-in-progress summaries, and industry IR&amp;D, digitization requests, and web inquiries
- Access Control Downloads (NIPRNET):  221,928 (+140% increase from FY 2013 levels)
- Public Document Downloads:  35,291,044 (+50% increase from FY 2013 levels)

3) Total STI holdings:  3.9M</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                                            </r2:R2aExhibit>
                                        </r2:Project>
                                        <r2:Project>
                                            <r2:ProjectNumber>002</r2:ProjectNumber>
                                            <r2:ProjectTitle>Information Analysis Centers</r2:ProjectTitle>
                                            <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                                            <r2:ProjectFunding>
                                                <r2:PriorYear>7.053</r2:PriorYear>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>5.748</r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>5.748</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>5.748</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearTwo>5.748</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearThree>5.748</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearFour>5.748</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearFive>5.748</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:ProjectFunding>
                                            <r2:R2aExhibit>
                                                <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>DoD Information Analysis Centers (IACs), established under DoD Instruction 3200.14, serve as a vital resource in providing timely, relevant information directly to users when and where it is needed. IACs serve as a bridge between the warfighter and the Acquisition/Research community, providing essential technical analysis and data support to a diverse customer base, to include the Combatant Commands (CCMDs), the Office of the Secretary of Defense, Defense Agencies, and the Military Services. IACs actively partner and collaborate with Defense Research and Engineering (R&amp;E) focus groups and communities of interest in areas of specialized fields or specific technologies. The IACs create and maintain comprehensive knowledge analysis centers that include historical, technical, scientific, and other data and information collected worldwide. They are staffed with scientists, engineers and information specialists to provide research and analysis to customers with diverse, complex and challenging requirements. IAC operations directly support the warfighter, and play an ongoing and critical role in solving key CCMD operational issues such as cyber security, unmanned aerial vehicle visual/audible signature reduction, and improvements to the ballistic resistance of body armor.  

The IAC Program Management Office at DTIC performs contract acquisition, management, and operational support for IAC contract operations and the technical information that is generated as a result of research and studies.  In a time of shrinking budgets and increasing responsibility, IACs are a valuable resource for accessing scientific and technical information culled from efforts to solve new and historic challenges. Direct IAC customer support activities, such as Technical Area Task (TAT) order processing, Basic Center Operations (BCO) support, Defense Finance and Accounting Service (DFAS) activities, contracting/acquisition related activities, etc., are funded in part through partnerships with the Defense R&amp;E community and the annual collection of customer reimbursements for shared direct costs, in accordance with the IAC Reimbursable Review Board (IRRB) recommendations, with OSD-COMPT and Office of General Counsel concurrence. This represents the maximum cost-sharing with IAC customers allowable, per guidance from the OSD Office of General Counsel. Annual IAC efforts and accomplishments are dependent on the level of participation and collaboration by the R&amp;E community at large.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                                    <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                        <r2:Title>Information Analysis Centers</r2:Title>
                                                        <r2:Accomplishment>
                                                            <r2:PriorYear>
                                                                <r2:Funding>7.053</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>- Supported the DTIC mission to provide technical information to DoD.
- Provided administrative oversight and basic core contract operations for DoD IACs to collect, analyze, synthesize and disseminate worldwide scientific and technical information (STI) in support of DoD's critical technologies and the warfighter.
- Responded to technical inquiries and provide in-depth science and technology (S&amp;T) analysis; created and provided STI results via IAC websites; captured STI products from new/on-going analysis tasks; and supported the exchange of information among members of the operational and technical communities.
- Completed IAC Program restructuring to achieve the following objectives:
-- Created and sustained a focus on the Better Buying Power initiatives to improve affordability, productivity, and standardization within defense acquisition programs.
-- Expanded scope to cover areas of emerging importance for the DoD (including energetics, autonomous systems, biometrics, alternative energy, and medical research).
-- Increased participation of small business in supporting exchanges of technical and operational information across the DoD.
-- Expanded the industrial base – from single vendors to multiple vendors in each technical focus area, lowering cost and improving quality through enhanced competition.
- Awarded small business set-aside contract for Defense Systems Basic Center Operations (BCO), as well as multiple award indefinite delivery, indefinite quantity (IDIQ) contracts for Homeland Defense and Security Technical Area Tasks (TATs) and Defense Systems TATs.  Provided over $1.0 Billion in new opportunities to small business.
- Managed and supported TATs ordered by the DoD and non-DoD customers; provide program strategy and ensure alignment with Department goals/direction.
- Began planning for the re-compete of the Software, Networks, Information, Modeling and Simulation (SNIM) contract to a new contract vehicle, Cyber Systems Technical Area Tasks (CS TAT).</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:PriorYear>
                                                        </r2:Accomplishment>
                                                        <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                            <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                <r2:Funding>5.748</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>- Support the DTIC mission to provide technical information to DoD.
- Provide administrative oversight and basic core contract operations for DoD IACs to collect, analyze, synthesize and disseminate worldwide scientific and technical information (STI) in support of DoD's critical technologies and the warfighter.
- Respond to technical inquiries and provide in-depth science and technology (S&amp;T) analysis; create and provide STI results via IAC websites; capture STI products from new/on-going analysis tasks; and support the exchange of information among members of the operational and technical communities.
- Manage and support TATs ordered by the DoD and non-DoD customers; provide program strategy and ensure alignment with Department goals/direction.
- Finalize acquisition strategy for the re-compete of the SNIM contract to Cyber Systems Technical Area Tasks (CS TAT).
- Effectively manage a 217 percent workload increase by transitioning 326 existing TATs from legacy contracts (CBRNIAC, WSTIAC, SURVIAC) to multi-award contracts (on top of the approximately 150 new TATs awarded annually).
- Establish a Technology Domain Awareness (TDA) initiative to leverage commercial innovation having defense applications by re-using scientific and technical information in the development and support of DoD weapons systems prototypes.</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                <r2:Funding>5.748</r2:Funding>
                                                            </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                <r2:Funding>5.748</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>- Support the DTIC mission to provide technical information to DoD.
- Provide administrative oversight and basic core contract operations for DoD IACs to collect, analyze, synthesize and disseminate worldwide scientific and technical information (STI) in support of DoD's critical technologies and the warfighter.
- Respond to technical inquiries and provide in-depth science and technology (S&amp;T) analysis; create and provide STI results via IAC websites; capture STI products from new/on-going analysis tasks; and support the exchange of information among members of the operational and technical communities.
- Manage and support TATs ordered by the DoD and non-DoD customers; provide program strategy and ensure alignment with Department goals/direction.
- Plan for the acquisition and re-compete of the Software, Networks, Information, Modeling and Simulation (SNIM) contract.
- Effectively manage a 144 percent workload increase by transitioning 216 existing TATs from legacy contracts (SENSIAC, RIAC, AMMTIAC) to multi-award contracts (on top of the approximately 150 new TATs awarded annually).
- Complete award of new multi-award contract for CS TAT.
- Further build out the Technology Domain Awareness (TDA) initiative by formalizing relationships with non-traditional industry partners to accelerate future technology innovation in the areas of Homeland Defense, Cyber Systems, and Defense Systems.</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                        </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                    </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                                <r2:PerformanceMetrics>Number of:
- IAC web inquiries:  3,577,707 for FY14 
- IAC technical inquiries:  4,484 for FY14 
- STI documents added to IAC collection:  30,798 for FY14 (up 14% from FY13)
- STI documents generated by Technical Area Tasks (TAT) activities:  6,895 for FY14 
- Training or meeting events: 1,381 for FY14 (up 44% from FY13)
- Number of training attendees: 7,390 for FY14 
- Documents uploaded to DTIC's online repository: 37,263 for FY14 (up 82% from FY13)

Amount of funding:
- Provided by external customer requesting IAC technical analysis (TAT Funding):  $1.82 Billion for FY14 (up 18% from FY13)
- Provided by external customers purchasing IAC information products (Non-TAT funding):  $434,469 for FY14 

Customer satisfaction regarding:
- IAC products and technical inquiry support (scale of 1 to 5, 5 being best): 4.8 for FY14 
- IAC TATs and training (scale of 1 to 5, 5 being best): 4.8 for FY14</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                                            </r2:R2aExhibit>
                                        </r2:Project>
                                    </r2:ProjectList>
                                </r2:ProgramElement>
                            </r2:R2Exhibit>
                        </r2:R2ExhibitList>
                    </jb:JustificationBook>
                </jb:JustificationBookInfo>
            </jb:JustificationBookInfoList>
        </jb:JustificationBookGroup>
    </jb:JustificationBookGroupList>
</jb:MasterJustificationBook>