<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jb:JustificationBook xmlns:jb="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/jb" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
    <jb:Title>Justification Book</jb:Title>
    <jb:BudgetYear>2014</jb:BudgetYear>
    <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
    <jb:SubmissionDate>2013-04</jb:SubmissionDate>
    <jb:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
    <jb:AppropriationCode>0400</jb:AppropriationCode>
    <jb:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</jb:AppropriationName>
    <jb:CoverPage/>
    <jb:ExternalDocuments>
        <jb:UserR1Doc>
            <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit R-1</jb:Title>
            <jb:FileName>TJS FY2014 R1C.pdf</jb:FileName>
        </jb:UserR1Doc>
    </jb:ExternalDocuments>
    <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        <jb:ForceEvenPages>true</jb:ForceEvenPages>
        <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>
        <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>
        <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>
        <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>
    </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
    <r2:R2ExhibitList xmlns:r2="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/r2" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
        <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElement format="R2Long">
                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0603828J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Joint Experimentation</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                <r2:R1LineItemNumber>65</r2:R1LineItemNumber>
                <r2:BudgetYear>2014</r2:BudgetYear>
                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                <r2:SubmissionDate>2013-04</r2:SubmissionDate>
                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>3</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Advanced Technology Development (ATD)</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                    <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>21.230</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>12.667</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>12.667</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>14.719</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>15.169</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>13.839</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>13.997</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Joint Experimentation (JE) Program Element provides funding for the Department’s Joint Concept Development &amp; Experimentation (JCD&amp;E) effort, carried out by the JCD&amp;E Community.  The JCD&amp;E Community is comprised of the Combatant Commands, Services, the Office of the Secretary of Defense (OSD), the Joint Staff, the National Guard Bureau (NGB), the United States Coast Guard (USCG) and several Defense agencies.  Intra-government agencies and coalition partners often participate in JCD&amp;E processes and projects.  The Director for Joint Force Development (DJ-7) leads the joint force development efforts on behalf of the Chairman.  The J-7 staff coordinates all efforts with respect to the JCD&amp;E Community.

To ensure the program focuses on needs of the warfighters, JCD&amp;E initiatives originate from an annual call for nominations from combatant commands and Services, and from assessment of Combatant Command identified critical warfighting capability gaps articulated in the Comprehensive Joint Assessment (CJA).  JCD&amp;E project submissions undergo preliminary analysis by the JCD&amp;E Community to confirm suitability for experimentation and, where feasible, to associate closely related subjects for economy of effort.  Preliminary analysis also confirms alignment to the Chairman’s priorities for developing Joint Force 2020 and Defense Planning Guidance (DPG) strategic priority areas.  The resulting annual list of project submissions includes concepts for development and experimentation efforts eligible for design and execution.  These efforts are prioritized and approved by the Combatant Command and Service members of the Synchronization Board and forwarded to the Joint Capabilities Board (JCB)/Joint Requirements Oversight Council (JROC) for approval.

JCD&amp;E activities examine potential solutions for combatant command operational needs emphasizing non-materiel solutions through targeted Doctrine, Organizational, Training, Leadership and Education, Personnel, Facilities, and Policy (DOT_LPF-P) improvements.  JCD&amp;E tackles joint concept and capability issues demanding sophisticated analysis, innovative design and complex execution.  JCD&amp;E projects address topics that would prove difficult for individual combatant commands and Services to capture in the context of their immediate operational and force generation responsibilities.  In partnership with the combatant commands and Services, JCD&amp;E mitigates operational risk by establishing procedural models to conduct emergent concepts that are not yet instantiated in conventional force generation.  The results are briefed to Functional Capability Boards (FCB) who integrate solutions into their functional investment plans.

Funding will be distributed to meet requirements, retaining the flexibility to develop field-sustainable joint capabilities that may be required to meet future, unforeseen challenges.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>21.230</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>21.667</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>21.667</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>21.230</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>12.667</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>12.667</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>-9.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-9.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                        <r2:CongressionalGeneralReductions>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        </r2:CongressionalGeneralReductions>
                        <r2:CongressionalDirectedReductions>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        </r2:CongressionalDirectedReductions>
                        <r2:CongressionalRescissions>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        </r2:CongressionalRescissions>
                        <r2:CongressionalAdds>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        </r2:CongressionalAdds>
                        <r2:CongressionalDirectedTransfers>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        </r2:CongressionalDirectedTransfers>
                        <r2:Reprogrammings>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        </r2:Reprogrammings>
                        <r2:SBIRSTTRTransfer>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        </r2:SBIRSTTRTransfer>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>FY2014 Program Adjustment</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>-9.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-9.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                    </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                    <r2:SummaryExplanation>The Chairman, Joint Chiefs of Staff has directed the J7 to transform the Joint Experimentation program.  The reduction in funding between FY2013 and FY2014 is part of the transformation from Joint Experimentation to a Joint Assessment program.

FY2014 efforts will focus on supporting the President’s “Sustaining U.S. Global Leadership Priorities for the 21st Century Defense” with emphasis on implementing the Joint Operational Access Concept, and building Joint Force 2020 as described in the Chairman Joint Chiefs of Staff Capstone Concept for Joint Operations.  Specific work will focus on concepts, and gap analysis and the resultant recommended non-materiel solutions that will improve current and future joint force capability including operating in anti-access and area denial environments, joint command &amp; control, intercontinental missile defense, counterterrorism, operations in space, and defeating threats in all domains, including cyber.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:ProjectList>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>P01</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Joint Experimentation</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>21.230</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>12.667</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>12.667</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>14.719</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>15.169</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>13.839</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>13.997</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Experimentation (JE) Program Element provides funding for the Department’s Joint Concept Development &amp; Experimentation (JCD&amp;E) effort, carried out by the JCD&amp;E Community.

The JCD&amp;E Community is comprised of the Combatant Commands, Services, the Office of the Secretary of Defense (OSD), the Joint Staff, the National Guard Bureau (NGB), the United States Coast Guard (USCG) and several Defense agencies. Intra-government agencies and coalition partners often participate in JCD&amp;E processes and projects. The Director for Joint Force Development (DJ-7) leads the joint force development efforts on behalf of the Chairman. The J-7 staff coordinates all efforts with respect to the JCD&amp;E Community.

To ensure the program focuses on needs of the warfighters, JCD&amp;E initiatives originate from an annual call for nominations from combatant commands and Services, and from assessment of combatant command identified critical warfighting capability gaps articulated in the Comprehensive Joint Assessment (CJA). JCD&amp;E project submissions undergo preliminary analysis by the JCD&amp;E Community to confirm suitability for experimentation and, where feasible, to associate closely related subjects for economy of effort. Preliminary analysis also confirms alignment to the Chairman’s priorities for developing Joint Force 2020 and Defense Planning Guidance (DPG) strategic priority areas. The resultant annual list of project submissions includes concepts for development and experimentation efforts eligible for design and execution. These efforts are prioritized and approved by the combatant command and Service members of the Synchronization Board and forwarded to the JCB/JROC for approval.

JCD&amp;E activities examine potential solutions for combatant command operational needs emphasizing non-materiel solutions through targeted Doctrine, Organizational, Training, Leadership and Education, Personnel, Facilities, and Policy (DOT_LPF-P) improvements. JCD&amp;E tackles joint concept and capability issues demanding sophisticated analysis, innovative design and complex execution. JCD&amp;E projects address topics that would prove difficult for individual combatant commands and Services to capture in the context of their immediate operational and force generation responsibilities. In partnership with the combatant commands and Services, JCD&amp;E mitigates operational risk by establishing procedural models to conduct emergent concepts that are not yet instantiated in conventional force generation. The results are briefed to Functional Capability Boards who integrate solutions into their functional investment plans.

Funding will be distributed to meet requirements, retaining the flexibility to develop field-sustainable joint capabilities that may be required to meet future, unforeseen challenges.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Joint Experimentation</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>The Joint Experimentation (JE) Program Element provides funding for the Department’s Joint Concept Development &amp; Experimentation (JCD&amp;E) effort, carried out by the JCD&amp;E Community.

The JCD&amp;E Community is comprised of the Combatant Commands, Services, the Office of the Secretary of Defense (OSD), the Joint Staff, the National Guard Bureau (NGB), the United States Coast Guard (USCG) and several Defense agencies. Intra-government agencies and coalition partners often participate in JCD&amp;E processes and projects. The Director for Joint Force Development (DJ-7) leads the joint force development efforts on behalf of the Chairman. The J-7 staff coordinates all efforts with respect to the JCD&amp;E Community.</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>21.230</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>The FY2013 Program of Work will include projects supporting the President’s “Sustaining U.S. Global Leadership Priorities for the 21st Century Defense.” Specific projects will focus on capabilities critical to the success of the future joint force, including intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance; counterterrorism; countering weapons of mass destruction; operating in anti-access environments and prevailing in all domains, including cyber.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>12.667</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>12.667</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>The Chairman, Joint Chiefs of Staff has directed the J7 to transform the Joint Experimentation program.  The reduction in funding between FY2013 and FY2014 is part of the transformation from Joint Experimentation to a Joint Assessment program.

FY2014 efforts will focus on supporting the President’s “Sustaining U.S. Global Leadership Priorities for the 21st Century Defense” with emphasis on implementing the Joint Operational Access Concept, and building Joint Force 2020 as described in the Chairman Joint Chiefs of Staff Capstone Concept for Joint Operations.  Specific work will focus on concepts, and gap analysis and the resultant recommended non-materiel solutions that will improve current and future joint force capability including operating in anti-access and area denial environments, joint command &amp; control, intercontinental missile defense, counterterrorism, operations in space, and defeating threats in all domains, including cyber.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>N/A</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>JCD&amp;A efforts result in development of and integration or transition of concepts and capabilities to improve current and future joint force capability, and are measured by the following:
(1) Concepts accounted for lessons learned reports, JCOA studies, training exercises, past wargames, previous operations, and other historically captured events.
(2) Collaborated with a broad, cross-cutting representation from Services, Academia, CCMDs, Defense Agencies, and Industry.
(3) Introduced innovative operating methods leading to DOTmLPF changes.
(4) Vetted through a deliberate, rigorous, process resulting in Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff (CJCS) endorsement.
(5) Approved by CJCS.
(6) Capabilities identified in concepts are described in a way to facilitate transition to gap analysis.
(7) Assessments have considered concepts, lessons learned, operational studies, and planned/projected force capabilities.
(8) Assessments are coordinated with relevant community of practice, current subject matter experts, industry, academia, and appropriate multinational partners.
(9) Assessments are completed in a responsive and timely manner, and staffed in accordance with established Department of Defense policy and guidelines.
(10) Provided sound, supportable recommendations derived from assessments that succinctly addressed identified gaps with practical and actionable options that indirectly or directly improved capabilities.
(11) Recommendations were appropriately transitioned to designated action offices of responsibility.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                </r2:ProjectList>
            </r2:ProgramElement>
        </r2:R2Exhibit>
        <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElement>
                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0604445J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Wide Area Surveillance</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                <r2:R1LineItemNumber>104</r2:R1LineItemNumber>
                <r2:BudgetYear>2014</r2:BudgetYear>
                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                <r2:SubmissionDate>2013-04</r2:SubmissionDate>
                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>4</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Advanced Component Development &amp; Prototypes (ACD&amp;P)</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                    <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>30.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>30.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>This program element is new to the Joint Staff and funds the continued management, advanced research and development and prototype evaluation of Homeland Surveillance technologies with the goal of improved Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense in the homeland. Additional details of the program are classified.

FY14 activities include, but are not limited to, advanced technology development, program management and those efforts to support transition of the program to the U.S. Air Force in FY2015.

This program is in Budget Activity 4, Advance Component Development and Prototypes (ACD&amp;P) because efforts are necessary to evaluate integrated technologies, representative modes or prototype systems in a high fidelity and realistic operating environment. 

Details of this project are classified.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>30.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>30.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>30.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>30.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:SummaryExplanation>This is a new Program Element on the Joint Staff in FY2014 and will transfer to the U. S. Air Force in FY2015.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:ProjectList>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>P001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Wide Area Surveillance</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>30.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>30.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>This program element is new to the Joint Staff and funds the continued management, advanced research and development and prototype evaluation of Homeland Surveillance technologies with the goal of improved Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense in the homeland. Additional details of the program are classified.

FY14 activities include, but are not limited to, advanced technology development, program management and those efforts to support transition of the program to the U.S. Air Force in FY2015.

This program is in Budget Activity 4, Advance Component Development and Prototypes (ACD&amp;P) because efforts are necessary to evaluate integrated technologies, representative modes or prototype systems in a high fidelity and realistic operating environment. 

Details of this project are classified.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Wide Area Surveillance</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>30.000</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>30.000</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Details of this program are classified.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Details of this program are classified.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>Details of this program are classified.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:R3Exhibit>
                            <r2:Remarks>To be determined.</r2:Remarks>
                            <r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                                <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                    <r2:Name>Product Development</r2:Name>
                                    <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>TBD</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:ContractMethod>C</r2:ContractMethod>
                                            <r2:ContractType>TBD</r2:ContractType>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>TBD</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>TBD</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>30.000</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>30.000</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2013-09</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                    </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                            </r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                        </r2:R3Exhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                </r2:ProjectList>
            </r2:ProgramElement>
        </r2:R2Exhibit>
        <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElement>
                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0604787J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Joint Systems Integration</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                <r2:R1LineItemNumber>108</r2:R1LineItemNumber>
                <r2:BudgetYear>2014</r2:BudgetYear>
                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                <r2:SubmissionDate>2013-04</r2:SubmissionDate>
                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>4</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Advanced Component Development &amp; Prototypes (ACD&amp;P)</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                    <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>3.273</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.402</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.402</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>7.546</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>7.655</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>7.754</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>7.902</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>In support of the Chairman’s responsibility for the assessment of the capability and adequacy of United States forces to successfully execute the national military strategy the Joint Systems Integration (JSI) Program Element provides mission funding for the Joint Staff J6 C4 Assessments Division (C4AD). C4AD conducts interoperability assessments and develops solutions/recommendations to improve integration of Service, Defense Agency, and coalition systems. 

C4AD's Persistent Command and Control Environment replicates an operational environment and provides Combatant Commands, Services, Agencies and Coalition partners at the joint force headquarters level, a laboratory and assessment venue for the warfighter and capability developer to identify and solve interoperability and integration issues with current and near-term joint and coalition capabilities. With this capability, C4AD assesses system of systems interoperability, operational capability, procedural compliance and technical suitability of emerging and existing systems and programs to confirm readiness for deployment.  

By establishing ground truth for interoperability and suggesting remedies for demonstrated shortfalls, C4AD is an enabler for the Chairman’s priorities to: pioneer new ways to combine and employ emergent capabilities, drive Jointness deeper, sooner in capability development, move quickly toward Joint information and simulation networks that support secure and agile command and control, expand the envelope of interagency and international cooperation, and promote multilateral security approaches and architectures.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>3.273</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.275</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.275</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>3.273</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.402</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.402</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>4.127</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>4.127</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>Program adjustment</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>4.127</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>4.127</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                    </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                    <r2:SummaryExplanation>Additional resources allocated to support mission requirements that transitioned to the Joint Staff after U.S. Joint Forces Command disestablishment.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:ProjectList>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>P787</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Joint Systems Integration</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>3.273</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.402</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.402</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>7.546</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>7.655</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>7.754</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>7.902</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>In support of the Chairman’s responsibility for the assessment of the capability and adequacy of United States forces to successfully execute the national military strategy the Joint Systems Integration (JSI) Program Element provides mission funding for the Joint Staff J6 C4 Assessments Division (C4AD). C4AD conducts interoperability assessments and develops solutions/recommendations to improve integration of Service, Defense Agency, and coalition systems. 

C4AD's Persistent Command and Control Environment replicates an operational environment and provides Combatant Commands, Services, Agencies and Coalition partners at the joint force headquarters level, a laboratory and assessment venue for the warfighter and capability developer to identify and solve interoperability and integration issues with current and near-term joint and coalition capabilities. With this capability, C4AD assesses system of systems interoperability, operational capability, procedural compliance and technical suitability of emerging and existing systems and programs to confirm readiness for deployment.  

By establishing ground truth for interoperability and suggesting remedies for demonstrated shortfalls, C4AD is an enabler for the Chairman’s priorities to: pioneer new ways to combine and employ emergent capabilities, drive Jointness deeper, sooner in capability development, move quickly toward Joint information and simulation networks that support secure and agile command and control, expand the envelope of interagency and international cooperation, and promote multilateral security approaches and architectures.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Interoperability Assessments (IA) and Interoperability Technology Demonstration Center (ITDC) </r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>Primary outcome for this effort is seamless interoperability between DoD and coalition C2 systems supporting the warfighter.  IA supports the interoperability assessment of systems in five categories: operational, system of systems, technical, software, and procedural.  These assessments provide supporting justification for continued development of a program within the acquisition system and resolve capability shortfalls of fielded systems.</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>1.276</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Continue the efforts initiated for FY 2012 and respond to unpredictable operational issues and shortfalls.  Interoperability assessments will be conducted to solve warfighter problems, including coalition challenges.  FY 2013 assessment objectives are focused on; Operations and Intelligence Integration, Tactical Edge Integration, Joint Fires Capabilities, Integrated Air Missile Defense, Data Strategy Implementation, and Information Sharing Capabilities.   

Future Mission Network (FMN) Development and Assessment – Provide interoperability assessments of selected U.S. and Coalition systems in support of FMN. 
 
Afghanistan Mission Network (AMN) Coalition Interoperability Assurance Validation (CIAV) Assessments – AMN is the primary Coalition, Command, Control and Communications and Computers, Intelligence, Surveillance, and Reconnaissance (C5ISR) network for International Assistance Forces (ISAF) in Afghanistan.  C4AD is supporting the assessment of Coalition Mission Threads (CMTs) and Coalition Tactics, Techniques and Procedures (CTTPs) to identify and correct ISAF interoperability problems.  FY 2013 AMN mission areas include: Joint ISR, Battlespace Awareness, and Service Management.  
Bold Quest (BQ) 2013 Technical Support and Mode V/IFF (identify frend or foe) Interoperability Assessments – Assess interoperability and document identified deficiencies of select systems within the joint fires mission thread during Bold Quest 13 operational venues.  

Joint Fires Support Joint Mission Thread (JFS JMT) – Develop, assess, and document identified deficiencies in the operational fire support system interoperability matrix.  Initial fire support systems to be evaluated include: Advanced Field Artillery Tactical Data System (AFATDS), Distributed Command Ground Station (DCGS), Joint Automated Deep Operations Coordination System (JADOCS), Theater Battle Management Core System (TBMCS), and Joint Targeting Tool-Kit (JTT).

C4 – Intelligence, Surveillance, Reconnaissance (C4ISR) Interoperability Assessments of DCGS and GCCS-J – Verify correction of interoperability issues identified in FY 12 assessments of the Global Command and Control System-Joint (GCCS-J) to Distributed Common Ground Station-Army (DCGS-A) and GCCS-J to DCGS Integration Backbone (DIB) interfaces.

Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO) Assessment Joint Tactical Air Picture (JTAP) Support – Assess the integration of tactical data into a capability approaching single integrated air picture standards for track reporting, timeliness, and joint interoperable data sharing of both friendly and threat air and missile defense tracks during JTAP events.

Unified Cross Domain Management Office (UCDMO) Enterprise Cross Domain Solutions (ECDS) Owl File Transfer Interoperability Assessment - Conduct a capability assessment of the Owl Enterprise Cross Domain Solution, measuring the functional strengths and weaknesses against UCDMO prescribed criteria.

Coalition Warrior Interoperability Experiment (CWIX) 2013 Interoperability Assessments – Conduct interoperability assessments between selected systems within the following mission areas; Coalition fires, Coalition Intelligence, Surveillance, Reconnaissance (ISR), and Coalition Ballistic Missile Defense during the CWIX event.

Tactical Infrastructure Enterprise Services (TIES) JCTD Assessment – Assess the capability of sharing data from authoritative data sources using web services in a C2 Core conformant, standardized data format.  

Joint Cross Domain eXchange (JCDX) Interoperability Assessment – Assess JCDX, a multi-level security capability, to exchange the common operation picture and support record/tactical communications interfaces between U.S. and Coalition forces.

Italy-U.S. Command and Control Interoperability Assessment – Continue assessing the exchange of C2 data between the U.S. Global Command and Control System Joint (GCCS-J) and the Italian SIACCON (Sistema Automatizzato di Commando e Controllo) system.  SIACCON is a distributed C2 system that provides battle management support across a range of functions for the Italian Army. 
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>2.894</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>2.894</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Continue the efforts initiated for FY2013 and respond to unpredictable operational issues and shortfalls. Interoperability assessments will be conducted to solve warfighter problems, including coalition challenges.  FY2014 assessment objectives are focused on; Cyberspace, Operations and Intelligence Integration, Tactical Edge Integration, Joint Fires Capabilities, Integrated Air Missile Defense, Data Strategy Implementation, and Information Sharing Capabilities.
  
Afghanistan Mission Network (AMN) Coalition Interoperability Assurance Validation (CIAV) Transition and Assessments – AMN is the primary Coalition, Command, Control and Communications and Computers, Intelligence, Surveillance, and Reconnaissance (C5ISR) network for International Assistance Forces (ISAF)in Afghanistan.  C4AD is supporting the assessment of Coalition Mission Threads (CMTs) and Coalition Tactics, Techniques and Procedures (CTTPs) to identify and correct ISAF interoperability problems.  

Bold Quest (BQ) 2014 Technical Support and Interoperability Assessments – Assess interoperability and document identified deficiencies of select systems within the joint fires mission thread during BQ 2014 operational venues.

Digitally-Aided Joint Fires Support and Assessment – Assess the implementation of various  messaging standards for Close Air Support (CAS) mission execution. 

Coalition Warrior Interoperability Experiment (CWIX) 2014 Interoperability Assessments – Conduct interoperability assessments between selected systems within the following mission areas; Coalition fires, Coalition Intelligence, Surveillance, Reconnaissance (ISR), and Coalition Ballistic Missile Defense during the CWIX event.

Terminal Fury 2014 Joint Automated Deep Operations Coordination System (JADOCS)Interoperability Assessment – Assess the system interoperability of JADOCS during Terminal Fury 2014.

C4-Intelligence, Surveillance, Reconnaissance (C4ISR) Interoperability Assessments – Assess interoperability of Service systems to Global Command and Control System-Joint (GCCS-J).

Unified Cross Domain Management Office (UCDMO) Enterprise Cross Domain Solutions (ECDS) Capability Assessment - Conduct a capability assessment of the specified ECDS, measuring the functional strengths and weaknesses against UCDMO prescribed criteria.

Mission Partner Environment (MPE) U.S. Development and Assessment and Federated Mission Network (FMN)Development and Support – Provide interoperability assessments of selected U.S. and Coalition systems.

Network Integration Evaluation (NIE) Facility and Interoperability Assessment Support – Assess potential networked and non-networked capabilities in a robust operational environment.

Joint Staff J7/J6 Partnership for the Operational Assessment Test (OAT) of the Joint Live Virtual Constructive (JLVC)Modeling and Simulation (M&amp;S) Federation – Assess networked systems as directed. 

Tactical Infrastructure Enterprise Services (TIES) Limited Technology Experiment (LTE) JCTD Assessment – Assess the capability of sharing data from authoritative data sources using web services in a C2 cCore conformant, standardized data format.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Technical Assessments and Integration (TA&amp;I)</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>Primary Outcome (objective) for this effort is near-term technical solutions for integration, assessment and delivery of operational capabilities that address near-term operational and tactical requirements.  TA&amp;I uses organic laboratory resources, equipment, and technical personnel to integrate emerging technologies. </r2:Description>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>1.080</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Continue FY 2012 initiatives investigating impacts of technology advances in wireless devices, mesh and ad-hoc networking, satellite modem technology, and small lightweight secure digital capabilities on warfighter command and control capabilities and match emerging critical warfighter requirements with the technologies to identify near-term technology solutions supporting Combatant Commanders.  Areas of concentration include Tactical Edge Integration and Joint Command and Control Capabilities.

Celestial Reach Joint Capability Technical Demonstration (JCTD) Assessment – Continue integrating a wide-band antenna solution for joint air, ground, and maritime operations and assessing the capability’s utility in providing wide-band communications that support Command and Control (C2) and Intelligence Surveillance and Reconnaissance (ISR) applications to enroute users.

National Security Agency (NSA) Commercial Solutions for Classified (CSfC) Secure Wireless Local Area Network (SWLAN) Integration Assessment – Continue assisting NSA in the development and assessment of a Suite B software encryption solution. This capability supports communicating over SECRET wireless networks without using Type-1 hardware solutions (e.g., SecNet 54, Talon, or KG-250s).

Air/Event Information Sharing Service (A/EISS) Integration Assessment – Integrate an automated data handling capability that fuses and shares decision support data from national level authoritative sources enabling senior decision makers to make time-critical decisions during air events over North America via desktop or mobile devices.

US Navy 4G Long Term Evolution (LTE) Afloat Sea Trial Integration and Assessment – Integrate innovations in Fourth Generation (4G) LTE Cellular technologies and mobile Ka band spread spectrum satellite communications to deliver megabits of data to mobile and dismounted teams equipped with mobile devices in support of the counter-piracy mission.

C2 Applications over Broadband Cellular (C2 ABC) Integration and Assessment – Integrate and assess emerging C2 and tailored applications using broadband cellular technologies to provide the warfighter at the tactical edge with expanded situational awareness.

Joint Operational Long Term Evolution Deployable (JOLTED) – Tactical Cellular System (TACTICS) JCTD Technical Manager - JOLTED-TACTICS is an Internet Protocol (IP) based system designed to provide robust communications to dismounted Special Operations Forces (SOF) teams and General Purpose Company and below tactical users.  This system leverages innovations in Fourth Generation (4G) LTE Cellular technologies and mobile Ka band spread spectrum satellite communications to deliver megabits of data to mobile and dismounted teams armed with mobile devices such as smartphones or netbooks.

Tactitical Mobility Security Integration and Assessment (TMSIA) Spiral II – Integrate in partnership with the National Security Agency a security architecture for lightweight, man-portable communications-on-demand packages that allow the user to quickly establish secure 4G cellular wireless networks.

Digitally-aided Personnel Recovery (DaPR) Personnel Recovery Support System (PRSS) 1B Integration and Assessment – Integrate a digital solution to provide standardized increment 1B digital messages and forwarding rules for direct machine to machine transmissions to applicable C2 systems.
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>2.429</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>2.429</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Continue FY2013 initiatives investigating impacts of technology advances in wireless devices, mesh and ad-hoc networking, satellite modem technology, and small lightweight secure digital capabilities on warfighter command and control capabilities and match emerging critical warfighter requirements with the technologies to identify near-term technology solutions supporting Combatant Commanders.  Areas of concentration include Tactical Edge Integration and Joint Command and Control Capabilities.

Joint Operational Long Term Evolution Deployable (JOLTED) – Tactical Cellular System (TACTICS) Integration Project - JOLTED-TACTICS is an Internet Protocol (IP) based system designed to provide robust communications to dismounted Special Operations Forces (SOF) teams and General Purpose Company and below tactical users.  This system leverages innovations in Fourth Generation (4G) LTE Cellular technologies and mobile Ka band spread spectrum satellite communications to deliver megabits of data to mobile and dismounted teams armed with mobile devices such as smartphones or netbooks.

Joint Operational Long Term Evolution Deployable (JOLTED) – Tactical Cellular System (TACTICS) JCTD Technical Manager – Serve as the JCTD technical manager.

C2 Applications over Broadband Cellular (C2 ABC) Integration and Assessment – Integrate and assess emerging C2 and tailored applications using broadband cellular technologies to provide the warfighter at the tactical edge with expanded situational awareness.

Celestial Reach Joint Capability Technical Demonstration (JCTD) Assessment – Continue integrating a wide-band antenna solution for joint air, ground, and maritime operations and assessing the capability’s utility in providing wide-band communications that support Command and Control (C2) and Intelligence Surveillance and Reconnaissance (ISR) applications to enroute users.

Maritime/Event Information Sharing Service (M/EISS) Integration and Assessment – Integrate an automated data fusion capability into the Maritime Domain Awareness process.

National Security Agency (NSA) Commercial Solutions for Classified (CSfC) Secure Wireless Local Area Network (SWLAN) Integration Assessment – Continue assisting NSA in the development and assessment of a Suite B software encryption solution. This capability supports communicating over SECRET wireless networks without using Type-1 hardware solutions (e.g., SecNet 54, Talon, or KG-250s).

Joint Command and Control Adaptive Planning and Execution (APEX) Assessment – Integrate a common user interface that allosws warfighters to customize their desktop to preference and present capabilities that fit mission needs through cloud computing and enterprise collaboration services.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Persistent Command and Control Environment</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>The persistent command and control environment provides a reconfigurable Joint Task Force national and coalition laboratory that supports the rapid assessment and integration of existing and emerging C4 capabilities.  It is a venue for the Department and allied partners to collaborately assess capability and interoperability of current and future warfighting systems and when connected with other joint, service, agency, and coalition laboratories provides a robust and tailorable system of systems assessment and engineering environment.</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>0.917</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Continue FY 2012 initiatives by engaging the Services and Communities of Interest (COI) to leverage the capabilities of the Persistent Command and Control Environment by bringing joint solutions through C4AD's integration and operational assessment process.  Also continue to expand existing relationships with Service and Coalition laboratory and engineering organizations.

C4AD Project Engineering Support – Provide infrastructure, communications, network, information assurance, security, and engineering support as required.

</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>2.079</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>2.079</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Continue FY 2013 initiatives by engaging the Services and Communities of Interest (COI) to leverage the capabilities of the Persistent Command and Control Environment by bringing joint solutions through C4AD's integration and operational assessment process.  Provide a comprehensive Joint Task Force (JTF) environment required to also support cyber training, cyber capability development, and cyber assessment by expanding the connectivity and capability of the existing persistent environment to support the Enterprise Cyber Range Environment focused on  user requirements, architectures, standards, measures, metrics, instrumentation, and data collection. 

C4AD Project Engineering Support – Provide infrastructure, communications, network, information assurance, security, and engineering support as required.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>C4AD supports interoperability of systems selected for acquisition, integration and fielding.  C4AD is a forcing function to discover and provide interoperable joint solutions as a means to foster rapid, near-term insertion of command and control technology by promoting the ability to meet the DoD direction for spiral development and evolutionary acquisition.  Services and Defense Agencies are responsible for conducting acquisition activities in Programs of Record (POR).</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>FY 2013 Strategic Goals Supported:  Chairman’s Priorities to “Achieve our National Objectives in our Current Conflicts and Develop Joint Force 2020” by:
- Driving resolution of C4 interoperability problems with actionable recommendations stemming from technical and operational demonstrations and assessments of existing and emerging C4 capabilities.

- Integrating and assessing technical solutions that provide gap-filling capabilities to satisfy near-term operational requirements.

- Providing a persistent C4 environment replicating an operational Joint Task Force Headquarters and/or subordinate elements to conduct interoperability, capability, and integration assessments.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:R3Exhibit>
                            <r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                                <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                    <r2:Name>Product Development</r2:Name>
                                    <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>General/Contractor Engineering Support</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:ContractMethod>C</r2:ContractMethod>
                                            <r2:ContractType>CPFF</r2:ContractType>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>General Dynamics</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Hampton Roads, VA</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>1.340</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>4.102</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>4.102</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>Government Engineering Support</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>MIPR</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>Various DoD</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Various DoD</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.392</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.700</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.700</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>Travel</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>TBD</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>Various DoD</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Various DoD</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.134</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.300</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.300</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                    </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                    <r2:Name>Support</r2:Name>
                                    <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>Government Communications Support</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>MIPR</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>Various DoD</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Various DoD</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.252</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.300</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.300</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>PC4 Environment/Laboratories</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>Various</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>Various</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Various</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>1.155</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>2.000</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>2.000</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                    </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                            </r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                        </r2:R3Exhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                </r2:ProjectList>
            </r2:ProgramElement>
        </r2:R2Exhibit>
        <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElement format="R2Long">
                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0604828J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Joint FIRES Integration and Interoperability Team</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                <r2:R1LineItemNumber>110</r2:R1LineItemNumber>
                <r2:BudgetYear>2014</r2:BudgetYear>
                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                <r2:SubmissionDate>2013-04</r2:SubmissionDate>
                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>4</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Advanced Component Development &amp; Prototypes (ACD&amp;P)</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                    <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>7.364</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.506</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.506</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>7.661</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>7.799</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>7.944</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>8.055</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Joint Deployable Analysis Team (JDAT) mission is to conduct field analysis in an operationally relevant environment of current and emergent Command and Control (C2) information systems and associated procedures to measure capabilities and limitations and to identify shortfalls and root causes producing decision-quality data and cogent solutions to customers and stakeholders to improve Joint C2 integration and interoperability.

The JDAT is a compact cell of unique Subject Matter Experts and analysts adding value to much larger Service investments in force elements delivering kinetic and non kinetic effects. Services, Joint, and Combatant Commanders and their Staffs proactively seek JDAT advice and assistance to improve the execution of combat fires applied in complex coalition and joint environments. 

</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>7.364</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.506</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.506</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>7.364</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.506</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.506</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:SummaryExplanation>.

</r2:SummaryExplanation>
                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:ProjectList>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>P857</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Joint Deployable Analysis Team </r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>7.364</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.506</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.506</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>7.661</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>7.799</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>7.944</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>8.055</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Deployable Analysis Team (JDAT) mission is to employ scientific methods to research, investigate, test, assess, and evaluate current and emergent Joint command and control (C2) information systems and associated procedures.  These activities measure capabilities and limitations, identify shortfalls and root cause, recommend and verify solutions, and validate joint capabilities.  The resulting empirical outcomes influence Joint Capability development in areas such as Policy; Joint Doctrine; Tactics, Techniques and Procedures; integration of capabilities; and digital interoperability.  JDAT provides decision-quality data and cogent solutions to customers and stakeholders responsible for improving Joint C2 information systems integration and interoperability to inform acquisition decisions and ensure that Services and Agencies field interdependent and interoperable systems.

The emphasis of JDAT assessment efforts is the evaluation of C2 Information Systems and Procedures to provide Services and Agencies findings and recommendations based on quantifiable data in order to improve Joint C2 integration and interoperability. JDAT collects and analyzes data and provides observations, findings, conclusions, and recommendations to identify policy, Joint doctrine, tactics, techniques, and procedures (TTP); and material solutions and products that promote capability improvement.  Evaluations range from small, single-focus events to large, multi-event/venue exercises.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Joint Deployable Analysis Team (JDAT) - Command and Control (C2) Information Systems and Procedures Capability Assessments</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>JDAT conducts assessments in conjunction with Service and Combatant Command (CCMD) exercises, experiments, and test and evaluation events. 

The primary outputs and efficiencies include:
- Improvement in the Services’ ability to employ Joint C2 information systems
- Recommendations for C2 system integration and interoperability
- Ability to define appropriate Joint context during system acquisition or development
- Updates/revisions to C2 related Chairman Joint Chief Staff (CJCS) Instructions and Manuals
- Development of related Universal Joint Tasks (UJT) and Additional Task Detail (ATD)
- Updates and revisions to doctrine, TTP, and Joint publications
- Development/refinement of analytical tools (i.e. Data Collection Architecture for Analytical Feedback (DCAAF), Track Event Reconstruction Application (TERA), Joint Windows-based Warfare Assessment Model (JWinWAM))
- Recommended solutions integrated within the Joint Requirements Oversight Council (JROC) Joint Capabilities Integration and Development System (JCIDS) 
- Identification of specific Key Performance Parameters (KPPs) and Key System Attributes (KSAs) for new systems that meet Joint warfighter operational requirements to ensure Services and Agencies field interdependent and interoperable systems
- Increased effectiveness/confidence in combat identification processes and a reduction in fratricide
- Increased effectiveness and confidence in C2 information systems and associated procedures</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>7.364</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>- Provide analytical support to a Military Utility Assessment of coalition and U.S. C2 information systems and procedures at Bold Quest 13.  Provide instrumentation, data collection, data capture, real-time mission monitoring, and feedback to participants via daily debriefings.  Benefits will include improved ability to assess various participating coalition and U.S. systems, improved joint task execution, and an effective Military Utility Assessment of U.S. C2 information systems while greatly reducing the timeline required to provide fact-based recommendations.

- Assist Commander, Operational Test and Evaluation Force (COMOPTEVFOR) with Identification Friend or Foe (IFF) Mode 5 Level 1 Joint Operational Test Approach (JOTA) analysis to validate integration and interoperability of fielded systems.  Develop data collection and analysis methodologies, design and implement data collection architectures and conduct analysis requisite to meet JOTA objectives.  Determine any gaps or shortfalls in integration and interoperability of Mode 5 systems. Provide Service Operational Test Agencies and Program Managers with fact-based findings.

- Provide analytical support to assess technology integration and interoperability during JIAMDO Joint Tactical Air Picture assessment event.  Provide data collection, analysis and display using JDAT developed tools.  Benefits will include improvements in a Joint Common Operational Picture to battlespace managers.

- Team with U.S. Army Test and Evaluation Command to conduct a Director, Operational Test and Evaluation (DOT&amp;E) interoperability assessment for EUCOM during Austere Challenge 2013.  Provide data collection, analysis and display using JDAT developed tools.  Benefits will include improvements in a Joint Common Operational Picture to COCOM Air Operations Center.

- Provide C2 data collection and analytical support to the Joint Fires Support Executive Steering Committee.  Lead Engineering Change Implementation Group. Conduct Digitally Aided Close Air Support (DACAS) Coordinated Implementation risk reduction assessments to validate service compliance with requisite Engineering Change Proposals.  Benefits will include recommendations for Tactics, Techniques, and Procedures in the areas of standardization and digital interoperability and development of associated Universal Joint Tasks.

- Chair the Joint Close Air Support Executive Steering Committee (JCAS ESC) chartered Digitally Aided Close Air Support (DACAS) Engineering Change Implementation Group. Plan and execute testing and validation of DACAS engineering change proposals and coordinate implementation across the Department of Defense and partner nations.

- Update Joint Windows-based Warfare Assessment Model (JWinWAM), Data Collection Architecture for Analytical Feedback (DCAAF) and Multi-Interface Gateway (MIG) software development to support JDAT assessment activities and the efforts of other government agencies as directed.

- Define Universal Joint Task (UJT) Additional Task Detail (ATD) for tactical task TA 3.3.2 Control Tactical Airspace and refine ATD for TA 3.2.2 Conduct Close Air Support (CAS) and TA 3.2.1 Conduct Joint Fires.

- Provide subject matter expertise and tier 2 architecture products on development of the Joint Close Air Support (CAS) Joint Mission Thread (JMT) and Joint Fires JMT.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>7.506</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>7.506</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>- Continue providing analytical support to a demonstration of U.S./Coalition C2 information systems and procedures at JS J6 Bold Quest 14.  Provide instrumentation, data collection, data management, real-time mission monitoring, and feedback to participants via daily debriefings. Benefits will include improved ability to assess various participating coalition and U.S. systems, improved joint task execution, and an effective demonstration of U.S./Coalition C2 information systems.

-Analytical support to assess DoD, Inter-Agency, and Industry’s counter-unmanned aircraft systems (C-UAS) capabilities across the IAMD joint engagement sequence during JS J8 Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO) Black Dart 2014 demonstration. Provide data collection, analysis, display, and feedback using JDAT developed tools. Benefits will include improvements to surveillance, detection, tracking, identification, and engagement of counter-unmanned aircraft systems.

-Team with U.S. Army Test and Evaluation Command to conduct DOT&amp;E interoperability and information assurance (cyberspace) assessments for USNORTHCOM during Exercise Vigilant Shield 2014. Provide C2 information system data collection and analysis using JDAT developed tools and correlate with red team network penetrations and actions using USA Threat Systems Management Office developed tools. Benefits will include improvements in combatant command’s Joint cyber center defensive cyberspace operations through improved situational awareness and understanding the impact on procedures supporting the commander’s decision cycle.

- Continue teaming with DOT&amp;E for FY 2014 combatant commands’ interoperability assessments. Provide data collection, analysis and display using JDAT developed tools. Benefits will include improvements in U.S. and Coalition C2 information systems interoperability, processes and procedures in support of the commander’s decision cycle.
- Continue providing analytical support to the Joint Personnel Recovery Agency by assessing selected engineering change proposals, identifying interoperability shortfalls, and recommending solutions.  Benefits include an end-to-end digitized Joint personnel recovery process.

- Continue providing C2 data collection and analytical support to the Joint Fires Support ESC.  Chair the Engineering Change Implementation Group.  Conduct Digitally Aided Fires (DACAS and Fires) Coordinated Implementation risk reduction assessments to validate service compliance with requisite ECPs. Plan and execute testing and validation of ECPs and coordinate implementation across the DoD and partner nations.  Benefits will include recommendations in the areas of interoperability, standardization, and development of associated Universal Joint Tasks and TTP.

- Continue to update JWinWAM, DCAAF, MIG, and TERA analysis software to support DOD-wide test and evaluation through the JMETC program.

- Continue to define UJT ATD for tactical task (TA) 3.3.2 Control Tactical Airspace and refine ATD for TA 3.2.2 Conduct CAS and TA 3.2.1 Conduct Joint Fires.

- Continue to provide subject matter expertise and architecture products on development of the Joint CAS JMT and Joint Fires JMT.

-Partner with JS J8 JIAMDO, JS J7 Joint Center for Operational Analysis, and other agencies to address persistent integrated air and missile defense interoperability issues.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Not applicable for this item.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>JDAT delivers Joint solutions for operational and tactical forces deployed to Combatant Commands (CCMDs) and Joint and Service Program managers. Deliverables may include: discrete improvements to training processes; doctrine; Tactics, Techniques, &amp; Procedures (TTPs); and/or technical system performance specifications and standards; validated Doctrine, Organization, Training, Material, Leadership, Personnel, Facilities, and Policy (DOTMLPF-P) recommendations; timely delivery of quality feedback to exercise participants and developers for systems under test; or improvements to Joint context of testing and training venues.  JDAT works with Joint Staff, CCMDs, and Services to approve the annual agenda of work and validate results.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:R3Exhibit>
                            <r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                                <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                    <r2:Name>Product Development</r2:Name>
                                    <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>Evaluation Other Costs</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>MIPR</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>JDAT</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Eglin AFB</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.725</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.530</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.530</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                    </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                    <r2:Name>Support</r2:Name>
                                    <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>Operational Test and Evaluation</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:ContractMethod>C</r2:ContractMethod>
                                            <r2:ContractType>CPFF</r2:ContractType>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>SAIC, Miratek, NDGI</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Eglin AFB</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:TotalPreviousYears>0.000</r2:TotalPreviousYears>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>6.639</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>6.776</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>6.776</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>Travel</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>TBD</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>Various DoD</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Various</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.200</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.200</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                    </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                            </r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                        </r2:R3Exhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                </r2:ProjectList>
            </r2:ProgramElement>
        </r2:R2Exhibit>
        <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElement>
                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0605126J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Joint Integrated Air &amp; Missle Defense Organization (JIAMDO)</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                <r2:R1LineItemNumber>144</r2:R1LineItemNumber>
                <r2:BudgetYear>2014</r2:BudgetYear>
                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                <r2:SubmissionDate>2013-04</r2:SubmissionDate>
                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>6</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>RDT&amp;E Management Support</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                    <r2:AllPriorYears>71.424</r2:AllPriorYears>
                    <r2:PriorYear>79.514</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>55.508</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>47.462</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>47.462</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>48.176</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>45.908</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>46.202</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>46.791</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO) is the organization within the Department of Defense (DoD) chartered to plan, coordinate, and oversee Joint Air and Missile Defense (AMD) requirements, joint operational concepts, and operational architectures.  As part of the CJCS staff, JIAMDO supports the Chairman in meeting his Title 10 responsibilities as they relate to air and missile defense issues.  JIAMDO serves as the operational community's proponent for characteristics, requirements, and capabilities in air and missile defense, and is the joint air and missile defense resource proponent within the DoD's resource allocation structures.  JIAMDO also leads AMD mission area and utility analyses, integrates air and missile defense within the Force Protection joint capability area, and conducts evaluations and demonstrations of joint air and missile defense architectures and concepts.

JIAMDO has established a close partnership with Combatant Commands (CCMDs) and maintains liaison offices at all major CCMD locations to facilitate coordination of integration issues and requirements.  In particular, JIAMDO maintains close coordination with US Strategic Command (USSTRATCOM) in support of ballistic missile defense of the U.S.  It provides the Chairman, JCS and the Joint Requirements Oversight Council (JROC) the ability to meet statutory responsibilities to review the cost, schedule and performance criteria of Missile Defense Agency (MDA) missile defense programs, and assesses the validity of those criteria in relation to national and military requirements.  At the request of USSTRATCOM, and at the direction of the CJCS, JIAMDO supports USSTRATCOM in the conduct of Military Utility Assessments and analysis of the Ballistic Missile Defense System (BMDS).  JIAMDO supports the USSTRATCOM mission by ensuring operational and technical requirements are integrated into the theater missile warning architecture.  JIAMDO represents the Joint Staff in work on the AMD Capabilities Based Assessment Joint Service Team.  JIAMDO also provides direct support to US Northern Command (USNORTHCOM) for homeland air surveillance issues.
</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>79.514</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>55.508</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>47.607</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>47.607</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>79.514</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>55.508</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>47.462</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>47.462</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>-0.145</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-0.145</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>Reduction</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>-0.145</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-0.145</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                    </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                    <r2:SummaryExplanation>JIAMDO-Homeland:  Programs will be near development completion and conducting Military Utility Assessment, which requires live assets and integration development.  

JIAMDO-Core:  The Joint Staff plans to reduce dependence upon contracted advisory and assistance service efforts, and increase leverage upon organic (military and federal civilian) labor.

FY2014 reduction is due to a both a decreasing resource environment and decreased reliance on contract support.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:ProjectList>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>P001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Core</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>24.751</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>9.030</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>22.508</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>21.767</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>21.767</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>22.481</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>19.967</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>20.627</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>20.916</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO) is the organization within the Department of Defense (DoD) chartered to plan, coordinate, and oversee Joint Air and Missile Defense (AMD) requirements, joint operational concepts, and operational architectures.  As part of the CJCS staff, JIAMDO supports the Chairman in meeting his Title 10 responsibilities as they relate to air and missile defense issues.  JIAMDO serves as the operational community's proponent for characteristics, requirements, and capabilities in air and missile defense, and is the joint air and missile defense resource proponent within the DoD's resource allocation structures.  JIAMDO also leads AMD mission area and utility analyses, integrates air and missile defense within the Force Protection joint capability area, and conducts evaluations and demonstrations of joint air and missile defense architectures and concepts.

JIAMDO has established a close partnership with Combatant Commands (CCMDs) and maintains liaison offices at all major CCMD locations to facilitate coordination of integration issues and requirements. In particular, JIAMDO maintains close coordination with US Strategic Command (USSTRATCOM) in support of ballistic missile defense of the U.S. It provides the Chairman, JCS and the Joint Requirements Oversight Council (JROC) the ability to meet statutory responsibilities to review the cost, schedule and performance criteria of Missile Defense Agency (MDA) missile defense programs, and assesses the validity of those criteria in relation to national and military requirements.  At the request of USSTRATCOM, and at the direction of the CJCS, JIAMDO supports USSTRATCOM in the conduct of Military Utility Assessments and analysis of the Ballistic Missile Defense System (BMDS).  JIAMDO supports the USSTRATCOM mission by ensuring operational and technical requirements are integrated into the theater missile warning architecture.  JIAMDO represents the Joint Staff in work on the AMD Capabilities Based Assessment Joint Service Team. JIAMDO also provides direct support to U.S. Northern Command (USNORTHCOM) for homeland air surveillance issues.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Core</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>Provides overall staff support for JIAMDO operations in the area of ballistic missile defense, air and cruise missile defense and homeland defense. This includes performing analyses, demonstrations, and programmatic assessments of technology, operations, requirements, and weapons systems. In coordination with Services and COCOMs, JIAMDO Core also leads the definition, assessment, development, and approval of Joint AMD Operational Concepts, Operational Architectures, and capability requirements to guide the Department's joint/interagency/combined fully integrated and net-centric capable air defense (including defense against cruise missiles, unmanned aerial vehicles, and ballistic missiles). JIAMDO Core also:
• Develops and integrates joint exercises, simulations, war-games, force resource allocations, and interoperability initiatives
• Manages relevant Congressional interaction and COCOM interface through a cadre of liaisons collocated with major headquarters
Directly supports and sponsors homeland air surveillance related demonstration and analysis activities
• Runs the AMD Working Group focusing COCOM, Joint Staff, and Service collaboration efforts in the generation of joint concepts and development of the integrated AMD architecture and roadmap
• Develops US positions for, and serves as the US representative to, the NATO Air Defense Committee

JIAMDO Core also enables strategic planning development, infrastructure, security, travel, administrative and other support activities. Funding pays for: Contractor Systems Engineering and Technical Assistance (SETA) support for Air &amp; Cruise Missile Defense (ACMD), Ballistic Missile Defense (BMD), Homeland Air Security (HAS) strategic planning, senior level briefings, and JIAMDO white papers; leased office space, including all upkeep services; all travel costs for government and contractor support personnel, including support for Combatant Commander liaison personnel travel; multiple levels of security including lease support for a Joint Worldwide Intelligence Communications System (JWICS) communications line and Special Compartmented Information (SCI) terminals (due to the classified nature and the diverse content of work in the JIAMDO portfolio); 24-hour physical security force and alarm monitoring and maintenance; daily on-site security personnel to meet DOD, National Industrial Security Program Operating Manual (NISPOM), and other security regulations; for all administrative and support functions; all associated Information Technology (IT) support, copier purchase and maintenance, as well as basic office supplies and furniture; all telephones, telephone lines, classified telephones, and classified/unclassified data connections.
</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>9.030</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Performed Ballistic Missile Defense directed studies and program support activities including: contracting, finance, systems engineering and technical assistance, administration, security, communications, leased space and supply.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>22.508</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Perform Ballistic Missile Defense directed studies and program support activities including:  contracting, finance, systems engineering and technical assistance, administration, security, communications, leased space and supply.  Program will reduced dependence on contracted advisory and assistance services, and intends to leverage organic (military and federal civilian) labor to achieve planned mission.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>21.767</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>21.767</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Perform Ballistic Missile Defense directed studies and program support activities including:  contracting, finance, systems engineering and technical assistance, administration, security, communications, leased space and supply.  Program will reduce dependence on contracted advisory and assistance services, and intends to leverage organic (military and federal civilian) labor to achieve planned mission.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Not required for Budget Activities 1, 2, 3 and 6.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>- Conduct two Protection Functional Capability Boards per month
- Conduct two Air and Missile Defense Working Groups per month
- Conduct quarterly Change Control Boards
- Support U.S. Representative to NATO Air Defense Council (NADC) to include 2 overseas NADC meetings per year
- Develop and maintain electronic library of current Joint and Service AMD Publications
- Develop and maintain operational architecture compliance with DoD architectural framework (DODAF) standards
- Ensure 100% of all government employee travel is in accordance with the JFTR/JTR
- Maintain all unclassified/classified LANs on a daily basis in accordance with TJS Office of the Chief Information Officer guidance/policy
- Ensure all computers, NIPRNET/SIPRNET, are refreshed according to OCIO policy/guidance</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>P002</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Homeland</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>14.347</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>25.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>6.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO) is the organization within the Department of Defense (DoD) chartered to plan, coordinate, and oversee Joint Air and Missile Defense (AMD) requirements, joint operational concepts, and operational architectures.  As part of the CJCS staff, JIAMDO supports the Chairman in meeting his Title 10 responsibilities as they relate to air and missile defense issues.  JIAMDO serves as the operational community's proponent for characteristics, requirements, and capabilities in air and missile defense, and is the joint air and missile defense resource proponent within the DOD's resource allocation structures.  JIAMDO also leads AMD mission area and utility analyses, integrates air and missile defense within the Force Protection joint capability area, and conducts evaluations and demonstrations of joint air and missile defense architectures and concepts.

JIAMDO has established a close partnership with Combatant Commands (CCMDs) and maintains liaison offices at all major CCMD locations to facilitate coordination of integration issues and requirements.  In particular, JIAMDO maintains close coordination with US Strategic Command (USSTRATCOM) in support of ballistic missile defense of the U.S.  It provides the Chairman, JCS and the Joint Requirements Oversight Council (JROC) the ability to meet statutory responsibilities to review the cost, schedule and performance criteria of Missile Defense Agency (MDA) missile defense programs, and assesses the validity of those criteria in relation to national and military requirements.  At the request of USSTRATCOM, and at the direction of the CJCS, JIAMDO supports USSTRATCOM in the conduct of Military Utility Assessments and analysis of the Ballistic Missile Defense System (BMDS).  JIAMDO supports the USSTRATCOM mission by ensuring operational and technical requirements are integrated into the theater missile warning architecture.  JIAMDO represents the Joint Staff in work on the AMD Capabilities Based Assessment Joint Service Team.  JIAMDO also provides direct support to US Northern Command (USNORTHCOM) for homeland air surveillance issues.
</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Homeland</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>Develop Homeland Surveillance technologies to enable Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense.
</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>25.000</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Perform technology development efforts.  Specific details of this project are classified.  </r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>6.000</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Perform technology development efforts.  Specific details of this project are classified.  </r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Not required for Budget Activities 1, 2, 3 and 6.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>Details of this project are classified.  

</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>P003</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Black Dart</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>3.833</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>5.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>4.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.454</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.454</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>3.458</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>3.492</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>3.492</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>3.485</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO), is the organization within the Department of Defense (DoD) chartered to plan, coordinate, and oversee Joint Air and Missile Defense (AMD) requirements, joint operational concepts, and operational architectures.  As part of the CJCS staff, JIAMDO supports the Chairman in meeting his Title 10 responsibilities as they relate to air and missile defense issues.  JIAMDO serves as the operational community's proponent for characteristics, requirements, and capabilities in air and missile defense, and is the joint air and missile defense resource proponent within the DOD's resource allocation structures.  JIAMDO also leads AMD mission area and utility analyses, integrates air and missile defense within the Force Protection joint capability area, and conducts evaluations and demonstrations of joint air and missile defense architectures and concepts.

JIAMDO has established a close partnership with Combatant Commands (CCMDs) and maintains liaison offices at all major CCMD locations to facilitate coordination of integration issues and requirements.  In particular, JIAMDO maintains close coordination with US Strategic Command (USSTRATCOM) in support of ballistic missile defense of the US.  It provides the Chairman, JCS and the Joint Requirements Oversight Council (JROC) the ability to meet statutory responsibilities to review the cost, schedule and performance criteria of Missile Defense Agency (MDA) missile defense programs, and assesses the validity of those criteria in relation to national and military requirements.  At the request of USSTRATCOM, and at the direction of the CJCS, JIAMDO supports USSTRATCOM in the conduct of Military Utility Assessments and analysis of the Ballistic Missile Defense System (BMDS).  JIAMDO supports the USSTRATCOM mission by ensuring operational and technical requirements are integrated into the theater missile warning architecture.  JIAMDO represents the Joint Staff in work on the AMD Capabilities Based Assessment Joint Service Team.  JIAMDO also provides direct support to US Northern Command (USNORTHCOM) for homeland air surveillance issues.

</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>JIAMDO Black Dart</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>Provides funding to support administration and execution of Black Dart demonstrations.  Black Dart is a joint, inter- agency demonstration which focuses on rapid development and implementation of Counter – Unmanned Aircraft Systems (C-UAS) technology from readily-available commercial and governmental products.</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>5.000</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Black Dart 2012 live-fly, live-fire C-UAS event 30 JUL 2012.  Event included interagency and classified events within the Black Dart C-UAS framework, with specific emphasis on non-kinetic capabilities as well an assessment on combat identification abilities of participating systems.  Intent was to assess C-UAS across IAMD kill chain in littoral/ maritime environment, provide a threat representative environment, refine C-UAS aspects of IAMD architecture, and establish operational / technical performance.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>4.000</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Continue development of kinetic and non-kinetic solutions to C-UAS threat set.  Continue coordination with the OSD JT&amp;E Couter-UAS activity within Black Dart 2013, refine existing inter-agency activities related to Black Dart participation, as well as develop Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) participation.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>3.454</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>3.454</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Increase fidelity of threat representations’ size &amp; performance.  Expand US DoD and Inter-agency system portfolio participation.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Not required for Budget Activities 1, 2, 3 and 6.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>- Complete events within schedule and budget.   Events provide useful data to improve C-UAS capability  
- Document gaps, develop &amp; substantiate hardware, software and employment concepts 
- Field C-UAS capability
</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>P004</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Joint Distributed Engineering Plant</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>4.785</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>8.927</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>3.250</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>2.983</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>2.983</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>2.978</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>3.097</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>2.718</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>2.755</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO) is the organization within the Department of Defense (DOD) chartered to plan, coordinate, and oversee Joint Air and Missile Defense (AMD) requirements, joint operational concepts, and operational architectures.  As part of the CJCS staff, JIAMDO supports the Chairman in meeting his Title 10 responsibilities as they relate to air and missile defense issues. JIAMDO serves as the operational community's proponent for characteristics, requirements, and capabilities in air and missile defense, and is the joint air and missile defense resource proponent within the DOD's resource allocation structures. JIAMDO also leads AMD mission area and utility analyses, integrates air and missile defense within the Force Protection joint capability area, and conducts evaluations and demonstrations of joint air and missile defense architectures and concepts.

JIAMDO has established a close partnership with Combatant Commands (COCOM) and maintains liaison offices at all major COCOM locations to facilitate coordination of integration issues and requirements. In particular, JIAMDO maintains close coordination with US Strategic Command (USSTRATCOM) in support of ballistic missile defense of the US. It provides the Chairman, JCS and the Joint Requirements Oversight Council (JROC) the ability to meet statutory responsibilities to review the cost, schedule and performance criteria of Missile Defense Agency (MDA) missile defense programs, and assesses the validity of those criteria in relation to national and military requirements. At the request of USSTRATCOM, and at the direction of the CJCS, JIAMDO supports USSTRATCOM in the conduct of Military Utility Assessments and analysis of the Ballistic Missile Defense System (BMDS). JIAMDO supports the USSTRATCOM mission by ensuring operational and technical requirements are integrated into the theater missile warning architecture. JIAMDO represents the Joint Staff in work on the AMD Capabilities Based Assessment Joint Service Team.  JIAMDO also provides direct support to US Northern Command (USNORTHCOM) for homeland air surveillance issues and for capabilities development and validation in support of the Unified Command Plan (UCP) assigned missions.
</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Joint Distributed Engineering Plant (JDEP)</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>Evaluates and improves interoperability by establishing and using a distributed, nationwide, hardware and software in-the-loop simulation capability that allows proposed combat capabilities and field combat weapon systems to operate in operationally representative, synthetic joint air and missile defense environments.</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>8.927</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Execute the Joint Tactical Air Picture (JTAP) Proof of Concept Demonstration to successfully test the following top level objectives.  
1. Demonstrate a capability approaching SIAP standards for track reporting , timeliness and Joint interoperable data sharing of both friendly &amp; threat air and missile defense (AMD) tracks using existing 6016 and 3011C mil standards over IP-enabled networks with Enhanced Data Rates (EDR) within a Bi-Directional Protocol Independent Multi-cast (Bi-Dir PIM) environment.
2.  Provide access to beyond line of sight (BLOS) surveillance data from 5th Gen aircraft in the contested and anti-access regions to support Strike (Offensive Counterair – Attacks Ops) and cueing of AMD weapons systems.
3.  Demonstrate measurable track reporting &amp; timeliness that approach SIAP standards and would support multiple Fire Control Quality requirements for cueing, early engagement, and/or engage-on-remote.
4.  Support development of a Joint Urgent Operational Need Statement (JUONS) to address legacy system(s) interface issues and support the Services current IAMD systems as they transition to the objective JIAMD capabilities.
5.  Provide a Simulation/Stimulation capability that could support future system testing, evaluation, TTP development, and training.
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>3.250</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Fund an appropriate joint distributed test event to assess the interoperability of joint, integrated air and missile defense weapons systems.  Provide users the means to create family of system (FoS) environments by linking existing capabilities using hardware, software, and operator-in-the-loop.  Link existing Service and Joint combat system engineering and test sites via distributed communications.   Reduce developmental cycle times by leveraging existing facilities.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>2.983</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>2.983</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Fund an appropriate joint distributed test event to assess the interoperability of joint, integrated air and missile defense weapons systems.  Provide users the means to create FoS environments by linking existing capabilities using hardware, software, and operator-in-the-loop.  Link existing Service and Joint combat system engineering and test sites via distributed communications.   Reduce developmental cycle times by leveraging existing facilities.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Not required for Budget Activities 1, 2, 3 and 6.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>- Each JDEP event develops measures of effectiveness (MOE) &amp; measures of performance (MOP) based on a eighteen month test planning and event process
- Complete events within schedule and budget 
- Events provide useful data to improve AMD interoperability, with implemented corrective changes</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>P005</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Nimble Fire</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>11.692</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>13.340</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>10.500</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>10.732</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>10.732</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>10.733</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>10.794</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>10.797</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>10.947</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO) is the organization within the Department of Defense (DoD) chartered to plan, coordinate, and oversee Joint Air and Missile Defense (AMD) requirements, joint operational concepts, and operational architectures.  As part of the CJCS staff, JIAMDO supports the Chairman in meeting his Title 10 responsibilities as they relate to air and missile defense issues.  JIAMDO serves as the operational community's proponent for characteristics, requirements, and capabilities in air and missile defense, and is the joint air and missile defense resource proponent within the DOD's resource allocation structures.  JIAMDO also leads AMD mission area and utility analyses, integrates air and missile defense within the Force Protection joint capability area, and conducts evaluations and demonstrations of joint air and missile defense architectures and concepts.

JIAMDO has established a close partnership with Combatant Commands (CCMDs) and maintains liaison offices at all major CCMD locations to facilitate coordination of integration issues and requirements.  In particular, JIAMDO maintains close coordination with US Strategic Command (USSTRATCOM) in support of ballistic missile defense of the US.  It provides the Chairman, JCS and the Joint Requirements Oversight Council (JROC) the ability to meet statutory responsibilities to review the cost, schedule and performance criteria of Missile Defense Agency (MDA) missile defense programs, and assesses the validity of those criteria in relation to national and military requirements.  At the request of USSTRATCOM, and at the direction of the CJCS, JIAMDO supports USSTRATCOM in the conduct of Military Utility Assessments and analysis of the Ballistic Missile Defense System (BMDS).  JIAMDO supports the USSTRATCOM mission by ensuring operational and technical requirements are integrated into the theater missile warning architecture.  JIAMDO represents the Joint Staff in work on the AMD Capabilities Based Assessment Joint Service Team.  JIAMDO also provides direct support to US Northern Command (USNORTHCOM) for homeland air surveillance issues.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>JIAMDO Nimble Fire </r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>The Department's only joint integrated air and missile defense operator-in-the-loop simulation that is comprised of current and future land, sea, and air weapon systems representing each of the Services AMD capabilities.  Operational personnel execute full mission scenarios in a realistic joint environment.  Distributed simulation in CONUS and overseas.  Enhances air and missile defense capability through the integration of robust representations of current and emerging weapons platform models that support operator-in-the-loop exercises.</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>13.340</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Integrate F-15E Strike Eagle simulators. Upgrade Army PATRIOT and Joint Land Attack Cruise Missile Defense Elevated Netted Sensor System (JLENS) simulators.  Enhanced Electronic Attack capabilities and composite tracking on JLENS.  Added Cooperative Engagement Capability on USMC TPS-59v3 and TPS-80 radars. Added four F-35 Joint Strike Fighter and 4 EA-18G Growler cockpits for joint forces.  Added IR-only kill chains. Support impacts of Electronic Attack in PACOM AOR from Asymmetric Missile Attack.  Executing three operator in the loop events.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>10.500</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Continue to upgrade Army simulators.  Enhance Electronic Attack capabilities, data links and composite tracking on all systems.  Integrate four F-35 Joint Strike Fighter cockpits for joint forces.  Support impacts of Electronic Attack, emerging CONOPS/TTP’s, limited offensive operations and Integrated Fire Control in PACOM and CENTCOM AORs.  Execute three operator in the loop events.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>10.732</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>10.732</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Continue to upgrade Army simulators.  Enhance Electronic Attack capabilities, data links and composite tracking on all systems.  Integrate four F-35 Joint Strike Fighter cockpits for joint forces.  Support impacts of Electronic Attack, emerging CONOPS/TTP’s, limited offensive operations and Integrated Fire Control in PACOM and CENTCOM AORs.  Execute three operator in the loop events.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Not required for Budget Activities 1, 2, 3 and 6.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>- Complete events within schedule and budget
- Specific details are classified
</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>P006</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Cruise Missle Combat Identification (CID)</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>12.016</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>18.217</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>9.250</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>8.526</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>8.526</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>8.526</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>8.558</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>8.568</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>8.688</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO) is the organization within the Department of Defense (DoD) chartered to plan, coordinate, and oversee Joint Air and Missile Defense (AMD) requirements, joint operational concepts, and operational architectures.  As part of the CJCS staff, JIAMDO supports the Chairman in meeting his Title 10 responsibilities as they relate to air and missile defense issues. JIAMDO serves as the operational community's proponent for characteristics, requirements, and capabilities in air and missile defense, and is the joint air and missile defense resource proponent within the DOD's resource allocation structures. JIAMDO also leads AMD mission area and utility analyses, integrates air and missile defense within the Force Protection joint capability area, and conducts evaluations and demonstrations of joint air and missile defense architectures and concepts.

JIAMDO has established a close partnership with Combatant Commands (CCMDs) and maintains liaison offices at all major CCMD locations to facilitate coordination of integration issues and requirements.  In particular, JIAMDO maintains close coordination with US Strategic Command (USSTRATCOM) in support of ballistic missile defense of the U.S.  It provides the Chairman, JCS and the Joint Requirements Oversight Council (JROC) the ability to meet statutory responsibilities to review the cost, schedule and performance criteria of Missile Defense Agency (MDA) missile defense programs, and assesses the validity of those criteria in relation to national and military requirements. At the request of USSTRATCOM, and at the direction of the CJCS, JIAMDO supports USSTRATCOM in the conduct of Military Utility Assessments and analysis of the Ballistic Missile Defense System (BMDS).  JIAMDO supports the USSTRATCOM mission by ensuring operational and technical requirements are integrated into the theater missile warning architecture.  JIAMDO represents the Joint Staff in work on the AMD Capabilities Based Assessment Joint Service Team and provides direct support to US Northern Command (USNORTHCOM) for homeland air surveillance issues.
</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Cruise Missile Combat Identification (CID)</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>Develops joint Counterair Combat Identification (CID) technology, and positions it for fielding on front-line weapon systems.  Monitors, assesses, and enhances joint AMD Combat ID programs.</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>18.217</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Details of this program are classified.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>9.250</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Details of this program are classified.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>8.526</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>8.526</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Details of this program are classified.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Not required for Budget Activities 1, 2, 3 and 6.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>Details of this program are classified.
</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                </r2:ProjectList>
            </r2:ProgramElement>
        </r2:R2Exhibit>
        <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElement>
                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0204571J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Joint Staff Analytical Support (JSAS)</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                <r2:R1LineItemNumber>168</r2:R1LineItemNumber>
                <r2:BudgetYear>2014</r2:BudgetYear>
                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                <r2:SubmissionDate>2013-04</r2:SubmissionDate>
                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>6</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>RDT&amp;E Management Support</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                    <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.018</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>2.097</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>2.097</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.924</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.942</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>1.029</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>1.038</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                    <r2:CostToComplete>0.0</r2:CostToComplete>
                    <r2:TotalCost>6.048</r2:TotalCost>
                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Joint Staff Analytical Support (JSAS) family of programs provides defense analytical support capabilities for the CJCS and Combatant Commands (CCMD).  JSAS encompasses the developmental tools and infrastructure required to conduct analyses and formulate the results to best assist the Chairman in fulfilling his statutory responsibilities.  Key deliverables provided by JSAS include wide-ranging force structure assessments, course of action development for the Joint Force environment, analyses and studies to aid in decision-making, and other analysis efforts to implement timely, low-cost initiatives.  </r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.018</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.018</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>2.097</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>2.097</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>2.097</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>2.097</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>Program change</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>2.097</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>2.097</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                    </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                    <r2:SummaryExplanation>Funding for additional Global Force Management requirements.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:ProjectList>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>P001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Concept Development Red Teaming </r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.018</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>0.0</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>0.018</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Staff Analytical Support (JSAS) family of programs provides defense analytical support capabilities for the CJCS and COCOMs. JSAS encompasses the developmental tools and infrastructure required to conduct analyses and formulate the results to best assist the Chairman in fulfilling his statutory responsibilities. Key deliverables provided by JSAS include wide-ranging force structure assessments, course of action development for the Joint Force environment, analyses and studies to aid in decision-making, and other analysis efforts to implement timely, low-cost initiatives.  </r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Concept Development Red Teaming </r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>Funds discovery experimentation activities supporting Joint Operations Concept (JOpsC) Development Process, implementation, and system integration.  Provides expert assessment of future conceptual approaches, alternate means to achieve future solutions and capabilities through Red Teaming.   Supports development and competition of ideas that provide the fundamental underpinnings for force development and design critical to assessing risk to DoD future capabilities.</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>0.018</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Funding provides program support for one concept.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>N/A</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>N/A</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>P002</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Global Force Management Data Initative (GFM DI) </r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>2.097</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>2.097</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.924</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.942</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>1.029</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>1.038</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>0</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>6.030</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>Automates the development of the Global Force Management Implementation Guidance Forces For Unified Commands Memorandum Assignment and Apportionment tables.  This will be accomplished using the Automated GFM Tool (AGT) and Collaborative Issue Resolution Tool (CIRT).  AGT and authoritative force structure data tagged with Organizational Unique Identifiers (OUID) will be transferred “machine-to-machine” from the Services to AGT. Additionally, AGT development will incorporate force readiness information.  The goal is to greatly improve the quality, timeliness, and accuracy of information available to perform Force Management (FM) throughout the Department.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Global Force Management Data Initative (GFM DI)</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>RDT&amp;E funds for the Global Force Management (GFM) program will enable the Assignment, the Allocation, and the Apportionment functions for forces to meet the requirements set forth in Title 10 U.S.C. and the Unified Command Plan.  The development of the Secretary of Defense’s “Forces for Unified Commands” Memorandum Assignment Tables has historically been a labor intensive staffing process conducted annually.  The Automated GFM Toolset is the first downstream consumer of force structure data resident in the seven organization (org) servers that are made available by the GFM DI effort.  CIRT has streamlined force management, increased common understanding of force assignment, and supported timely force management decisions.  The objective is to automate the generation of the Global Force Management Implementation Guidance (GFMIG) and Forces For Unified Commands (Forces For) Assignment, Apportionment and Allocation tables.  These efforts will flatten, streamline, and automate the current process while providing high fidelity data and transparency and enhance Combatant Commander risk assessment to operational plans.  

Failure to fund for this effort negatively impacts the ability of the Services, CCMDs, JS and OSD to efficiently manage force structure resources.  Without continued funding, the current FY13 Forces For staffing cycle will rely on manual, inefficient, less-timely spreadsheets to develop the Assignment and Apportionment Tables.  Additionally, this initially successful CIRT and AGT will fail and negatively impact the use of authoritative force structure data in GFM DI Next Steps.  
</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>2.097</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>2.097</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Development of the AGT for Assignment and Apportionment functions to meet FOC schedule.  Once FOC, AGT will need to be tested with actual data via individual service management systems (servers) to validate the forces Assignment. </r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>N/A</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>- The Services, CCMDs, JS and OSD will be able to efficiently manage force structure resources in half the time the current process takes
- Global force structure management will now become near-real time planning tool</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                </r2:ProjectList>
            </r2:ProgramElement>
        </r2:R2Exhibit>
        <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElement format="R2Long">
                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0303166J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Support to Information Operations Capability</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                <r2:R1LineItemNumber>172</r2:R1LineItemNumber>
                <r2:BudgetYear>2014</r2:BudgetYear>
                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                <r2:SubmissionDate>2013-04</r2:SubmissionDate>
                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>6</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>RDT&amp;E Management Support</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                    <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>8.238</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>8.394</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>8.394</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>8.552</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>8.713</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>8.876</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>9.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The National Military Strategy of the United States stresses the importance of integrating Information Operations (IO) capabilities for the success of Joint Operations and Decision Superiority.  The Defense-Wide IO Program Review revalidated a requirement for an integrated range supporting exercises, testing, and development of IO capabilities.  Further direction by the Office of the Secretary of Defense (OSD) identified the need for an integrated IO test and evaluation capability to assess IO technologies and tactics in a representative operational environment against realistic targets.  The 2006 National Security Strategy identifies "Strengthen Alliances to Defeat Global Terrorism and Work to Prevent Attacks Against Us and Our Friends", which involves significant Information Operations (IO) and Cyber operations as a goal.  Through the Defense Planning Guidance (DPG) and the Integrated Priority Lists, COCOMs repeatedly state the need to expand IO/Cyber training and education for the developing cadre of IO/Cyber professionals and provide an environment for analysis, testing, training, combat assessments, and measures of effectiveness for more reliable IO/Cyber capabilities.  </r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>8.238</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>8.394</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>8.394</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>8.238</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>8.394</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>8.394</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:ProjectList>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Information Operations Range</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>8.238</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>8.394</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>8.394</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>8.552</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>8.713</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>8.876</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>9.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Information Operations Range (JIOR) is a closed-loop network that forms a live-fire range utilizing encrypted tunneling over existing networks to conduct training, testing, and experimentation in support of Information Operations (IO) (Electronic Warfare (EW), Computer Network Attack (CNA)/Computer Network Defense (CND)) and Cyberspace mission areas in a threat representative environment.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>IO Range</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>The Joint Information Operations Range (JIOR) is a closed-loop network that forms a live-fire range utilizing encrypted tunneling over existing networks to conduct training, testing, and experimentation in support of Information Operations (IO) (Electronic Warfare (EW), Computer Network Attack (CNA)/Computer Network Defense (CND)) and Cyberspace mission areas in a threat representative environment.</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>8.238</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>• Expand national DoD and Inter-Agency awareness and support regarding IO and cyber related activities

• Improve the threat representation and operational relevance of the network

• Improve the integration of live, virtual, and constructive (LVC) simulations with other Joint training and testing communities and infrastructures

• Develop a long term JIOR infrastructure development, operation and sustainment management plan that supports the application of user resources allocated by JIOR stakeholders to support user activities, to include JIOR expansion and modernization and interoperability with National and DoD Cyber Ranges

• Improve capability to rapidly reset, regenerate, and adapt events 

• Improve capability to provide timely assessment for evaluation

• Establish cost-reimbursable funding construct</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>8.394</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>8.394</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>• Expand national DoD and Inter-Agency awareness and support regarding IO and cyber related activities

• Improve the threat representation and operational relevance of the network

• Improve the integration of live, virtual, and constructive (LVC) simulations with other Joint training and testing communities and infrastructures</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>The Joint IO Range, under JS Joint and Coalition Warfighting (JCW), manages the development and expansion of Joint IO Range capabilities to an increasing number of customers.  Integration into the Joint Exercise program has allowed users to increase the use and capability of the range.  Continued development of tools for the range will be required as adversarial capabilities improve.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>Performance metrics are measured through internal management controls and external assessments.  Performance metrics include, but are not limited to time, money, realism, and fidelity as defined below:

• Time – Will the effort enable the warfighter faster access to non-kinetic capabilities than current capabilities allow?
• Money – Will the effort enable the warfighter to reduce duplication of effort and to prepare and execute events at a more effective and efficient cost than current capabilities allow?
• Realism – Will the effort enable the warfighter to create an environment that is closer to what he/she will operate in during real world operations than current capabilities allow? 
• Fidelity – Will the effort ensure unity of efforts throughout the IO/CYBER Community?</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                </r2:ProjectList>
            </r2:ProgramElement>
        </r2:R2Exhibit>
        <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElement format="R2Long">
                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0607828J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Joint Integration &amp; Interoperability</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                <r2:R1LineItemNumber>190</r2:R1LineItemNumber>
                <r2:BudgetYear>2014</r2:BudgetYear>
                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                <r2:SubmissionDate>2013-04</r2:SubmissionDate>
                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>7</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Operational Systems Development</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                    <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>5.013</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>12.652</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>12.652</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>12.895</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>12.982</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>13.020</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>13.231</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Joint Integration &amp; Interoperability (JI&amp;I) Program Element underwrites the Department’s core joint Command and Control (C2) efforts for military needs development and validation, for development of associated Doctrine, Organization, Training, Materiel, Leadership and Education, Personnel, and Facilities (DOTMLPF), and for operational assessment of materiel solutions proposed and delivered by the Defense acquisition enterprise.  Funds from the JI&amp;I Program are used to address joint capabilities including, but not limited to operational through tactical level joint integration of the following capabilities: Common Operational and Tactical Pictures; Combat Identification; Situational Awareness; Adaptive Planning and Execution (APEX); Interoperability among Service/ Agency intelligence systems; Interoperable Joint Fires, Maneuver, and Intelligence; and Integrated Joint Battle Management Command and Control.

Activities funded by the JI&amp;I Program aim to:

- Identify, and/or develop mission capable solutions for COCOM integration and interoperability shortfalls with emphasis on non-materiel elements;
- Assess operational suitability and sufficiency of materiel solutions identified by the Defense acquisition enterprise in response to validated joint C2 needs;
- Provide Combatant Commanders with interoperable combat identification and situational awareness capabilities among United States Interagencies, and Allied and Coalition Forces in support of Overseas Contingency Operations;
- Develop joint requirements supporting C2-intensive joint missions such as Joint Close Air Support and Joint Fires;
- Develop joint integrated architectures that guide service capability mapping to achieve joint interoperability;
- Establish fundamental joint data standards and cross domain solutions to facilitate future system integration and interoperability; and,
- Undertake other activities to resolve emergent operational and tactical needs associated with joint C2.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>5.013</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>4.997</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>4.997</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>5.013</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>12.652</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>12.652</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.655</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.655</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>Program requirements</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.655</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.655</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                    </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                    <r2:SummaryExplanation>Additional resources allocated to support mission requirements that transitioned to the Joint Staff after U.S. Joint Forces Command disestablishment, and the re-establishment of the Joint Staff J6 Directorate / CIO.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:ProjectList>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>P818</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Joint Integration &amp; Interoperability</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>5.013</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>12.652</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>12.652</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>12.895</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>12.982</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>13.020</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>13.231</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Integration &amp; Interoperability (JI&amp;I) Program Element underwrites the Department’s core joint Command and Control (C2) efforts for military needs development and validation, for development of associated Doctrine, Organization, Training, Materiel, Leadership and Education, Personnel, and Facilities (DOTMLPF), and for operational assessment of materiel solutions proposed and delivered by the Defense acquisition enterprise.  Funds from the JI&amp;I Program are used to address joint capabilities including, but not limited to operational through tactical level joint integration of the following capabilities: Common Operational and Tactical Pictures; Combat Identification; Situational Awareness; Adaptive Planning and Execution (APEX); Interoperability among Service/ Agency intelligence systems; Interoperable Joint Fires, Maneuver, and Intelligence; and Integrated Joint Battle Management Command and Control.

Activities funded by the JI&amp;I Program aim to:

- Identify, and/or develop mission capable solutions for COCOM integration and interoperability shortfalls with emphasis on non-materiel elements;
- Assess operational suitability and sufficiency of materiel solutions identified by the Defense acquisition enterprise in response to validated joint C2 needs;
- Provide Combatant Commanders with interoperable combat identification and situational awareness capabilities among United States Interagencies, and Allied and Coalition Forces in support of Overseas Contingency Operations;
- Develop joint requirements supporting C2-intensive joint missions such as Joint Close Air Support and Joint Fires;
- Develop joint integrated architectures that guide service capability mapping to achieve joint interoperability;
- Establish fundamental joint data standards and cross domain solutions to facilitate future system integration and interoperability; and,
- Undertake other activities to resolve emergent operational and tactical needs associated with joint C2.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Joint Integration &amp; Interoperability</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>Primary objective is the resolution of C2 warfighter requirements and interoperability shortfalls; development, oversight, and execution of the DoD C2 Strategic and Implementation Plan objectives for:
1) Improved, integrated, interoperable, and networked joint force;
2) Reduction in duplicative C2 systems/programs across the DoD portfolio; and
3) Improved decisions and recommendations regarding capability trade-off investment strategies and development efforts.</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>5.013</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Lead the requirements definition process and implementation framework necessary to evolve the DoD Future Mission Network (FMN) / Mission Partner Environment (MPE) capability; follow-on to the Afghanistan Mission Network (AMN).  Provide oversight and management of integration activities in accordance with JROC-approved FMN / MPE implementation plan to address steady-state and contingency coalition information sharing needs and Combatant Command shortfalls.  Provide oversight and management of FY13 joint combat development projects and integration activities: joint C2 requirements definition and prioritization for the JROC, kinetic and non-kinetic (cyber) joint fires capabilities, mission thread architectures and analysis, enterprise data standards and services and operational assessments to optimize C2 portfolio capabilities. Provide a persistent joint environment for test and assessment to address COCOM issues in operational assessments/venues.

Perform C2 capability prioritization and sequencing via the USD(AT&amp;L)-sponsored Joint C2 Sustainment and Modernization Plan process, with follow-on C2 capability production, integration, fielding and sustainment for FY13-15.  Perform the JROC-directed Operational Impact and Risk Assessment of Joint C2 capabilities based on COCOM and Service inputs to inform stakeholders of the current state of joint C2 with respect to the JROC’s “Do No Harm” mandate.  Sustain and utilize the Net-Enabled Requirements Identification Database (NRID) and the Decision Support Tool (DST) to provide accessibility and visibility into C2 capability needs (gaps, shortfall), defined requirements (old, new, emerging), and potential solutions for C2 stakeholders and decision-makers to consider. Develop JCIDS and requirements documents to sustain the Joint C2 family of programs and lead the way for future joint C2 capability development. Develop requirements for Future Mission Network (FMN) / Mission Partner Environment (MPE) capabilities and consider C2 Doctrine, Organization, Training, Leadership and Education, Personnel, Facilities, and Policy (DOT_LPF-P) solution tradeoffs and recommendations. Develop and/or collaborate on Capability Definition Packages (CDPs) for Global Force Management Synchronization, Concept Development, and Joint Execution Mission Management.  Develop Capability Packages (CPs) for Adaptive Planning and Execution Force Projection, Future Mission Network (FMN) / Mission Partner Environment (MPE), and Unclassified Information Sharing Services.

Lead the configuration management of C2 Core Version 2.0 and facilitate C2 Core implementation through the Tactical Edge Data Solutions Joint Capability Technology Demonstration and piloting activities with the National Geospatial Agency and the Open Geospatial Consortium.  Support DoD CIO development of the DoD Data Framework and DoD adoption of the National Information Exchange Model (NIEM). Lead the NATO C3 Board Information Integration Services Capability Team to facilitate data sharing capabilities with NATO nations. Execute FY 2013 Authoritative Data Source (ADS) Annual Review Board in conjunction with the Joint C2 Sustainment and Modernization Plan process to synchronize data exposure with capability development.  Expand the C2 ADS management approach in coordination with all functional capability boards (FCBs.  Verify C2 ADS information in the DoD Enterprise ADS Registry and report ADS exposure and utilization metrics to ensure ADS exposures are meeting warfighter requirements.  Map ADS to Joint Mission Threads directly supporting warfighter requirements and analysis. Provide data &amp; service strategy reviews and recommendations for ISPs/IAPs, capabilities development documents, and guidance and policy documents to ensure programs are complying with warfighter requirements and policy.  Lead the C2 Data and Services Steering Committee to provide a formal process to establish C2 data sharing priorities and standards for C2 capabilities.  Maintain oversight of DOD's tactical information exchange standards.  Oversee refinement and implementation of the Interoperability Enhancement Process (IEP) to ensure data interoperability in the field.

Lead interoperability efforts across DOD and partner nations at operational and tactical level for mission partner operations, fire support, Combat Identification (CID), and Friendly Force Tracking (FFT) capabilities. Function as Secretariat for the Joint Requirements Oversight Council(JROC)-chartered, FOGO-level Joint Fire Support (JFS) and CID/FFT Executive Steering Committees (ESCs)— which focuses Service and NATO/coalition partners on joint and combined solutions to policy, interoperability, doctrine, and tactics, techniques, and procedural (TTP) issues and initiatives. Execute the Director, Joint Staff-approved Bold Quest 2013 assessment demonstration, including a Joint Operational Test for Mark XII Mode 5 Interoperability to support initial operational capability for US forces in 2014; and a long range air defense event to test the air-to-ground integration of Mode 5—meeting long-standing requests by the Navy and USAF. Expand the JROC-directed JFS Joint Mission Thread beyond the “execution phase” to the entire fires support process—increasing systems interoperability and fires execution with materiel and non-materiel initiatives (doctrine, training, TTP).  Execute the OPSDEPS/Director JS J-6 approved Joint Terminal Attack Controller (JTAC), Forward Air Controller-Airborne (FAC-A), and Joint Fires Observer (JFO) Memorandums of Agreement—which standardize schoolhouse curriculums; training materials and equipment; simulation and simulators; and instructor requirements.  Conduct JFS ESC standardization team accreditation visits to US and partner nation schoolhouses to ensure MOA signatories are accomplishing schoolhouse training in compliance with the Memorandums—reporting results to the JFS ESC and FOGO-level Commander that include deviations from the MOAs; recommendations for improvement, and best practices. Pursue Digitally Aided Close Air Support (DACAS) implementation testing and documentation to provide the ability to digitally transmit instructions (9-line and digital target marking) to expedite attack execution and reduce the potential for friendly-fire by lessening the possibility for human translation error and increasing the opportunity for target confirmation between the JTAC and the attacking aircraft crew. Continue to support Combat Identification Server operational execution in CENTCOM theater of operations while transitioning to gaining Service.

Update the C2OTM Reference Architecture and add additional analysis and architectures. Continue to analyze JCIDS Capability Documents, ISPs and TISPs. Review and analyze NR KPP architectures, KPPs, KSAs and capabilities for interoperability and integration. Provide NR KPP Waiver Recommendations based on GIG connection and operational / systems requirements analysis.  Maintain the Future Mission Network (FMN) / Mission Partner Environment (MPE) Integrated Architecture. Support C4/CYBER FCB on JROC Interest issues with analysis and architectures. Provide additional functions for inclusion in the Joint Common System Function List (JCSFL). Provide analysis and architecture support to the Joint Aerial Layer Network initiative.  Develop the Joint Information Environment (JIE) ICD Architectures.  Analyze and provide recommendations for the JIE Reference and Solutions Architectures.  Support the Federation effort with capabilities requirements to proposed capabilities and capability gaps analysis using authoritative sources of information and data.  Develop Solutions architectures and perform analysis to determine capability development priorities, identify capability redundancies/gaps, and identify critical Joint C2 interoperability opportunities and requirements.

Begin development of six new Tier 1 JMTs based on JROC and FCB guidance and partnership opportunities. Support cross-DoD efforts to enhance the capability to collaborate on, leverage and improve developed and developing JMTs.  Support the management of the DACAS Change Control Engineering Change Proposal (ECP) implementation with Program Managers and Mission Partners.  Manage the Joint Fires Support JMT in support of the JROC mandated analyses, implementing the ECPs identified in the analysis conducted in FY-2012/2013.  Provide JMT data via web-enabled portal capability providing operational context and mission-based data reuse for the testing, training, programming, program development, experimentation, and modeling and simulation communities of interest across DoD.

Provide architecture and capability analysis support for joint Command &amp; Control (C2) systems and Service systems joint integration in support of the Combat Capability Development. Provide architecture analysis and products in support of the development of C2 related ICDs (Initial Capabilities Documents), CDDs (Capability Development Documents), CPDs (Capability Production Documents), ISPs (Information Support Plans) and TISPs (Tailored Information Support Packages) for compliance with the JCIDS process.

Provide the capability to support use of architecture data in Joint Staff and OSD capability analysis processes.  Provide and expand the development of web services and standardized portal interface for exposure and federation of Joint Mission Threads, C/S/A Architectures, and other authoritative sources of data. Provide an Integrated Dictionary of authoritative WMA architecture elements for reuse by programs and other capability developers.  Incorporate and align joint architecture development environment with data model and methodology standards in conjunction with OSD, Joint Staff, and Service and Combatant Command communities. The result of the enhanced Federation capabilities will be the increased efficiency of architecture development through discovery access and reuse and the increased effectiveness through the greater availability of authoritative products. </r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>12.652</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>12.652</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Develop an integrated and prioritized C2 capabilities action plan to address C2 capability shortfalls for JS J6 endorsement and signature. Lead implementation efforts necessary to continue to evolve the DoD FMN / MPE capability IAW with JROCMs 081-12 and 026-13.  Develop a Joint C4I Partnership to establish and manage a predictable and operationally realistic environment for capability development, assessment, test, and certification of COCOM and JTF C4I systems. Assess and test systems providing capabilities to joint missions in the expected operational environment and verify interoperability earlier in the development cycle to enhance the effectiveness and efficiency of joint and coalition force C4I assessment, test and certification.  Provide real time support for urgent COCOM and coalition requirements, JCS exercises, contingencies and current ops. Additionally, continue to provide oversight and management of FY14 joint combat development projects and integration activities. Provide recommendations to inform JROC and DOD executive level C4/Cyber capability trade-off, investment and divestiture decisions impacting FY16.  

Continue the prioritization and sequencing of C2 capabilities via the USD(AT&amp;L)-sponsored Joint C2 Sustainment and Modernization Plan process, with follow-on C2 capability production, integration, fielding and sustainment for FY14-16.  Continue to perform the Operational Impact and Risk Assessment of Joint C2 capabilities based on COCOM and Service inputs.  Direct engagement with Component materiel developers to shape solutions and ensure requirements traceability through product delivery.  Continue the sustainment and utilization of the NRID and DST to provide accessibility and visibility into C2 capability needs, defined requirements, and potential C2 solutions. Provide funding strategies to decision-making forums that support sustainment of current capabilities while continuing to migrate C2 to an agile, services-oriented environment. Continue to develop JCIDS and requirements documents to sustain the Joint C2 family of programs and lead the way for future joint C2 capability development. Continue to develop requirements for Future Mission Network (FMN) / Mission Partner Environment (MPE) capabilities and consider C2 DOT_LPF-P solution tradeoffs and recommendations.  Develop and/or collaborate on CDPs for Unit Command and Control and access to Intelligence, Surveillance and Reconnaissance Collection Management information. Develop CPs for Global Force Management Synchronization, and Course of Action Development, and collaborate on the Command and Control Air Operation Services CP.  

Transition the C2 Core data exchange standard to the National Information Exchange Model (NIEM) and stand up the NIEM Military Operations Domain. Provide training and support to NIEM implementation activities within the Warfighter Mission Area (WMA) to promote DoD and interagency interoperability.  Support DoD CIO efforts to refine and implement the DoD Data Framework and lead the implementation of the DoD Data Framework within the WMA. Continue to lead the NATO C3 Board Information Integration Services Capability Team and define a NATO Core Data Framework to facilitate data sharing capabilities with NATO nations.  Execute FY 2014 Authoritative Data Source (ADS) Annual Review Board in conjunction with the Joint C2 Sustainment and Modernization Plan process to synchronize data exposure with capability development.  Continue to verify C2 ADS information in the DoD Enterprise ADS Registry and report ADS exposure and utilization metrics.  Lead, facilitate, and/or support NIEM and other relevant WMA Data Standard implementation and technical demonstrations/pilots to enhance US and coalition data interoperability.  Continue providing data &amp; service strategy reviews and recommendations for ISPs/IAPs, capabilities development documents, and guidance and policy documents to ensure programs are complying with warfighter requirements and policy. Stand up the WMA Data and Services Steering Committee to provide a formal process to establish WMA data sharing priorities and standards for WMA capabilities.  Maintain oversight of DOD's tactical information exchange standards.


Continue to lead interoperability efforts across DOD and partner nations at operational and tactical level for mission partner operations, fire support, Combat Identification (CID), and Friendly Force Tracking (FFT) capabilities. Continue to function as Secretariat for the JROC-chartered, FOGO-level Joint Fire Support (JFS) and CID/FFT Executive Steering Committees (ESCs). Execute the JFS/Joint Close Air Support (JCAS) and CID-FFT Action Plans to fulfill JFS and CID/FFT responsibilities. Execute the Joint Staff-approved Bold Quest 2014 assessment demonstration.  Continue to expand the JROC-directed JFS Joint Mission Thread beyond the “execution phase” to the entire fires support process.  Continue to execute OPSDEPS/Director JS J-6 approved Joint Terminal Attack Controller (JTAC), Forward Air Controller-Airborne (FAC-A), and Joint Fires Observer (JFO) Memorandums of Agreement.  Continue to conduct JFS ESC standardization team accreditation visits to US and partner nation schoolhouses to ensure MOA signatories are accomplishing schoolhouse training in compliance with the Memorandums.  Continue DACAS implementation testing and documentation to provide the ability to digitally transmit instructions to expedite attack execution and reduce the potential for friendly-fire.

Continue to analyze NR KPP architectures and capabilities for interoperability and integration, and provide NR KPP Waiver Recommendations based on operational / systems requirements analysis.  Continue to maintain the Future Mission Network (FMN) / Mission Partner Environment (MPE) Integrated Architectures and Joint Information Environment Architectures.  Develop solutions architectures for the Warfighting Enterprise Architectures. Support C4/CYBER FCB on JROC Interest issues with analysis and architectures. Provide additional functions for the Joint Common System Function List. Review emerging DoD policy addressing architectures and standards. Continue to support FCB architecture-based analysis requirements through expanding the architecture federation effort, to include the capability to provide discovery and reuse of capabilities requirements to proposed capabilities traceability and capability gaps analysis reports using authoritative sources of information and architecture data.

Continue development of new Tier 1 JMTs based on JROC and FCB guidance and partnership opportunities. Identify future Joint Fires Support (JFS) Block ECPs. Provide JMT data via web-enabled portal capability providing operational context data reuse for the testing, training, programming, and program development.

Provide support to the Joint Staff J6 Combat Capability Development Division (CCDD) by conducting architecture analysis and developing DoDAF products that support the Joint C2 requirements development process and the DoD Sustainment &amp; Modernization Planning process (SMPP) to enable gap analysis and solution identification.  Provide Joint C2 architecture data via federated capability providing operational context and C2 mission-based data reuse for the testing, training, programming, program development, experimentation, and modeling and simulation communities of interest.

Continue to expand the amount and quality of Warfighting Mission Area (WMA) architecture data available to support DoD CIO architecture requirements and Joint Staff capability analysis, test and evaluation, and modeling and simulation processes.  Improve capability for discovery, accessibility, and use/re-use of WMA and Joint Information Environment architectures, architecture-based analysis reports and associated data.  Continue to expand the federated architecture environment to include Combatant Command, Service, and Agency (C/S/A) partner repositories of authoritative architecture information and data.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Not applicable for this item. </r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>• Develop coordinated joint C4 operational assessments, tests and evaluations to identify, prioritize and document interoperability deficiencies that produce Component plans and actions to reduce or eliminate identified deficiencies
• Provide mission capable solutions for joint interoperability and integration capability shortfalls to influence and resource joint C2 solutions in the POM
• Provide situational awareness and cooperative / non-cooperative identification capabilities that enable U.S., NATO / coalition warfighters to identify friendly, enemy and neutral forces for “shoot/don’t shoot” decisions
• Synchronize Service testing, acquisition and fielding of Mode 5 IFF capability, with an Initial Operating Capability (IOC) in 2014 and Full Operational Capability (FOC) in 2020
• Complete Definition Package for Block 2 of Digitally Aided Close Air Support (DACAS) coordinated implementation in conjunction with participating Service programs of record
• Conduct Accreditation Biennial Visits for 6 Joint Terminal Attack Controller (JTAC) and 2 Joint Fires Observer (JFO) Schoolhouses
• Monitor compliance for Mode 5 IOC in FY14 and FOC in FY20 
• Develop annual JROC approved plan to identify prioritized and synchronized capabilities sufficient for near-term development and fielding to warfighters  (12-18 month delivery)
• Develop, as required, JROC requirements documentation (ICDs, CDDs, CPDs, CDPs, CONOPs, MOEs/MOPs) sufficient for  agile/flexible use by the acquisition community
• Continue development of reusable architecture products to provide capability developers an upfront, operational/systems view at the enterprise level to support of capability acquisition, requirements generation, development, and testing.
• Establish common WMA data and service standards and facilitate access to authoritative data assets in order to provide the warfighter timely access to critical information for Joint, Interagency, and Multinational partners. </r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:R3Exhibit>
                            <r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                                <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                    <r2:Name>Management Services</r2:Name>
                                    <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>FFRDC Engineering &amp; Techical Services</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>FFRDC</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>MITRE</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Hampton Roads, VA</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.190</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2013-02</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.190</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.190</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2013-09</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>Contract Management Support Services</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:ContractMethod>C</r2:ContractMethod>
                                            <r2:ContractType>CPFF</r2:ContractType>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>Various DoD</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Various</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>2.214</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2013-09</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>4.782</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>4.782</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2014-09</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>Contract Engineering and Technical Services</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:ContractMethod>C</r2:ContractMethod>
                                            <r2:ContractType>CPFF</r2:ContractType>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>MAN-TECH</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Hampton Roads, VA</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.220</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2013-02</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>3.100</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>3.100</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2013-10</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>FFRDC Engineering &amp; Technical Services</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>FFRDC</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>Old Dominion University</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Norfolk, VA</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.180</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2012-12</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.180</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.180</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2013-12</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>Contract Engineering and Technical Services</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:ContractMethod>C</r2:ContractMethod>
                                            <r2:ContractType>CPFF</r2:ContractType>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>GTRI</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Various</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.720</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2012-12</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>1.500</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>1.500</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2013-12</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>Contract Engineering and Technical Services</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>MIPR</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>Bold Quest</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Various</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.889</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>2.300</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>2.300</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>Contract Management Support Services</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>MIPR</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>SADIE</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Various</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.400</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2013-03</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.400</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.400</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2014-03</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>Travel</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>TBD</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>DoD</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Various</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.200</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.200</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.200</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                    </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                            </r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                        </r2:R3Exhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                </r2:ProjectList>
            </r2:ProgramElement>
        </r2:R2Exhibit>
        <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElement format="R2Long">
                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0208043J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Planning and Decision Aid System (PDAS)</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                <r2:R1LineItemNumber>191</r2:R1LineItemNumber>
                <r2:BudgetYear>2014</r2:BudgetYear>
                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                <r2:SubmissionDate>2013-04</r2:SubmissionDate>
                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>7</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Operational Systems Development</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                    <r2:AllPriorYears>2.288</r2:AllPriorYears>
                    <r2:PriorYear>2.402</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>3.922</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.061</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.061</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>4.172</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>4.043</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>3.732</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>3.788</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>Provide engineering and testing support to the Planning and Decision Aid System, a classified Joint Staff automated information system supporting the combatant commanders, services, and Department of Defense Agencies.  </r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>2.402</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>3.922</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.648</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.648</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>2.402</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>3.922</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.061</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.061</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>-0.587</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-0.587</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>Program adjustment</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>-0.587</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-0.587</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                    </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:ProjectList>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>P001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Planning and Decision Aid System OPS</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>2.288</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>2.402</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>3.922</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.061</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.061</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>4.172</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>4.043</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>3.732</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>3.788</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>Provide engineering and testing support to the Planning and Decision Aid System, a classified Joint Staff automated information system supporting the combatant commanders, services, and Department of Defense Agencies.  </r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Planning and Decision Aid System (PDAS)</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>Critical engineering support monitors the ever-changing information technology environment and develops strategies and solutions to integrate modern commercial off the shelf upgrades to the existing system.  Contractor-independent testing ensures government developmental testing is performed on all software upgrades regardless of size.</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>2.402</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Details of the program are classified.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>3.922</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Details of the program are classified.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>3.061</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>3.061</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Details of the program are classified.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Details of this program are classified.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>- Independent testing of at least 3-client and 2-server based software patches
- Maintenance of the Planning and Decision Aid System technology road-map
- Trade studies for specific commercial off the shelf solutions
</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:R3Exhibit>
                            <r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                                <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                    <r2:Name>Management Services</r2:Name>
                                    <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>TBD</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:ContractMethod>C</r2:ContractMethod>
                                            <r2:ContractType>TBD</r2:ContractType>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>TBD</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>TBD</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:PriorYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>2.402</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:PriorYear>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>3.922</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2012-09</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>3.061</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>3.061</r2:Amount>
                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2013-09</r2:AwardDate>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                    </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                            </r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                        </r2:R3Exhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                </r2:ProjectList>
            </r2:ProgramElement>
        </r2:R2Exhibit>
        <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElement format="R2Long">
                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0902298J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Management Headquarters</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                <r2:R1LineItemNumber>249</r2:R1LineItemNumber>
                <r2:BudgetYear>2014</r2:BudgetYear>
                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                <r2:SubmissionDate>2013-04</r2:SubmissionDate>
                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>7</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Operational Systems Development</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                    <r2:AllPriorYears>2.807</r2:AllPriorYears>
                    <r2:PriorYear>2.730</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>4.100</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.533</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.533</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>5.530</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>5.146</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>5.086</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>5.479</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>Management Headquarters provides the financial resources necessary to support future TJS operations. Across the Joint Staff, Management Headquarters supports various efforts including network infrastructure, civilian pay accounts, supplies, travel, training, portfolio management, business process reviews and transformation initiatives.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>2.730</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>4.100</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>4.019</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>4.019</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>2.730</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>4.100</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.533</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.533</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>-0.486</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-0.486</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>Program adjustment</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>-0.486</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-0.486</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                    </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:ProjectList>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>P001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Joint Staff Information Network (JSIN)</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>2.807</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>2.730</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>4.100</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.533</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.533</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>5.530</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>5.146</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>5.086</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>5.479</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>Management Headquarters provides the day-to-day financial resources necessary to support TJS operations. Across the Joint Staff, Management Headquarters supports various efforts including network infrastructure, civilian pay accounts, supplies, travel, training, portfolio management, business process reviews, and transformation initiatives.  </r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Joint Staff Information Network (JSIN)</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Description>Provides RDT&amp;E funds for the Joint Staff Information Network (JSIN). JSIN is the network infrastructure (for both classified and unclassified information) enabling collaboration and information-sharing among the Joint Staff, Combatant Commands (CCMD) and the Services.  The JSIN also provides crucial business-related, decision-making information and workflow support affecting military operations in support of the JCS.  JSIN improves actions processing for faster coordination of critical issues with CCMDs, Services, and agencies, as well as within the Joint Staff.</r2:Description>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>2.730</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Established independent government cost analysis; enhanced cost controls for $21M IT projects – cutting overruns by 15%. Consolidated software licensing process between Pentagon and Hampton Roads, reducing additional contract overhead and gaining renewal cost efficiencies with centralized management and consolidated procurement. Established a framework for a JS-wide robust Portfolio Management process, integrated with organizational processes, to enhance senior leaders’ JS-wide IT investment oversight, decision-making and ability to improve strategic alignment with JS mission &amp; vision, enterprise initiatives and DoD Business Efficiencies guidance. Led DoD as five person member of the DISA mobility pilot – Testing five iPhones; first testers to request an organizational account. Led Windows 7 migration on an accelerated schedule; reduced security risks by 40%. Prioritized and led IT analyses for multiple JS initiatives such as: Thin Client (S/U), DISA Enterprise Content Management Services (DECMS/U), Desktop Server and Application virtualization, Mobile Computing, and the JS-ITA Service Desk Consolidation effort, which guaranteed C4ISR support to the joint force while providing resource efficiencies and improved network security posture.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>4.100</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Provide planning and support to Joint Staff Information Technology initiatives, including planning and letter estimates for DECC migration for JS applications, Thin Client (S) and the VDI proof of concept, Defense Enterprise Email (DEE) (S), Defense Enterprise Portal Services (DEPS) (U), Desktop, Server and Application Virtualization (S), Cross Domain Services IOC, DISA Enterprise Content Management (DECMS) (U), Mobile Computing solutions, Unified Communications Capabilities, Enterprise Services Implementation and Joint Information Environment (JIE) planning, JS Service Desk optimization plan, and Identity and Access Management capabilities  to achieve efficiencies, improve mission effectiveness, and strengthen our security posture. Research, analyze, architect, plan the transition to, and support the sequencing and dependencies for this portfolio of Core IT investments as well as Mission systems within the Joint Staff.</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>3.533</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>3.533</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>Provide planning and support to Joint Staff Information Technology initiatives, including continued Defense Enterprise Computing Center (DECC) migration for JS applications, Thin Client (U) and Mobile Computing, Defense Enterprise Portal Services (DEPS) (S), continue Application Virtualization (S) and (U), Cross Domain Services FOC, DISA Enterprise Content Management (DECMS) (U) optimization and integration, Mobile Computing solutions, Unified Communications Capabilities transition to VOIP/VoSIP, Enterprise Services Implementation including Enterprise Task Management (U/S), JS Service Desk optimization implementation, Identity and Access Management capabilities and Cloud Computing readiness to achieve efficiencies, improve mission effectiveness, and strengthen our security posture. </r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>- Reduce technical support hours per desktop minimum of 10% through deployment of thin client and virtualized management of the IT baseline 
- Cost avoided for technology refresh of NIPR and SIPR desktops via the proper planning, testing and piloting of a Joint Staff Thin Client solution
- Reduce the cost of building, operating and maintaining Joint staff specific solutions through implementation of enterprise capabilities and adoption of new cost models for execution (DEE, DEPS, Enterprise Task management, and Unified Communications)
- Reduce redundancies in Core and Mission IT Capabilities through implementation of a comprehensive Portfolio management policy and avoid cost through the institutionalization of investment management governance model</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:R3Exhibit>
                            <r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                                <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                    <r2:Name>Product Development</r2:Name>
                                    <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>Contract Support</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>MIPR</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>SPAWAR</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Washington, DC</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:PriorYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>2.730</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:PriorYear>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>3.131</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>2.555</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>2.555</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                    </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                    <r2:Name>Support</r2:Name>
                                    <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>Contract Support</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>MIPR</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>SPAWAR</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Washington, DC</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.969</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.978</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>0.978</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                    </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                            </r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                        </r2:R3Exhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                </r2:ProjectList>
            </r2:ProgramElement>
        </r2:R2Exhibit>
    </r2:R2ExhibitList>
</jb:JustificationBook>