<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jb:JustificationBook xmlns:jb="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/jb" targetSchemaVersion="1.0" classification="UNCLASSIFIED">
    <jb:Title>Justification Book</jb:Title>
    <jb:BudgetYear>2017</jb:BudgetYear>
    <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
    <jb:SubmissionDate>2016-02</jb:SubmissionDate>
    <jb:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Technical Information Center</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
    <jb:AppropriationCode>0400</jb:AppropriationCode>
    <jb:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</jb:AppropriationName>
    <jb:CoverPage/>
    <jb:ExternalDocuments>
        <jb:UserR1Doc>
            <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit R-1</jb:Title>
            <jb:FileName>R-1C1 as of 27 January 2016 PB 2017 Revised_rotated_resized.pdf</jb:FileName>
        </jb:UserR1Doc>
    </jb:ExternalDocuments>
    <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        <jb:ForceEvenPages>true</jb:ForceEvenPages>
        <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>
        <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>
        <jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>true</jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>
    </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
    <r2:ProgramElementList xmlns:r2="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/r2" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
        <r2:ProgramElement monetaryUnit="Millions" classification="UNCLASSIFIED">
            <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0605801KA</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
            <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Defense Technical Information Center</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
            <r2:R1LineNumber>160</r2:R1LineNumber>
            <r2:BudgetYear>2017</r2:BudgetYear>
            <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
            <r2:SubmissionDate>2016-02</r2:SubmissionDate>
            <r2:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Technical Information Center</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
            <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
            <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
            <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>6</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
            <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>RDT&amp;E Management Support</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
            <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:AllPriorYears>56.024</r2:AllPriorYears>
                <r2:PriorYear>50.789</r2:PriorYear>
                <r2:CurrentYear>56.775</r2:CurrentYear>
                <r2:BudgetYearOne>43.834</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>43.834</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                <r2:BudgetYearTwo>45.504</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                <r2:BudgetYearThree>46.517</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                <r2:BudgetYearFour>47.190</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                <r2:BudgetYearFive>48.034</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
            </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
            <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Defense Technical Information Center’s (DTIC) unique mission is to provide rapid, accurate, and reliable access to essential research, development, test, and evaluation (RDT&amp;E) information, supporting all DoD users. DTIC, a DoD Field Activity, is the DoD’s singular executive agent and designated source for DoD-funded scientific, technical, engineering, and industry-related information. DTIC is an information delivery house that delivers technical information nearly instantaneously to all DoD users. DTIC also operates DoD Information Analysis Centers (IACs) focused on Defense Systems, Cyber Security and Information Systems, and Homeland Defense and Security. DTIC captures, preserves, protects, and shares research and development (R&amp;D) information assets, and encourages collaboration to connect user communities. DTIC seeks to provide a department level mapping of R&amp;D activity. This activity and its results advance research by providing researchers, warfighters, research and engineering (R&amp;E) management, and decision makers with insight into current and past research conducted, highlighting progress made and by whom, and, just as important, where research leads to dead ends.  As new capability needs are identified, technical challenges arise--rather than starting anew--work can pick up from the point of most recent results. Through the preservation and sharing of the results of billions of dollars of past DoD investment, DTIC increases the return on past investments and accelerates current efforts. Through its collaboration tools and outreach to the R&amp;E community, DTIC connects researchers across the lab enterprise, to include research and engineering, warfighters and DoD’s industry partners. DTIC operations focus on six key areas:

1) Collect, document and preserve what works, what has promise (for reuse and additional investments).
2) Provide results that identify dead-ends that do not merit additional investment (avoid waste).
3) Facilitate and encourage engagement among cross-cutting communities of interest (bring together experts across the acquisition enterprise to meet warfighter needs).
4) Present overarching picture of research investment that enables decision-makers to link multiple efforts with integrated capabilities (employ resources to highest priority efforts and coordinate efforts across Services).
5) Protect intellectual property (IP) and industry proprietary data assets entrusted to DTIC’s stewardship (protect information access).
6) Provide industry and citizen scientists the results of unrestricted research.

DTIC recognizes the need to accomplish its mission while increasing the value of the services and products we provide in an environment of Department-wide budget reductions.  DTIC has reduced its headquarter staffing, physical footprint, civilian personnel and contract support; restructured the IAC program; and continues to consolidate its data center.  At the same time, DTIC has taken on additional programs, to include its new role in leading the Department in efforts to provide public access to DoD-funded journal articles and research data and increase outreach to industry through the Defense Innovation Marketplace.  Moreover, DTIC activities promote Citizen Science, which mobilizes the public to participate in the scientific process to address real-world problems, in ways that include identifying research questions, collecting and analyzing data, interpreting results, making new discoveries, developing technologies and applications, and solving complex problems.  DTIC continues to ensure its activities are efficient and effective, meet users’ expectations, and employ industry best practices and standards, while protecting from cyber threats. DoD’s $120 Billion annual investment in research, development and procurement, support current and future capabilities. The results of these efforts are a national asset that DTIC must preserve for reuse across the acquisition enterprise. Approximately 23 percent of the four million records in DTIC’s information holdings are sensitive DoD only, federal government only and industry proprietary. DTIC is the only enterprise source for both publicly accessible and DoD sensitive material.

DTIC's Information Analysis Centers (IACs) drive innovation and technological development by anticipating and responding to the information needs of the defense and broader community. The IAC Program Office provides core funding, management and oversight of three IACs, which are chartered by DoD to collect, analyze, and disseminate worldwide scientific and technical information in specialized fields. IAC multi-award task order contracts maximize use of the knowledge within the centers, ensuring that new research, analysis, and development builds on prior investments and best practices of government, industry, and academia. The IAC approach is deemed a "best practice" by the Director, Defense Procurement and Acquisition Policy in a Jan 2015 memo promoting maximum use of the IAC contracts across DoD.  IACs are structured into three technology groupings: Cyber Security and Information Systems, Homeland Defense and Security, and Defense Systems. As part of the Department's Better Buying Power initiative, the IAC multi-award contracts enhance competition, increase outreach to and usage of small-businesses, and reduce government costs. The IAC model has demonstrated cost savings of 17-25%, delivering vetted technical expertise to address many of the complex challenges DoD faces. An independent assessment by the Center for Strategic and International Studies reported that the IACs improve affordability, productivity, and standardization within defense acquisition programs. Providing the acquisition enterprise access to thousands of industry subject matter experts, DTIC's IACs perform over $1 Billion of customer funded research and prototyping support annually.  The results of the work are a rich source of material in DTIC's information asset collections and are available to users across the Department (and other federal agencies, e.g., Department of Energy, Department of Homeland Security).

This Program Element (PE) supports DTIC mission operations. DTIC focuses on three core mission areas (Collection, Dissemination and IACs) and purchases space and shared services (e.g., human resources (HR); financial management; contracting; IT security; communications; and civilian payroll services) from expert and efficient DoD providers. DTIC’s role in the Department is to deliver the tools and collections that empower the research and engineering enterprise to accelerate the development of the technologies that will maintain U.S. technical superiority in the future; preserve and disseminate the research that led to the technologies our warfighters use today and will use in the future, and stimulate innovation with public/industry access to journal articles and the digital data that supports research conclusions funded by DoD. These activities maximize the value of each dollar the DoD spends through the analysis of funding data, work in progress and IR&amp;D to identify gaps, challenges and the way forward.  DTIC’s FY 2015-16 efforts support the Agency’s evolution from data dissemination to information dissemination. Laying the groundwork through the exploration of semantic technologies, and updating DTIC’s Thesaurus to provide a basis for semantic analysis, will result in applying semantic linking and tagging technology to new collections, such as grant journal articles, data set metadata and acquisition data and pilot a solution to consolidate multiple organization name taxonomies to enable consistent and comprehensive organization search, browse, and linking across DTIC content.  FY 2017 funds support the launch of information products that will take advantage of information architecture improvements to support U.S technological superiority with advances in warfighter technologies.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
            <r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>50.789</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>51.775</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>50.410</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>50.410</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>50.789</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>56.775</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>43.834</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>43.834</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>5.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>-6.576</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-6.576</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                    <r2:CongressionalGeneralReductions>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    </r2:CongressionalGeneralReductions>
                    <r2:CongressionalDirectedReductions>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    </r2:CongressionalDirectedReductions>
                    <r2:CongressionalAdds>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>5.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                    </r2:CongressionalAdds>
                    <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                            <r2:Title>Reprogramming to PE 0605998KA</r2:Title>
                            <r2:Funding>
                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>-4.400</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-4.400</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            </r2:Funding>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                            <r2:Title>Program Changes</r2:Title>
                            <r2:Funding>
                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>-2.044</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-2.044</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            </r2:Funding>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                            <r2:Title>Economic Assumptions - Pay/NonPay Inflation</r2:Title>
                            <r2:Funding>
                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>-0.132</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-0.132</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            </r2:Funding>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                    </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                <r2:SummaryExplanation>Specific changes to the FY 2017 program (net decrease of $12.941 Million from the FY 2016 “Current President’s Budget” funding level; $6.576 Million less from the previous FY 2017 PB Base) are outlined below:

FY 2016 Congressional Adds:  $5.000 Million one-time congressional add to the FY 2016 DTIC program element.  The omnibus language cites “Program Increase:  National security technology accelerator technology knowledge exchange.” This has not been programmed as an enduring increase; as such, this appears as a $5.0 Million decrease in the FY 2017 PB position.

Previous President’s Budget:  The $1.365 Million reduction from the FY 2016 position to the FY 2017 Base reflects the curtailment of operating activities across the enterprise, and the deferment of modernization and development of DTIC tools and applications slated for DTIC’s various user communities.  Reductions to civilian FTEs and the streamlining of DTIC contract requirements continue in FY 2017.

FY 2017 Program Changes: The DTIC mission serves as an efficiency enabler to the Department.  Funding reductions to the DTIC program, as necessitated by budget realities, reduces opportunities for the Department to gain efficiencies and cost reductions across the enterprise.  In FY 2017, there is a $2.044 Million budget reduction from the FY 2016 funding level.  As a result of this reduction, the following DTIC efforts and program content will be down-scoped in FY 2017:

- Public Access program/Public website capabilities.
-- The collection of data sets associated with Public Access will be limited to a pilot in FY 2017.  Activities will be limited to current capacity.  The procurement of additional storage capacity and bandwidth will be delayed to FY 2018.
-- Development of advance search capabilities related to public search of Technical Reports (TRs) will be delayed.
-- User training, along with the establishment of compliance and enforcement measures within the Department, will be deferred to FY 2018.
-- Search capabilities associated with DTIC’s public website will not be expanded, limiting site utility to the user community.
- Development and capability upgrades planned for the Defense Innovation Marketplace will be deferred, limiting access and utility by both Department and industry users.
- Reduce efforts focused on the integration of data, communities and analysis across the Acquisition and Science and Technology (S&amp;T) enterprise.  Development of product enhancements that support visibility of--and integration across--existing acquisition data sources will be limited.
- Limit the introduction of unclassified material available to users on the Department’s SIPRNET. The updating of SIPRNET data content and capabilities will be delayed, thereby creating a parity lag with comparable NIPRNET applications.
- The funding reduction will limit DTIC’s responsiveness in addressing emerging requirements and mandates, and degrade our ability to enable efficiencies to offset Management HQ reduction impacts in OSD and the Services.

FY 2017 Economic Assumptions:  $.132 Million represents pricing adjustments based on revised economic and inflation factors.

FY 2017 Reprogramming:  $4.400 Million was reprogrammed by the Department from the DTIC PE 0605801KA to create a new DTIC Management Headquarters PE 0605998KA. The newly established PE and accompanying funding will support the HQ staff element assigned to DTIC.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
            </r2:ChangeSummary>
            <r2:ProjectList>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Defense Technical Information Center</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>48.971</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>45.041</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>51.027</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>38.086</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>38.086</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>39.756</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>40.620</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>41.212</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>41.930</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>DTIC is responsible for developing, coordinating and enabling a strong scientific and technical information (STINFO) program for the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering (ASD(R&amp;E)) and the DoD scientific &amp; technical (S&amp;T) enterprise. In this role, DTIC sets policy for scientific and technical information (STI) exchanges for the research and engineering (R&amp;E) community. DTIC’s aim is to maximize the availability and use of technical information and products resulting from Defense-funded technical activities while ensuring restrictions to safeguard national security, export control, and intellectual property rights.

Recognizing the common elements across budget justification documents, progress reports, completed work reports, studies, and journal articles, DTIC is mapping relationships to enable users to access the life cycle of research projects from planning to final results. DTIC employs technology to verify and validate information submitted and improve user confidence in DoD research documentation.

DTIC is leading the Department’s efforts to implement public access to published journal articles, and digital data from research funded by taxpayers. In this role, DTIC is actively working with partners across the Services, components, other federal agencies and publishers.  These ongoing efforts directly complement and support the Department’s objectives associated with Citizen Science.  Consistent with the Administration’s (Office of Management and Budget) emphasis for open standards and machine readable formats, DTIC initiated the transition from paper and Portable Document Format (PDF) based information to Web Service Extensible Markup Language (XML) standard data submission and machine readable delivery. DTIC partnered with the OSD Comptroller to collect investment account budget justification documentation in XML and embed this XML in PDF for justification books delivered to Congress. DTIC employed this same technology in collecting S&amp;T progress reports from the Services and Agencies, and Independent Research and Development (IR&amp;D) data from industry. DTIC is planning the migration of completed technical reports collection to the same open standards – machine readable formats.

Through the use of commercial search technology, DTIC provides an industry leading search capability that links its knowledge of the DoD domain and metadata to support both text searches and data mining. DTIC continually works to enable additional features within our search capabilities and from commercial partners to improve information discovery and relevance.

DoD conducts research at its 60+ labs, in the Federally Funded Research and Development Centers (FFRDCs), DTIC’s Information Analysis Centers (IACs), through contracts and grants, and across over a dozen distinct priority area communities of interest; this work is available through DTIC’s web-based R&amp;E Gateway. To protect this information, DTIC maintains a database of registered users; in addition, DTIC utilizes commercial software and follows DoD Identity Management Standards, providing Common Access Card (CAC) users instant authenticated access.  DTIC’s unclassified assets, tools and community interaction capabilities foster innovation, competition and identification of solutions in an access controlled environment.

Focus on User Communities and Distribution Points:  DTIC supports user communities on the network where they work, NIPRNET, SIPRNET and Internet, and uniquely provides access controls within unclassified and classified material to protect intellectual property in our search, distribution, and collaboration tools.

- DoD’s Acquisition Enterprise: As a Field Activity to ASD(R&amp;E)/AT&amp;L, DTIC’s priority is the acquisition enterprise, hosting information assets and tools on the NIPRNET (the primary network for the community).

- Warfighter: Improving coordination between the acquisition enterprise and warfighter communities, DTIC hosts a subset of information assets and tools on the SIPRNET. DTIC is working to expand the availability of S&amp;T information, to include Independent Research and Development (IR&amp;D), on the SIPRNET.  Efforts continue to establish parity of information and capabilities on applications hosted on both NIPRNET and SIPRNET platforms.

- Industry and Academia via Internet:  Engaging industry outside the NIPRNET “firewall” to support Better Buying Power initiatives and encourage the introduction of innovation, DTIC hosts unclassified “public” information and tools accessible to all users on the Internet. The Public Access initiative adds importance to the public distribution point, to encourage technology transfer of basic and public research to the private sector, and to give an economic boost to small businesses that can use that data to provide new applications to consumers.

Summary.  DTIC protects and preserves DoD’s multi-billion dollar investment in research, which empowers the acquisition enterprise through innovative tools, information systems, and decision support capabilities. The benefits can be enormous; each 1 percent increase in reuse of S&amp;T, elimination of inefficient redundancy and increased community interaction, results in a more capable military and gives the DoD the opportunity to redirect >$100 Million. DTIC is uniquely positioned to support and unleash the value of DoD’s R&amp;D portfolio.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Defense Technical Information Center</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>45.041</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>- Managed and implemented the primary objectives associated with public access to publications and digital data. Providing public access to federally funded research not only brings the Department into compliance with the OSTP Memorandum, but also provides DoD a central repository of all published S&amp;T information and datasets.
-- Worked with the Defense Basic Research Advisory Group (DBRAG) to initiate policy changes for phase I, intramural basic research projects.
-- Explored and identified a monitoring and compliance mechanism; added public access compliance fields to Unified Research and Engineering Database (URED).
-- Identified a catalog/locator to track data set locations, and potential DoD digital repositories for storage.
-- Completed the interface pilot program in partnership with Department of Energy to provide access to DoD-funded publications.
- Evolved and improved Defense Innovation Marketplace capabilities in alignment with the Department’s Better Buying Power 2.0/3.0 initiative, enabling acquisitions experts to include industry-sponsored research in their buying plans.
-- Captured industry’s classified Independent Research and Development (IR&amp;D) and moved search collection to the SIPRNET environment.
-- Employed the Marketplace for virtual Technology Interchange Meetings with industry.
- Acquired a solution and initiated implementation of consolidated DTIC data collections into one common storage infrastructure (the Master Data Repository) for increased analysis capabilities across the suite of collections.
- Bolstered capabilities of the DoD Research and Engineering (R&amp;E) Gateway based on specific user requirements and usage.  The Acquisition community, the S&amp;T communities of interest (CoIs), and the Department requested access to the R&amp;E Gateway databases on SIPRNET to ensure all users have access to the same information.
-- Engaged defense communities and their subject matter experts; worked with partners to expand user-provided content and research materials to benefit the DoD mission.
-- Promoted information sharing and secure collaboration among the 17 DoD science and technology (S&amp;T) communities of interest (COIs) by assisting them with DTIC’s collaborative tools.
-- Expanded technical and budget content available on SIPRNET version.
- Deployed new Unified Research and Engineering Database (URED) capabilities for the user community to expand Department’s usage of URED information.  Modified and enhanced DoD research summaries to capture information related to public access of journal articles and digital data.  
- Strengthened access controls to the DoD Research and Engineering (R&amp;E) Gateway and other DTIC provided tools with the introduction of smart-card login for eligible users within the defense industry, to comply with the DoD CIO mandate to eliminate user ID and password access.
- Expanded the searchable International Agreements Database (IADB) for DoD users by integrating international agreements from Defense Threat Reduction Agency (DTRA), Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) and Missile Defense Agency (MDA) to provide a single access point for users seeking information on DoD International Agreements.
- Implemented Initial Operating Capability (IOC) for the new DTIC unclassified content management system in the DoD-hosted cloud.
-- Determined a solution to securely transfer data between the unclassified and classified content management systems.
- Met DoD’s audit readiness milestones and requirements.
- Began the planning and implementation of data center migration to a DoD-CIO approved facility and/or cloud service.  
- Implemented the data center IT hardware and software refresh, reducing the both the physical footprint and related support costs, while improving system security and reliability.
- Aligned with the DoD initiative for the Federal Data Center Consolidation Initiatives (FDCCI) to maximize the virtualization of DTIC systems and applications and how to best support DoD, industry partners, and academia users.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Accomplishment>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>51.027</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>- In an effort to offset the impacts of budgetary and staff reductions, investigate the potential and capabilities of semantics to automate the auto-tagging and mapping of relationships across DTIC’s suite of collections.  If successful, this effort would enable users to discover information with less expertise.
- Support DoD’s public access effort; implement Phase I, intramural basic research, including compliance tracking and enforcement for public access, and the policy development process for contracts and grants. Public access to federally funded research provides DoD a central repository of all published S&amp;T information and datasets.  Expand publically-available content in support of the Department’s Citizen Science objectives.  
-- Implement a catalog/locator to track data set locations.
-- Process journal articles, and look into hosting smaller data sets in support of intramural research.
-- Begin pilot projects for voluntary submission of contract and grant published articles and data sets.
- Expand Defense Innovation Marketplace search and analytic capabilities in alignment with the Department’s Better Buying Power 3.0 initiative; add small business research information.
-- Employ the Marketplace for virtual Technology Interchange Meetings with industry.
-- Explore the utility of Technology Domain Awareness (TDA) activities.  Develop roadmap and execute initial outreach with the National Defense University (NDU).
- Implement Full Operating Capability (FOC) of DTIC standard library content management system in the DoD-hosted cloud; implement a classified version.
-- Consolidate report collection into a DTIC standard input solution, reducing the footprint of multiple technologies and driving efficiencies and cost avoidance.
- Implement Full Operating Capability of the Master Data Repository (MDR) solution to consolidate DTIC data collections into one common storage infrastructure for increased analysis and visualization capabilities across the suite of collections.
-- Implement a classified version of the MDR.
-- Expand the collections available to DTIC users with an advanced, integrated search on both the NIPRNET and SIPRNET.
- Collaborate with the DoD Intelligence community on policy and planning for the implementation of the new Controlled Unclassified Information (CUI) federal marking regulations.
- Offer enhanced Unified Research and Engineering Database (URED) capabilities and training for the user community, to include advanced search and visualization functionalities to support better decision making across the Department.  Provide requested capabilities to expand the Department’s usage of the URED information.
- Evaluate metrics, usage patterns and new user requirements to determine and implement more advanced, integrated capabilities for the DoD Research and Engineering (R&amp;E) Gateway collaboration, search and analytics on the NIPRNET and SIPRNET based on this feedback. By evaluating usage metrics on a continuous basis DTIC can provide better customer services and training opportunities targeted to user groups.
-- Expand outreach to the DTIC user community and DoD science and technology (S&amp;T) communities of interest (COIs) by offering onsite briefings, demonstrations and training for the R&amp;E Gateway search and collaborative tools.
- Implement a reporting and dashboard capability in the International Agreements Database (IADB).
- Meet DoD’s audit readiness milestones and requirements.
- Align with DoD Joint Information Environment (JIE) initiative for the Federal Data Center Consolidation Initiatives (FDCCI) by maximizing the virtualization of DTIC systems and applications that services all of the DoD, industry partners, and academia users.
- Plan the migration of DTIC to a DoD-CIO approved cloud service provider, based on final guidance from the Department.  Assist DTIC-hosted customers to do the same.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>38.086</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>38.086</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>- Evaluate FY 2016 progress in semantic technology; expand semantic enhancement of content to promote exploration and discovery to the extent maturing capabilities allow.  If progress in semantic technology is deemed insufficient, the following plans will be jeopardized. 
-- Apply semantic linking and tagging technology to new collections, such as grant journal articles, data set metadata and acquisition data.
-- Pilot solution to consolidate multiple organization name taxonomies to enable consistent and comprehensive organization search, browse, and linking across DTIC content.
- Support DoD’s public access effort, albeit at a reduced level; implement Phase II, extramural basic research, for contracts and grants, as the policy language is published in the Code of Federal Regulations (CFR). Providing public access to federally funded research not only brings the Department into compliance with the OSTP Memorandum, but also provides DoD a central repository of all published S&amp;T information and datasets.
-- Begin accepting voluntary submission of journal articles and digital data, albeit limited to file size under 2GB.
-- Provide public pilot searchable catalog to order digital data.
-- Promote and support the Department’s Citizen Science efforts; improve data quality, advance openness and the preserving and sharing of data, and expand public participation in the scientific process, helping to find solutions to DoD challenges.
- Complement the Department’s Better Buying Power 3.0 (BBP 3.0) initiative by expanding the search and analytic capabilities of the Defense Innovation Marketplace.
-- Broaden the scope to include commercial, domestic, and international data sources, contributors and users.
-- Maintain the Marketplace capability to support all the Services’ communications with industry for virtual Technology Interchange Meetings, across all of the Communities of Interest (COIs).
-- Expand Independent Research and Development (IR&amp;D) database fields to comply with BBP 3.0 and Defense Procurement and Acquisition Policy (DPAP) guidelines for technical sponsors and written technical reports on the projects.
-- Review Technology Domain Awareness (TDA) results, and develop next steps to reach and access non-traditional commercial sources.
- Continue migrating legacy standalone collection feeds to DTIC’s standard library content management system in the DoD-hosted cloud, reducing the footprint of multiple technologies and driving efficiencies and cost avoidance.
-- Add additional collections and processing to the content management system.
-- Create a programming interface for bulk load of input from the DoD Labs.
-- Seek opportunities with DoD Labs to pilot a service to automatically pull technical reports or project information from local document management systems, reducing the burden on labs, opportunities for error, and lag time to publish.
- Employ the Master Data Repository (MDR) solution to increase analysis and visualization capabilities across the suite of collections.
-- Add new collections to the MDR.
-- Investigate the use of MDR for development of new customer and ASD(R&amp;E) products using information across DTIC collections.
-- Implement ability to automatically publish web pages on topical areas.
-- Create a programming interface for searches to promote reuse of S&amp;T content by other DoD and federal organizations.
- Begin implementation of the new Controlled Unclassified Information (CUI) markings and programming validation for the new categories into DTIC systems.
-- Change user validation categories in registration system, document markings in input system and access control rules in MDR.
- Develop and enhance integrated search and analysis tools across all collections, including ongoing and completed research by industry, academia, and government, on the NIPRNET and SIPRNET. Provide requested capabilities to expand the Department’s usage of the URED information.
- Continue migration of DTIC sites and tools, along with DTIC-hosted external customer sites and tools, to the cloud and other hosting locations, as approved by DoD-CIO.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>Figures reflect FY 2015 end-of-year data.

Community Interaction
1) Unique NIPRNET and SIPRNET Users:  29.2K
- SIPRNET users added in FY 2015 metrics.

Research Support and Library Repository
1) Scientific and technical information (STI) collected (both NIPRNET and SIPRNET ):  96.8K  
- SIPRNET collected added in FY 2015 metrics.

2) Total STI disseminated, to include competed work reports, work-in-progress summaries, industry IR&amp;D, digitization requests, web inquiries, and citations (added in FY 2015 metrics):
- Access Control Downloads (NIPRNET and SIPRNET):  1.52M
- Public Document Downloads:  34.7M

3) Total STI holdings:  4.1M</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>002</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Information Analysis Centers</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>7.053</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>5.748</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>5.748</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>5.748</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>5.748</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>5.748</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>5.897</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>5.978</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>6.104</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>DoD Information Analysis Centers (IACs), established under DoD Instruction 3200.14, serve as a vital resource in providing timely, relevant information directly to users when and where it is needed. IACs serve as a bridge between the warfighter and the Acquisition/Research community, providing essential technical analysis and data support to a diverse customer base, to include the Combatant Commands (CCMDs), the Office of the Secretary of Defense, Defense Agencies, and the Military Services. IACs actively partner and collaborate with Defense Research and Engineering (R&amp;E) focus groups and communities of interest in areas of specialized fields or specific technologies. The IACs create and maintain comprehensive knowledge analysis centers that include historical, technical, scientific, and other data and information collected worldwide. They are staffed with scientists, engineers and information specialists to provide research and analysis to customers with diverse, complex and challenging requirements. IAC operations directly support the warfighter, and play an ongoing and critical role in solving key CCMD operational issues such as cyber security, unmanned aerial vehicle visual/audible signature reduction, and improvements to the ballistic resistance of body armor.

The IAC Program Management Office at DTIC performs contract acquisition, management, and operational support for IAC contract operations and the technical information that is generated as a result of research and studies. In a time of shrinking budgets and increasing responsibility, IACs are a valuable resource for accessing scientific and technical information culled from efforts to solve new and historic challenges.  Direct IAC customer support activities, such as Technical Area Task (TAT) order processing, Basic Center Operations (BCO) support, Defense Finance and Accounting Service (DFAS) activities, contracting/acquisition related activities, etc., are funded in part through partnerships with the Defense R&amp;E community and the annual collection of customer reimbursements for shared direct costs, in accordance with the IAC Reimbursable Review Board (IRRB) recommendations, with OSD-COMPT and Office of General Counsel concurrence.  This represents the maximum cost-sharing with IAC customers allowable, per guidance from the OSD Office of General Counsel. Annual IAC efforts and accomplishments are dependent on the level of participation and collaboration by the R&amp;E community at large.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Information Analysis Centers</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>5.748</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>- Supported the DTIC mission to provide technical information to DoD.
- Provided administrative oversight and basic core contract operations for DoD IACs to collect, analyze, synthesize and disseminate worldwide scientific and technical information (STI) in support of DoD's critical technologies and the warfighter.
- Responded to technical inquiries and provide in-depth science and technology (S&amp;T) analysis; create and provide STI results via IAC websites; captured STI products from new/on-going analysis tasks; and supported the exchange of information among members of the operational and technical communities.
- Managed and supported TATs ordered by the DoD and non-DoD customers; provided program strategy and ensured alignment with Department goals/direction.
- Finalized acquisition strategy for the re-compete of the Software, Networks, Information, Modeling and Simulation (SNIM) contract to Cyber Systems Technical Area Tasks (CS TAT).
- Awarded 105 new Technical Area Tasks (TAT) and Core Analysis Tasks (CAT) over six contract vehicles, representing over $2 Billion in research and analysis work for the Department.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Accomplishment>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>5.748</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>- Support the DTIC mission to provide technical information to DoD.
- Provide administrative oversight and basic core contract operations for DoD IACs to collect, analyze, synthesize and disseminate worldwide scientific and technical information (STI) in support of DoD's critical technologies and the warfighter.
- Respond to technical inquiries and provide in-depth science and technology (S&amp;T) analysis; create and provide STI results via IAC websites; capture STI products from new/on-going analysis tasks; and support the exchange of information among members of the operational and technical communities.
- Manage and support TATs ordered by the DoD and non-DoD customers; provide program strategy and ensure alignment with Department goals/direction.
- Plan for the re-placement of the Software, Networks, Information, Modeling and Simulation (SNIM) contract. 
- Complete award of new multi-award contract for Cyber Systems TAT.
- Award approximately 71 new TATs and 30 new CATs totaling approximately $2.2 Billion in new research and analysis work.  This is approximately a 9% increase in the typical annual work load for the IAC program.
- Increase the ceiling limit for the Defense Systems TAT (DS TAT) multi-award contract from its current $3 Billion limit to about $7 Billion (at its present ceiling burn rate, DS TAT will hit its ceiling in June 2016, about 2.5 years before it ends).</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>5.748</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>5.748</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>- Support the DTIC mission to provide technical information to DoD.
- Provide administrative oversight and basic core contract operations for DoD IACs to collect, analyze, synthesize and disseminate worldwide scientific and technical information (STI) in support of DoD's critical technologies and the warfighter.
- Respond to technical inquiries and provide in-depth science and technology (S&amp;T) analysis; create and provide STI results via IAC websites; capture STI products from new/on-going analysis tasks; and support the exchange of information among members of the operational and technical communities.
- Manage and support TATs ordered by the DoD and non-DoD customers; provide program strategy and ensure alignment with Department goals/direction.
- Continue to use ACC Picatinny for processing TAT awards; engage in aggressive customer outreach to initiate processing early.
- Increase the ceiling limit for the Homeland Defense TAT (HD TAT) multi-award contract from its current $900 Million limit to about $2 Billion (at its present ceiling burn rate, HD TAT will hit its ceiling in Jan 2017, about 2.3 years before it ends).
- Develop and implement an acquisition strategy for follow-on contract vehicles for DS TAT and HD TAT.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>Figures reflect FY 2015 end-of-year data.

Number of:
- IAC web inquiries:  1,492,346
- IAC technical inquiries:  4,067
- STI documents added to IAC collection:  31,806
- STI documents generated by Technical Area Task (TAT) activities:  6,714
- Training or meeting events:  1,673
- Number of training attendees:  5,385
- Documents uploaded to DTIC's online repository:  27,333

Amount of funding:
- Provided by external customer requesting IAC technical analysis (TAT Funding):  $1,305,721,327
- Provided by external customers purchasing IAC information products (Non-TAT funding):  $110,577

Customer satisfaction regarding:
- IAC products and technical inquiry support (scale of 1 to 5, 5 being best):  4.9
- IAC TATs and training (scale of 1 to 5, 5 being best):  4.9</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
            </r2:ProjectList>
        </r2:ProgramElement>
        <r2:ProgramElement monetaryUnit="Millions" format="R2Long" classification="UNCLASSIFIED">
            <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0605998KA</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
            <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Management HQ - Defense Technical Information Center (DTIC)</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
            <r2:R1LineNumber>164</r2:R1LineNumber>
            <r2:BudgetYear>2017</r2:BudgetYear>
            <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
            <r2:SubmissionDate>2016-02</r2:SubmissionDate>
            <r2:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Technical Information Center</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
            <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
            <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
            <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>6</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
            <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>RDT&amp;E Management Support</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
            <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                <r2:BudgetYearOne>4.400</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>4.400</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                <r2:BudgetYearTwo>4.187</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                <r2:BudgetYearThree>4.470</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                <r2:BudgetYearFour>4.270</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                <r2:BudgetYearFive>4.560</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
            </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
            <r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>4.400</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>4.400</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>4.400</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>4.400</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                    <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                            <r2:Title>Reprogrammed from PE 0605801KA</r2:Title>
                            <r2:Funding>
                                <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>4.400</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>4.400</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            </r2:Funding>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                    </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                <r2:SummaryExplanation>Specific changes to the FY 2017 program (net increase of $4.400 Million from both the FY 2016 funding level and the previous PB Base) are outlined below:

- $4.400 Million was reprogrammed by the Department from the DTIC PE 0605801KA to create a new DTIC Management Headquarters PE 0605998KA.  The newly established PE and accompanying funding will support the HQ staff element assigned to DTIC.  FY 2017 funding reflects a reduction in civilian HQ full time equivalents (FTEs) from FY 2016 levels.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
            </r2:ChangeSummary>
            <r2:ProjectList>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Management HQ - Defense Technical Information Center (DTIC)</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>4.400</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>4.400</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>4.187</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>4.470</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>4.270</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>4.560</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>This program element (PE) provides funding for the Management Headquarters (HQ) element of the Defense Technical Information Center (DTIC), a DoD Field Activity to the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering (ASD(R&amp;E)/AT&amp;L).  The PE supports personnel compensation for HQ-assigned civilians, along with related administrative support costs.  This second DTIC PE is established to track activities deemed as headquarters functions, with no operational efficiencies or enhancement to mission.

The new PE supports the following HQ functions and mission essential activities critical to the success of DTIC’s business operations, and mandated by law or regulation: 

- Activity leadership, strategic planning, and Front Office support staff.
-- The front office staff (~ 6 authorizations) represents a small component of this PE.  Most of the specialized functions and skill-sets described below are centralized activities within the PE, yet support the larger organization and its employees.  These activities were consolidated as a means to improve efficiencies throughout DTIC, and are essential to the operation of DTIC’s primary PE 0605801KA.
-- Reductions to DTIC’s HQ staffing levels continue, reducing civilian full time equivalents (FTEs) below FY 2016 levels. 
- Financial Management and Comptroller.  Provides integrated resource management at the Agency level to obtain, control, and execute budget and manpower authorities to support the organization's mission requirements.  Develops and prepares agency budget documents and exhibits for submission to both OSD and Congress.
-- Accounting support to DTIC’s mission operations; partners with the Defense Finance and Accounting Service to present accurate financial reporting and Fund Balance with Treasury. 
-- Financial Improvement and Audit Readiness (FIAR) activities and oversight in compliance with the Department’s audit goals, objectives, and milestones.
- Human Resources (HR) Liaison Support.  Provides the DTIC enterprise with payroll processing and “Hire to Retire” mission support; oversees and organizes employee training, professional development, and certification programs (e.g., Acquisition, Financial Management, and IT programs).
-- Coordinates recruitment placement and classification action for the mission areas; liaison to the Defense Finance and Accounting Service for HR servicing and the Defense Logistics Agency (DLA) for Equal Employment Opportunity (EEO) program maintenance.
- Mandatory Records Management compliance activities and administration programs.
- IT Management/Chief Information Officer (CIO).  Collects, analyzes, and reports information necessary to effectively and efficiently manage enterprise IT resources; CIO functions are performed in compliance with DoD-CIO guidance, instructions and mandates. 
- IT Help Desk/Local Area Network (LAN).  Office automation supports desktop computing customers; resolves IT-related equipment or system incidents; provides assured system and network availability, info delivery, and secure IT solutions to support current and future business and mission requirements.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Management HQ - Defense Technical Information Center</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>0.000</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>- N/A.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Accomplishment>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>0.000</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>- N/A.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>4.400</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>4.400</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>- Execute the program, activities and functions as described above in Section A, Mission Description of PE 0605998KA.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>N/A</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
            </r2:ProjectList>
        </r2:ProgramElement>
    </r2:ProgramElementList>
</jb:JustificationBook>