<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jb:MasterJustificationBook xmlns:jb="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/jb" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
    <jb:BudgetYear>2016</jb:BudgetYear>
    <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
    <jb:SubmissionDate>2015-02</jb:SubmissionDate>
    <jb:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Security Service</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
    <jb:CoverPage/>
    <jb:ExternalDocuments>
        <jb:UserR1Doc>
            <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit R-1</jb:Title>
            <jb:FileName>12345678.pdf</jb:FileName>
        </jb:UserR1Doc>
    </jb:ExternalDocuments>
    <jb:TableOfContents>
        <jb:TocItemList>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 1</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Missile Defense Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 2</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Office of the Secretary Of Defense</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 3</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Chemical and Biological Defense Program</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 4</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Contract Management Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>DoD Human Resources Activity</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Information Systems Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Logistics Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Security Cooperation Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Security Service</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Technical Information Center</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Threat Reduction Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>The Joint Staff</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>United States Special Operations Command</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Washington Headquarters Service</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Operational Test and Evaluation, Defense</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Geospatial Intelligence Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>(see NIP and MIP Justification Books)</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Intelligence Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>(see NIP and MIP Justification Books)</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>National Security Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>(see NIP and MIP Justification Books)</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
        </jb:TocItemList>
    </jb:TableOfContents>
    <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        <jb:GenerateP1m>true</jb:GenerateP1m>
    </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
    <jb:JustificationBookGroupList>
        <jb:JustificationBookGroup>
            <jb:JustificationBookInfoList>
                <jb:JustificationBookInfo>
                    <jb:BookDescription>Defense Security Service</jb:BookDescription>
                    <jb:BookLabel>Volume</jb:BookLabel>
                    <jb:BookNumber>5</jb:BookNumber>
                    <jb:JustificationBook targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
                        <jb:Title>Justification Book</jb:Title>
                        <jb:BudgetYear>2016</jb:BudgetYear>
                        <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
                        <jb:SubmissionDate>2015-02</jb:SubmissionDate>
                        <jb:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Security Service</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
                        <jb:AppropriationCode>0400</jb:AppropriationCode>
                        <jb:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</jb:AppropriationName>
                        <jb:CoverPage/>
                        <jb:ExternalDocuments>
                            <jb:UserR1Doc>
                                <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit R-1</jb:Title>
                                <jb:FileName>12345678.pdf</jb:FileName>
                            </jb:UserR1Doc>
                        </jb:ExternalDocuments>
                        <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
                            <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>
                            <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>
                            <jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>true</jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>
                        </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
                        <r2:R2ExhibitList xmlns:r2="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/r2" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
                            <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
                                <r2:ProgramElement>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0604130V</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Enterprise Security System</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                                    <r2:R1LineNumber>178</r2:R1LineNumber>
                                    <r2:BudgetYear>2016</r2:BudgetYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                                    <r2:SubmissionDate>2015-02</r2:SubmissionDate>
                                    <r2:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Security Service</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                                    <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                                    <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                                    <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>7</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                                    <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Operational Systems Development</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                        <r2:AllPriorYears>93.925</r2:AllPriorYears>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>7.552</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>3.988</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.929</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.929</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>6.641</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>3.275</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>3.332</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>3.399</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                    </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Defense Security Service (DSS) oversees the protection of the nation's most critical technological and information assets, administers the National Industrial Security Program (NISP) on behalf of the Department of Defense and 27 other Federal agencies.  In this capacity, DSS is responsible for providing security oversight, counterintelligence coverage and support to almost 10,000 cleared companies (comprising over 13,500 + industrial facilities and about 1.2 million cleared contractors), and accreditation of more than 14,000 classified information technology systems in the NISP.  DSS also serves as the functional manager responsible for the execution and maintenance of DoD security training.

The Defense Security Service manages the National Industrial Security Program (NISP) to provide an effective, real-time, security support capability for the Military Departments, DoD Agencies, the NISP, and other Federal Agencies.  In compliance with the Expanded Electronic Government, President’s Management Agenda, and the DoD Enterprise Architecture Framework, NISP is the unified offering of security mission systems which facilitate and automate improved national investigative and adjudicative standards, streamline security processes, and increase DoD community collaboration.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                                    <r2:ChangeSummary>
                                        <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>7.552</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>3.988</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.800</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.800</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>7.552</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>3.988</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.929</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.929</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>4.129</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>4.129</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                        <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                                                <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                                    <r2:Title>Other Program Increase</r2:Title>
                                                    <r2:Funding>
                                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>4.129</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>4.129</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    </r2:Funding>
                                                </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                                        </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                                        <r2:SummaryExplanation>Increase is due to additional funds being allocated to the support of Mobile Web applications and Proactive Monitoring.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
                                    </r2:ChangeSummary>
                                    <r2:ProjectList>
                                        <r2:Project>
                                            <r2:ProjectNumber>000</r2:ProjectNumber>
                                            <r2:ProjectTitle>Enterprise Security System</r2:ProjectTitle>
                                            <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                                            <r2:ProjectFunding>
                                                <r2:AllPriorYears>93.925</r2:AllPriorYears>
                                                <r2:PriorYear>7.552</r2:PriorYear>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>3.988</r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.929</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.929</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearTwo>6.641</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearThree>3.275</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearFour>3.332</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearFive>3.399</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:ProjectFunding>
                                            <r2:R2aExhibit>
                                                <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Defense Security Service manages the Enterprise Security System (ESS) to provide an effective, real-time, security support capability for the Military Departments, DoD Agencies, the NISP, and other Federal Agencies.  In compliance with the Expanded Electronic Government, President’s Management Agenda, and the DoD Enterprise Architecture Framework, ESS is the unified offering of security mission systems which facilitate and automate improved national investigative and adjudicative standards, streamline security processes, and increase DoD community collaboration.

The DSS Mission Information Technology (IT) systems provide critical service to the major DSS mission areas for Industrial Security Oversight and Security Education.  DSS performs this critical function through operation of its mission production systems to include the Industrial Security Facilities Database (ISFD), the DSS Gateway, and the Security Training Education and Professionalization Portal (STEPP).  RDT&amp;E for DSS mission systems primarily includes pre-planned product improvements to the applications, researching and improving assured information sharing to better posture systems and networks against vulnerabilities, ensuring self-defense of systems and networks, and safeguarding data at all stages for the DSS to increase efficiencies by providing web-based systems to manage certification and accreditation activities. These IT systems are as follows:   

Office of Designated Approving Authority (ODAA) Business Management System (OBMS).  The OBMS will automate the approval and certification process of cleared industry’s classified information processing security plans and operations.  This will increase mission efficiency by providing a web-based system to manage certification and accreditation activities, provide improved reporting capabilities to support DSS and industry through improved metrics, accreditation timeliness and accuracy and reduce the number of unaccredited systems by providing automated notifications to DSS and industry.  

EFCL:  The eFCL will be a centralized repository for information of facilities participating in the National Industrial Security Program (NISP). The eFCL will capture facility information relating to a cleared facility, from the initial processing of the facility clearance, the record decision pertaining to facility clearance request, to include Foreign Ownership Control or Influence (FOCI) information, as well as decommissioning the facility clearance, and capturing the DSS oversight activities.  The eFCL will provide a means for users to submit, update, search, and view facility verification requests.

Industrial Security Facilities Database (ISFD).  ISFD is the main DSS mission system that tracks and executes the National Industrial Security Program for DoD and 27 other Federal Executive Agencies of cleared industrial security facilities.  The ISFD provide users with a nationwide perspective on National Industrial Security Program related facilities, as well as, facilities under DSS oversight in the DoD conventional AA&amp;E program. ISFD provides source data for the DoD Joint Personnel Adjudicative System (JPAS) and the Facility Verification Request (FVR) application.

National Industrial Security System (NISS, formerly known as Field Operations System (FOS).  The NISS is slated as the next generation enterprise capability, replacing the Industrial Security Facility Database (ISFD).  Additionally, NISS will provide seamless integration of other DSS systems and applications, such as eFCL, OBMS, DD-254, and Mobile Workforce Applications.  NISS will provide DSS with comprehensive enhanced capability to manage its entire mission portfolio.  NISS will improve information sharing and collaboration, providing timely and accurate data in the hands of field representatives for decision-making.  The system will provide agency-wide metrics to measure and improve agency performance in providing security oversight and the protection of national security.  

The National Contract Classification System (NCCS).  The Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) requires a DD Form 254 be incorporated in each classified contract, and the National Industrial Security Operating Manual (NISPOM)(4-103a) requires a DD 254 be issued by the government with each Invitation for Bid, Request for Proposal, or Request for Quote. The DD Form 254 provides contractor (or a subcontractor) the security requirements and classification guidance necessary to perform on a classified contract. Contract Security Classification Specification required by DoD 5220.22-4, Industrial Security Regulation and the National Industrial Security Program Operating Manual (NISPOM) is to develop a federated system for the oversight and management of providing classified information access and guidance required to perform on classified contracts. The DD 254, an underlying business processes, is critical to ensure access to our Nation’s classified information is properly safeguarded.


National Industrial Security Program (NISP) Control Access and Information Security System (NCAISS) formerly known as Identity Management (IdM).  NCAISS is mandatory for compliance with Department of Defense (DoD) Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Program Management Office and Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Networks and Information Integration (ASD-NII), Joint Task Force for Global Networks Operations (JTF-GNO) Communications Tasking Order (CTO) 06-02, CTO 07-015, and Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Memo 11-11 (M-11-11), directing accelerated use of PKI across the enterprise.  This initiative is designed to enable multiple DSS business systems to have service-accessibility that is controlled through PKI-compliant single sign-on authentication.  Expanded use of the NCAISS across the DSS enterprise to provide CAC-based authentication for business support applications to support the SIPRNet and JWICS domains, provide enhanced identity and access control analytics. It will also incorporate any remaining DSS operated application into the DSS NCAISS solution.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                                    <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                        <r2:Title>Systems Enhancement</r2:Title>
                                                        <r2:Accomplishment>
                                                            <r2:PriorYear>
                                                                <r2:Funding>7.552</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>1. National Industrial Security System (NISS).  Completed Phase I of Business Re-engineering (BPR). Completed Phase I Functional Requirements. Obtained DCMO Pre-Milestone A approval for acquisition of the NISS Material Solution. Initiated Phase II of the Business Re-engineering (BPR) in July 2014 which includes non-material solutions review and implementations.
 
2. Mobile Workforce Applications (MWA).  Complete the functional and technical requirements, and test prototypes.  Leverage DoD Enterprise Mobility capabilities in deploying services to DSS, DoD, and Industry.
 
3. National Industrial Security Program (NISP) Control Access and Information Security System (NCAISS).  Accomplish migration from the IdM to its replacement since Oracle will no longer support the Sun IdM product. This will be a major upgrade to the IdM program. Once existing applications are interfaced with NCAISS and transitioned; production to incorporate other DSS’s applications to the new platform will continue.

4. Migration from Sun-based NCAISS Solution to its replacement, Oracle will no longer support the Sun NCAISS product in 2014.  This will be a major upgrade to the NCAISS program.  Once existing applications are interfaced with NCAISS, transitioned, production to incorporate other DSS' application to the new platform will continue into FY2014.

5. Office of Designated Approving Authority(ODAA) Business Management System (OBMS). The OBMS system was released for initial operating capability (IOC) in July for a 6 month user testing effort. Continue to support operations and sustainment activities which typically are applying security patches and software upgrades plus other system administration functions.</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:PriorYear>
                                                        </r2:Accomplishment>
                                                        <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                            <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                <r2:Funding>3.988</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>1. NISS. Execute acquisition of NISS Project Integrator through Proof of Concept product demonstrations. Conduct prototyping of Facility Clearance
(FCL) Processing module with initial development exception rules. Acquisition will include purchase of infrastructure licensing and hardware. Initial baseline includes Analytics and Reporting capabilities. DCMO approval will permit acquisition for development activities to begin approximately at the end of Q2 of FY2015 with delivery increment one during late Q3 of FY2015.  Maintenance is scheduled to begin the first year.  
2. ISFD. Completed assessment of ISFD application code with automated and manual checks.</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                <r2:Funding>7.929</r2:Funding>
                                                            </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                <r2:Funding>7.929</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>1. NISS. Complete development for the FCL Processing module.  Revalidate requirements begin prototyping incident response and proactive monitoring modules. Requirements workshops to support Mobile Workforce Applications (MWA) will follow the completion of each new module immediately after development of core capabilities.  Analytics and reporting capabilities will expand with each new module.  Begin Development of NISS Increment 1 for consolidation of ISFD and eFCL functions, implement BPR Future state workflows, dashboard, notification and native mobile capabilities.
2. NCCS.  Continued enhancements and version releases and FOC in FY 16.
3. OBMS.  Application enhancements, Security patching, software upgrades and continued sustainment activities. 
4. NCAISS. Continued integration and application sustainment costs, with some software upgrades
5. ISFD.  Execute LDAP (may include NCAISS Interface) and Discoverer (OBIEE) Upgrades.</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                        </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                    </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                                <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>DSS will use a variety of acquisition appropriate vehicles such as Indefinite Delivery, Indefinite Quantity (IDIQ), Blanket Purchase Agreements (BPA), and multiple or single award contracts for the development of new applications, enhancement of other applications, and perform system integration with COTS and GOTS solutions and technology. These efforts will significantly reduce the lead time in contract award process and reduce overhead contract cost, improve technical solutions and deployments, and deliver more effective and efficient automation projects for DSS and the NISP community.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                                                <r2:PerformanceMetrics>N/A</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                                            </r2:R2aExhibit>
                                            <r2:R3Exhibit>
                                                <r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                                                    <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                                        <r2:Name>Product Development</r2:Name>
                                                        <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                                            <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                                <r2:Name>Enterprise Security System</r2:Name>
                                                                <r2:ContractMethod>C</r2:ContractMethod>
                                                                <r2:ContractType>BPA</r2:ContractType>
                                                                <r2:PerformingActivity>SAIC, Northrup Grumman, EDS, Herndon, VA and Columbia, MD</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                                                <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Herndon, VA</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                                                <r2:Cost>
                                                                    <r2:TotalPreviousYears>93.925</r2:TotalPreviousYears>
                                                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                                                        <r2:Amount>7.552</r2:Amount>
                                                                        <r2:AwardDate>2013-11</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                        <r2:Amount>3.988</r2:Amount>
                                                                        <r2:AwardDate>2014-12</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                        <r2:Amount>7.929</r2:Amount>
                                                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                        <r2:Amount>7.929</r2:Amount>
                                                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                                                    <r2:TargetValue>Continuing</r2:TargetValue>
                                                                </r2:Cost>
                                                            </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                        </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                                    </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                                </r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                                            </r2:R3Exhibit>
                                            <r2:R4Exhibit>
                                                <r2:ScheduleProfile>
                                                    <r2:ImageFileName>DSS Part 4 R-Doc 15 Sep 2014.GIF</r2:ImageFileName>
                                                </r2:ScheduleProfile>
                                            </r2:R4Exhibit>
                                            <r2:R4aExhibit>
                                                <r2:SubProjectScheduleList>
                                                    <r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                                                        <r2:Title>Technology Development of ESS Applications</r2:Title>
                                                        <r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                                                            <r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                                                <r2:EventTitle>Production and Deployment Enhancements</r2:EventTitle>
                                                                <r2:Schedule>
                                                                    <r2:Start>
                                                                        <r2:Quarter>1</r2:Quarter>
                                                                        <r2:Year>2014</r2:Year>
                                                                    </r2:Start>
                                                                    <r2:End>
                                                                        <r2:Quarter>4</r2:Quarter>
                                                                        <r2:Year>2020</r2:Year>
                                                                    </r2:End>
                                                                </r2:Schedule>
                                                            </r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                                        </r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                                                    </r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                                                </r2:SubProjectScheduleList>
                                            </r2:R4aExhibit>
                                        </r2:Project>
                                    </r2:ProjectList>
                                </r2:ProgramElement>
                            </r2:R2Exhibit>
                            <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
                                <r2:ProgramElement>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0305327V</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Insider Threat</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                                    <r2:R1LineNumber>225</r2:R1LineNumber>
                                    <r2:BudgetYear>2016</r2:BudgetYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                                    <r2:SubmissionDate>2015-02</r2:SubmissionDate>
                                    <r2:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Security Service</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                                    <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                                    <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                                    <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>7</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                                    <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Operational Systems Development</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                        <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>8.670</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>11.733</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>11.733</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>2.100</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                    </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The DoD Insider Threat program will provide an integrated capability to monitor and audit information for insider threat detection and mitigation. The program will gather, integrate, review, assess, and respond to information derived from CI, security, cyber security, civilian and military personnel management, workplace violence, anti-terrorism risk management, law enforcement, the monitoring of user activity on DoD information networks, and other sources as necessary and appropriate to identify, mitigate, and counter insider threats.  Key elements of the Insider Threat program and security reform efforts are the implementation of Continuous Evaluation (CE) and establishment of the Defense Insider Threat Management and Analysis Center (DITMAC).</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                                    <r2:ChangeSummary>
                                        <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>8.670</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>8.670</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>11.733</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>11.733</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>11.733</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>11.733</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                        <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                                                <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                                    <r2:Title>One -Time Increase</r2:Title>
                                                    <r2:Funding>
                                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>11.733</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>11.733</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    </r2:Funding>
                                                </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                                        </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                                    </r2:ChangeSummary>
                                    <r2:ProjectList>
                                        <r2:Project>
                                            <r2:ProjectNumber>0305327V</r2:ProjectNumber>
                                            <r2:ProjectTitle>Insider Threat</r2:ProjectTitle>
                                            <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                                            <r2:ProjectFunding>
                                                <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                                                <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>8.670</r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>11.733</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>11.733</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearTwo>2.100</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:ProjectFunding>
                                            <r2:R2aExhibit>
                                                <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The DoD Insider Threat program will provide an integrated capability to monitor and audit information for insider threat detection and mitigation. The program will gather, integrate, review, assess, and respond to information derived from CI, security, cybersecurity, civilian and military personnel management, workplace violence, anti-terrorism risk management, law enforcement, the monitoring of user activity on DoD information networks, and other sources as necessary and appropriate to identify, mitigate, and counter insider threats.  Key elements of the Insider Threat program and security reform efforts are the implementation of Continuous Evaluation (CE) and establishment of the Defense Insider Threat Management and Analysis Center (DITMAC).</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                                    <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                        <r2:Title>Insider Threat</r2:Title>
                                                        <r2:Accomplishment>
                                                            <r2:PriorYear>
                                                                <r2:Funding>0.000</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>N/A</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:PriorYear>
                                                        </r2:Accomplishment>
                                                        <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                            <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                <r2:Funding>8.670</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>Funding enhances the capabilities of the Insider Threat program to deter, detect and mitigate threats from exploitation, compromise and or other unauthorized disclosure. Funds development and evaluation of CE tools and systems. Expands CE capacity and Improves access to near real time data feeds from systems capable of providing reports and alerts. Performs proof of concept to identify analytic tools' efficacy and inform future system development. Funding also supports assessment of emerging technologies and development of DITMAC technical requirements.</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                <r2:Funding>11.733</r2:Funding>
                                                            </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                <r2:Funding>11.733</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>Funding will continue development of the DoD Insider Threat program, including the enhancement of CE and DITMAC tools and systems. Research and development efforts will be used to prove the technical capability of using automated record checks in an end-to-end process to achieve CE and influence personnel security reform.  Efforts will include a synthesis of current investigative and adjudicative standards, as well as new methodologies to evaluate the whole-person concept. Furthers DITMAC IT Architecture Engineering Development for systems that will provide ingest, processing, and case management capabilities, relying on feeds from CE and monitoring systems.</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                        </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                    </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                                <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>N/A</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                                                <r2:PerformanceMetrics>TBD</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                                            </r2:R2aExhibit>
                                            <r2:R3Exhibit>
                                                <r2:Remarks>Funding will further enhance the capabilities of the Insider Threat program to deter, detect and mitigate threats through successful implementation of Continuous Evaluation and establishment of the Defense Insider Threat Management and Analysis Center .</r2:Remarks>
                                            </r2:R3Exhibit>
                                            <r2:R4Exhibit>
                                                <r2:ScheduleProfile>
                                                    <r2:ImageFileName>IT FY16.GIF</r2:ImageFileName>
                                                </r2:ScheduleProfile>
                                            </r2:R4Exhibit>
                                            <r2:R4aExhibit>
                                                <r2:SubProjectScheduleList>
                                                    <r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                                                        <r2:Title>Insider Threat</r2:Title>
                                                        <r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                                                            <r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                                                <r2:EventTitle>Insider Threat</r2:EventTitle>
                                                                <r2:Schedule>
                                                                    <r2:Start>
                                                                        <r2:Quarter>1</r2:Quarter>
                                                                        <r2:Year>2015</r2:Year>
                                                                    </r2:Start>
                                                                    <r2:End>
                                                                        <r2:Quarter>4</r2:Quarter>
                                                                        <r2:Year>2017</r2:Year>
                                                                    </r2:End>
                                                                </r2:Schedule>
                                                            </r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                                        </r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                                                    </r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                                                </r2:SubProjectScheduleList>
                                            </r2:R4aExhibit>
                                        </r2:Project>
                                    </r2:ProjectList>
                                </r2:ProgramElement>
                            </r2:R2Exhibit>
                        </r2:R2ExhibitList>
                    </jb:JustificationBook>
                </jb:JustificationBookInfo>
            </jb:JustificationBookInfoList>
        </jb:JustificationBookGroup>
    </jb:JustificationBookGroupList>
</jb:MasterJustificationBook>