<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jb:MasterJustificationBook xmlns:jb="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/jb" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
    <jb:BudgetYear>2015</jb:BudgetYear>
    <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
    <jb:SubmissionDate>2014-03</jb:SubmissionDate>
    <jb:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Security Service</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
    <jb:CoverPage/>
    <jb:ExternalDocuments>
        <jb:UserR1Doc>
            <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit R-1</jb:Title>
            <jb:FileName>25 Feb 2014 R1.pdf</jb:FileName>
        </jb:UserR1Doc>
    </jb:ExternalDocuments>
    <jb:TableOfContents>
        <jb:TocItemList>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 1</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Missile Defense Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 2</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Office of the Secretary of Defense</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 3</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Chemical and Biological Defense Programs</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 4</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Contract Management Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Human Resources Activity</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Information Systems Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Logistics Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Security Cooperation Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Security Service</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Technical Information Center</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Threat Reduction Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>The Joint Staff</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>U.S. Special Operations Command</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Washington Headquarters Service</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Operational Test and Evaluation</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Geospatial Intelligence Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>(see NIP and MIP Justification Books)</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Intelligence Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>(see NIP and MIP Justification Books)</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>National Security Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>(see NIP and MIP Justification Books)</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
        </jb:TocItemList>
    </jb:TableOfContents>
    <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        <jb:GenerateP1m>true</jb:GenerateP1m>
    </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
    <jb:JustificationBookGroupList>
        <jb:JustificationBookGroup>
            <jb:JustificationBookInfoList>
                <jb:JustificationBookInfo>
                    <jb:BookDescription>Defense Security Service</jb:BookDescription>
                    <jb:BookLabel>Volume</jb:BookLabel>
                    <jb:BookNumber>5</jb:BookNumber>
                    <jb:JustificationBook targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
                        <jb:Title>Justification Book</jb:Title>
                        <jb:BudgetYear>2015</jb:BudgetYear>
                        <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
                        <jb:SubmissionDate>2014-03</jb:SubmissionDate>
                        <jb:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Security Service</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
                        <jb:AppropriationCode>0400</jb:AppropriationCode>
                        <jb:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</jb:AppropriationName>
                        <jb:CoverPage/>
                        <jb:ExternalDocuments>
                            <jb:UserR1Doc>
                                <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit R-1</jb:Title>
                                <jb:FileName>25 Feb 2014 R1.pdf</jb:FileName>
                            </jb:UserR1Doc>
                        </jb:ExternalDocuments>
                        <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
                            <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>
                            <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>
                            <jb:GenerateP1>true</jb:GenerateP1>
                            <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>
                            <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>
                            <jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>true</jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>
                        </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
                        <r2:R2ExhibitList xmlns:r2="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/r2" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
                            <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
                                <r2:ProgramElement>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0604130V</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Enterprise Security System</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                                    <r2:R1LineNumber>178</r2:R1LineNumber>
                                    <r2:BudgetYear>2015</r2:BudgetYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                                    <r2:SubmissionDate>2014-03</r2:SubmissionDate>
                                    <r2:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Security Service</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                                    <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                                    <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                                    <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>7</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                                    <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Operational Systems Development</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                        <r2:AllPriorYears>85.766</r2:AllPriorYears>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>8.159</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>7.552</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.988</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.988</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>3.800</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>3.295</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>3.304</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>3.362</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                    </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Defense Security Service (DSS) oversees the protection of the nation's most critical technological and information assets, administers the National Industrial Security Program (NISP) on behalf of the Department of Defense and 27 other Federal agencies.  In this capacity, DSS is responsible for providing security oversight, counterintelligence coverage and support to almost 10,000 cleared companies (comprising over 13,500 + industrial facilities and about 1.2 million cleared contractors), and accreditation of more than 14,000 classified information technology systems in the NISP.  DSS also serves as the functional manager responsible for the execution and maintenance of DoD security training.

The Defense Security Service manages the National Industrial Security Program (NISP) to provide an effective, real-time, security support capability for the Military Departments, DoD Agencies, the NISP, and other Federal Agencies.  In compliance with the Expanded Electronic Government, President’s Management Agenda, and the DoD Enterprise Architecture Framework, NISP is the unified offering of security mission systems which facilitate and automate improved national investigative and adjudicative standards, streamline security processes, and increase DoD community collaboration.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                                    <r2:ChangeSummary>
                                        <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>8.866</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>7.552</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>6.963</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>6.963</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>8.159</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>7.552</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.988</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.988</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>-0.707</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>-2.975</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-2.975</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                        <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                                            <r2:CongressionalGeneralReductions>
                                                <r2:PriorYear>-0.012</r2:PriorYear>
                                            </r2:CongressionalGeneralReductions>
                                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                                                <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                                    <r2:Title>Sequestration Reduction</r2:Title>
                                                    <r2:Funding>
                                                        <r2:PriorYear>-0.695</r2:PriorYear>
                                                    </r2:Funding>
                                                </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                                <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                                    <r2:Title>Other Program Reduction</r2:Title>
                                                    <r2:Funding>
                                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>-2.975</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-2.975</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    </r2:Funding>
                                                </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                                        </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                                    </r2:ChangeSummary>
                                    <r2:ProjectList>
                                        <r2:Project>
                                            <r2:ProjectNumber>000</r2:ProjectNumber>
                                            <r2:ProjectTitle>Enterprise Security System</r2:ProjectTitle>
                                            <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                                            <r2:ProjectFunding>
                                                <r2:AllPriorYears>85.766</r2:AllPriorYears>
                                                <r2:PriorYear>8.159</r2:PriorYear>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>7.552</r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.988</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.988</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearTwo>3.800</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearThree>3.295</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearFour>3.304</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearFive>3.362</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:ProjectFunding>
                                            <r2:R2aExhibit>
                                                <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Defense Security Service manages the Enterprise Security System (ESS) to provide an effective, real-time, security support capability for the Military Departments, DoD Agencies, the NISP, and other Federal Agencies.  In compliance with the Expanded Electronic Government, President’s Management Agenda, and the DoD Enterprise Architecture Framework, ESS is the unified offering of security mission systems which facilitate and automate improved national investigative and adjudicative standards, streamline security processes, and increase DoD community collaboration.

The DSS Mission Information Technology (IT) systems provide critical service to the major DSS mission areas for Industrial Security Oversight and Security Education.  DSS performs this critical function through operation of its mission production systems to include the Industrial Security Facilities Database (ISFD), the DSS Gateway, and the Security Training Education and Professionalization Portal (STEPP).  RDT&amp;E for DSS mission systems primarily includes pre-planned product improvements to the applications, researching and improving assured information sharing to better posture systems and networks against vulnerabilities, ensuring self-defense of systems and networks, and safeguarding data at all stages for the DSS to increase efficiencies by providing web-based systems to manage certification and accreditation activities. These IT systems are as follows:   

Office of Designated Approving Authority (ODAA) Business Management System (OBMS).  The OBMS will automate the approval and certification process of cleared industry’s classified information processing security plans and operations.  This will increase mission efficiency by providing a web-based system to manage certification and accreditation activities, provide improved reporting capabilities to support DSS and industry through improved metrics, accreditation timeliness and accuracy and reduce the number of unaccredited systems by providing automated notifications to DSS and industry.  

Open Source Corporate Management Information System (OSCMIS).  OSCMIS is a Web-based Federal workforce management, workflow, and administrative software suite with more than 50 applications and tools to manage human resource, training, security, acquisition and related functions. The DSS OSCMIS project will deliver direct improvements in the management of information and functional business processes to effectively manage the agency's Manpower, Human Resources, Training, Security, and Continuity of Operation Plan (COOP) functions.

Industrial Security Facilities Database (ISFD).  ISFD is the main DSS mission system that tracks and executes the National Industrial Security Program for DoD and 27 other Federal Executive Agencies of cleared industrial security facilities.  The ISFD provide users with a nationwide perspective on National Industrial Security Program related facilities, as well as, facilities under DSS oversight in the DoD conventional AA&amp;E program. ISFD provides source data for the DoD Joint Personnel Adjudicative System (JPAS) and the Facility Verification Request (FVR) application.

National Industrial Security System (NISS, formerly known as Field Operations System (FOS).  The NISS is slated as the next generation enterprise capability, replacing the Industrial Security Facility Database (ISFD).  Additionally, NISS will provide seamless integration of other DSS systems and applications, such as eFCL, OBMS, DD-254, and Mobile Workforce Applications.  NISS will provide DSS with comprehensive enhanced capability to manage its entire mission portfolio.  NISS will improve information sharing and collaboration, providing timely and accurate data in the hands of field representatives for decision-making.  The system will provide agency-wide metrics to measure and improve agency performance in providing security oversight and the protection of national security.  

The National Contract Classification System (NCCS).  The Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) requires a DD Form 254 be incorporated in each classified contract, and the National Industrial Security Operating Manual (NISPOM)(4-103a) requires a DD 254 be issued by the government with each Invitation for Bid, Request for Proposal, or Request for Quote. The DD Form 254 provides contractor (or a subcontractor) the security requirements and classification guidance necessary to perform on a classified contract. Contract Security Classification Specification required by DoD 5220.22-4, Industrial Security Regulation and the National Industrial Security Program Operating Manual (NISPOM) is to develop a federated system for the oversight and management of providing classified information access and guidance required to perform on classified contracts. The DD 254, an underlying business processes, is critical to ensure access to our Nation’s classified information is properly safeguarded.

Mobile Workforce Applications (MWA).  The global DSS industrial security and oversight mission requires field representatives to audit remote contract facilities and information systems that process classified information. Integrating mobile technologies into daily operations, provides the workforce with access to relevant and timely information, critical in ensuring security oversight decision-making.  

National Industrial Security Program (NISP) Control Access and Information Security System (NCAISS) formerly known as Identity Management (IdM).  NCAISS is mandatory for compliance with Department of Defense (DoD) Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Program Management Office and Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Networks and Information Integration (ASD-NII), Joint Task Force for Global Networks Operations (JTF-GNO) Communications Tasking Order (CTO) 06-02, CTO 07-015, and Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Memo 11-11 (M-11-11), directing accelerated use of PKI across the enterprise.  This initiative is designed to enable multiple DSS business systems to have service-accessibility that is controlled through PKI-compliant single sign-on authentication.  Expanded use of the NCAISS across the DSS enterprise to provide CAC-based authentication for business support applications to support the SIPRNet and JWICS domains, provide enhanced identity and access control analytics. It will also incorporate any remaining DSS operated application into the DSS NCAISS solution.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                                    <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                        <r2:Title>Systems Enhancement</r2:Title>
                                                        <r2:Accomplishment>
                                                            <r2:PriorYear>
                                                                <r2:Funding>8.159</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>1. ODAA Business Management System (OBMS). Achieved Full operational Capability. Deployed Iteration 6 to SS ODAA internal users, which completely modernized the manual DSS security oversight and protection mission by automating the submission and management of System Security Plans (SSP) and Certification and Accreditation (C&amp;A) documentation.  This automation allows DSS to more effectively oversee classified information in the hands of industry, improving mitigation and response to new and emerging threats to our cleared Industrial Base.
 
2. Open Source Corporate Management Information System (OSCMIS).  Achieved full operational capability.
 
3. National Industrial Security System (NISS).  Completed the functional and technical requirements. Began the Business Process Re-Engineering Phase; Continue development of NISS and submission of pre-Milestone A artifacts for DCMO approval.
 
4. NISP Contract Classification System.  Completed the functional and technical requirements, and developed and implemented the system.  
 
5. Mobile Workforce Applications (MWA).  Researched technical capabilities to implement mobile technologies to improve the efficacy of the DSS mission.</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:PriorYear>
                                                        </r2:Accomplishment>
                                                        <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                            <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                <r2:Funding>7.552</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>1. National Industrial Security System (NISS).  Complete functional and technical requirements.  Begin the business re-engineering phase.
 
2. Mobile Workforce Applications (MWA).  Complete the functional and technical requirements, and test prototypes.
 
3. National Industrial Security Program (NISP) Control Access and Information Security System (NCAISS).  Accomplish migration from the IdM to its replacement since Oracle will no longer support the Sun IdM product. This will be a major upgrade to the IdM program. Once existing applications are interfaced with NCAISS and transitioned; production to incorporate other DSS’s applications to the new platform will continue.

4. Migration fron Sun-based NCAISS Solution to its replacement, Oracle will no longer support the Sun NCAISS product in 2014.  This will be a major upgrade to the NCAISS program.  Once existing applications are interfaced with NCAISS, transitioned, production to incorporate other DSS' application to the new platform will continue into FY2014.</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                <r2:Funding>3.988</r2:Funding>
                                                            </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                <r2:Funding>3.988</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>1. NISS.  Revalidation and then development of initial Mobile Web applications and initial Proactive Monitoring.  Development of initial core ISFD.

2. DCMO approval will permit aquisition for development activities to begin in approximately Q2 of FY2015 with delivery increment one during late Q3 of FY2015.  Maintenance is scheduled to begin the first year.</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                        </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                    </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                                <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>DSS will award a new Blanket Purchase Agreement (BPA) in Fiscal Year 2015 for the development of new applications, enhancement of other applications, and perform system integration with COTS and GOTS solutions and technology. These efforts will be issued as BPA task order which will significantly reduce the lead time in contract award process and reduce overhead contract cost, improve technical solutions and deployments, and deliver more effective and efficient automation projects for DSS and the NISP community.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                                                <r2:PerformanceMetrics>N/A</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                                            </r2:R2aExhibit>
                                        </r2:Project>
                                    </r2:ProjectList>
                                </r2:ProgramElement>
                            </r2:R2Exhibit>
                            <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
                                <r2:ProgramElement>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0305327V</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Insider Threat</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                                    <r2:R1LineNumber>229</r2:R1LineNumber>
                                    <r2:BudgetYear>2015</r2:BudgetYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                                    <r2:SubmissionDate>2014-03</r2:SubmissionDate>
                                    <r2:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Security Service</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                                    <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                                    <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                                    <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>7</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                                    <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Operational Systems Development</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>8.670</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>8.670</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                    </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                    <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Defense Security Service (DSS) oversees the protection of the nation's most critical technology and information assets, administers the National Industrial Security Program (NISP) on behalf of the Department of Defense and 27 other Federal agencies.  In this capacity, DSS is responsible for providing security oversight, counterintelligence coverage and support to almost 10,000 cleared companies (comprising over 13,500 + industrial facilities and about 1.2 million cleared contractors), and accreditation of more than 14,000 classified information technology systems in the NISP.  DSS also serves as the functional manager responsible for the execution and maintenance of DoD security training.  

The Defense Security Service manages the National Industrial Security Program (NISP) to provide an effective, real-time, security support capability for the Military Departments, DoD Agencies, the NISP, and other Federal Agencies.  In compliance with the Expanded Electronic Government, President’s Management Agenda, and the DoD Enterprise Architecture Framework, NISP is the unified offering of security mission systems which facilitate and automate improved national investigative and adjudicative standards, streamline security processes, and increase DoD community collaboration.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                                    <r2:ChangeSummary>
                                        <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>8.670</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>8.670</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>8.670</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>8.670</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                        <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                                                <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                                    <r2:Title>New Mandated and Funded Requirement</r2:Title>
                                                    <r2:Funding>
                                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>8.670</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>8.670</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    </r2:Funding>
                                                </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                                        </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                                    </r2:ChangeSummary>
                                    <r2:ProjectList>
                                        <r2:Project>
                                            <r2:ProjectNumber>0305327V</r2:ProjectNumber>
                                            <r2:ProjectTitle>Insider Threat</r2:ProjectTitle>
                                            <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                                            <r2:ProjectFunding>
                                                <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>8.670</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>8.670</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            </r2:ProjectFunding>
                                            <r2:R2aExhibit>
                                                <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>National Industrial Security System (NISS, formerly known as Field Operations System (FOS).  The NISS will be the next generation enterprise capability, replacing the Industrial Security Facility Database (ISFD).  Additionally, NISS will provide seamless integration of other DSS systems and applications, such as eFCL, OBMS, DD-254, and Mobile Workforce Applications.  NISS will provide DSS with a comprehensive enhanced capability to manage its entire mission portfolio.  NISS will improve information sharing and collaboration, providing timely and accurate data for decision-making in the hands of field representatives.  The system will provide agency-wide metrics to measure and improve agency performance in providing security oversight and the protection of national security.  

The National Contract Classification System (NCCS).  The Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) requires that a DD Form 254 be incorporated in each classified contract, and the National Industrial Security Operating Manual (NISPOM)(4-103a) requires that a DD 254 be issued by the government with each Invitation for Bid, Request for Proposal, or Request for Quote. The DD Form 254 provides to the contractor (or a subcontractor) the security requirements and the classification guidance that would be necessary to perform on a classified contract. Contract Security Classification Specification required by DoD 5220.22-4, Industrial Security Regulation and the National Industrial Security Program Operating Manual (NISPOM) is to develop a federated system for the oversight and management of providing classified information access and guidance required for the performance on classified contracts. The DD 254, an underlying business processes, is critical to ensure access to our Nation’s classified information is properly safeguarded.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                                    <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                        <r2:Title>Insider Threat</r2:Title>
                                                        <r2:Accomplishment>
                                                            <r2:PriorYear>
                                                                <r2:Funding>0.000</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>N/A</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:PriorYear>
                                                        </r2:Accomplishment>
                                                        <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                            <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                <r2:Funding>0.000</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>N/A</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                <r2:Funding>8.670</r2:Funding>
                                                            </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                <r2:Funding>8.670</r2:Funding>
                                                                <r2:Text>The continued development of the NISS and NCCS will further enhance the capabilities of the  Insider Threat program to deter, detect and mitigate in the safeguarding of classified informtion in the hands of Industry from exploitation, compromise and or other unauthorized disclosure.</r2:Text>
                                                            </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                        </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                    </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                                <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>N/A</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                                                <r2:PerformanceMetrics>TBD</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                                            </r2:R2aExhibit>
                                        </r2:Project>
                                    </r2:ProjectList>
                                </r2:ProgramElement>
                            </r2:R2Exhibit>
                        </r2:R2ExhibitList>
                    </jb:JustificationBook>
                </jb:JustificationBookInfo>
            </jb:JustificationBookInfoList>
        </jb:JustificationBookGroup>
    </jb:JustificationBookGroupList>
</jb:MasterJustificationBook>