<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jb:JustificationBook xmlns:jb="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/jb" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
    <jb:Title>Justification Book</jb:Title>
    <jb:BudgetYear>2014</jb:BudgetYear>
    <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
    <jb:SubmissionDate>2013-04</jb:SubmissionDate>
    <jb:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Technical Information Center</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
    <jb:AppropriationCode>0400</jb:AppropriationCode>
    <jb:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</jb:AppropriationName>
    <jb:CoverPage/>
    <jb:ExternalDocuments>
        <jb:UserR1Doc>
            <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit R-1</jb:Title>
            <jb:FileName>R 1 Exhibit PB 2014 Page 160-rotated.pdf</jb:FileName>
        </jb:UserR1Doc>
    </jb:ExternalDocuments>
    <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        <jb:ForceEvenPages>true</jb:ForceEvenPages>
        <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>
        <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>
        <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>
        <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>
    </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
    <r2:R2ExhibitList xmlns:r2="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/r2" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
        <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElement>
                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0605801KA</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Defense Technical Information Center</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                <r2:R1LineItemNumber>160</r2:R1LineItemNumber>
                <r2:BudgetYear>2014</r2:BudgetYear>
                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                <r2:SubmissionDate>2013-04</r2:SubmissionDate>
                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Technical Information Center</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>6</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>RDT&amp;E Management Support</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                    <r2:AllPriorYears>57.790</r2:AllPriorYears>
                    <r2:PriorYear>56.269</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>55.454</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>56.024</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>56.024</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>55.577</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>54.276</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>54.876</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>56.175</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Defense Technical Information Center’s (DTIC) mission is to provide essential, technical research, development, test and evaluation (RDT&amp;E) information products in a rapid, accurate and trusted manner to support DoD customers' needs.  DTIC, a DoD field activity, along with its Information Analysis Centers (IACs), is the DoD designated source for DoD-funded scientific, technical, engineering, and business-related information.

With a modest funding level, DTIC serves as an efficiency enabler by developing and implementing products and services supporting collaboration and communication within the Department’s Scientific and Technical (S&amp;T) community.  Leaning on mature, low-risk, and commercially available technologies, DTIC delivers secure and effective products to its customers.  In this manner, DTIC’s collaborative products are essential to linking DoD’s dispersed laboratories and Federally Funded Research and Development Centers (FFRDCs) together.  In today’s fiscal environment, the Department cannot afford to conduct business as usual.  DTIC’s existing and future suite of products provide the potential for enabling DoD customers to develop answers to complex problems--for less money--by providing the opportunity to elimination of unnecessary research efforts and reducing the traditional reliance on conferences, training and travel as a means of connecting with professional colleagues.

Building on progress from previous investments, the FY 2014 budget request supports four major thrust areas within DTIC:  1) modernize collaborative tools and innovative applications, 2) enhance the effectiveness of DTIC’s library collection and content, 3) continued restructuring of the Information Analysis Center (IAC) Program, and 4) recast the organization’s workforce.   In this budget program, DTIC resources are focused on the following efforts:

1.  DTIC is committed to accelerating the flow and dissemination of information, delivering professional and organizational networking tools for use within DoD, and between business partners in industry and academia.  Since the 2008 advent of DoDTechipedia, DTIC’s collaborative tools enable rapid customer response to current and emerging threats across the defense enterprise, and help identify solutions to complex technology challenges.  Once fully implemented, these tools will offer users visualization, analysis, and data mining functionality, all in a secure environment.  These evolving DTIC capabilities are essential to the S&amp;T and RDT&amp;E communities, and will play a critical role in finding better, faster, and cheaper solutions.  A number of key tools are highlighted below:    

- A recent venture for DTIC is the DoD Research and Engineering (R&amp;E) Portal (DoDTechSpace), a secure professional networking tool for the DoD enterprise.  The tool offers a navigator through which DTIC’s customers can collaborate, share, find, and post information.  A secure application, it connects the defense research and engineering community, DoD laboratories, warfighters, and other DoD agencies, while providing current and next generation employees and researchers with advanced Web 2.0 tools.  A related tool, DoDTechipedia, one of DoD’s first scientific and technical wikis, was launched by DTIC in 2008.  The tool provides an encyclopedia-like resource of science and technology information for DoD and federal government employees.

- The Defense Innovation Marketplace (or “the Marketplace”) was launched in 2011 as an online public and non-public/limited resource for DoD and industry to exchange information.  Creation of this site was a direct result of the Department’s “Better Buying Power” initiative, which calls for the DoD to deliver better value to the taxpayer and warfighter by improving the way it was doing business.  The Marketplace includes a collaborative tool that accepts industry Independent Research &amp; Development (IR&amp;D) project summaries to improve DoD awareness of current industry efforts and identify technology gaps.  

2.  The transformation of DTIC from a static repository of information to an agile delivery agent of dynamic content; i.e., real-time, user supplied, collaborative information.  This effort seeks to enhance DTIC’s authoritative data.  Recent actions involve improving and expanding both the access and content available on the SIPRNET.  Improving content and the quality of information directly supports better decision-making envisioned in the Department’s Better Buying Power (BBP) initiative.  DTIC is active in working to federate access to Scientific and Technical Information (STI) content from government, industry, and academic sources. 

3.  The Information Analysis Center (IAC) Program Office at DTIC provides core funding, management and oversight of the IACs. The IACs are chartered by DoD to collect, analyze, and disseminate worldwide scientific and technical information in specialized fields.  At present, the IAC program is undergoing a multi-year restructuring from ten IACs to three, in order to reduce customer costs and reflect new DoD technical interest areas.  The new structure will focus on three technology groupings, to include Cyber Security and Information Systems, Homeland Defense and Security, and Defense Systems.  In concert with the Department’s Better Buying Power initiative, new multi-award contracts are being put into place, improving competition, small-business presence, and reducing government costs.  Once complete, the restructured IAC Program will be in an even better position to improve affordability, productivity, and standardization within defense acquisition programs. 

4.  DTIC is in the midst of a multi-year process of transforming its workforce.  The ongoing effort is seeking, through attrition, to shift staff expertise and skill sets from an emphasis on traditional librarian services to one that is more technology-savvy.  Through this new staffing model, the organization is hiring talent to take advantage of available technologies to collect, organize, model, analyze, and share information faster and more cheaply.  Concurrently, DTIC is bolstering program management expertise to optimize business processes and operations.  In this vein, DTIC is actively building an expanding cadre of experts in Information Technology, Information Sciences and Architecture, and Acquisition.

This Program Element (PE) supports DTIC mission operations, to include four core integrated functions: 
•	Collaboration
•	Research Support &amp; Library Repository 
•	Web Services &amp; Hosting
•	Information Analysis Centers (IACs) 

These functions are addressed in the R-2A sections of this document.

Mission funding provides for salaries and benefits of government civilian personnel assigned to DTIC; training, professional development, and travel for DTIC personnel; support agreements for Defense Logistics Agency (DLA) facility-related services; Defense Finance and Accounting Service (DFAS) financial activities and Human Resource (HR) services; Defense Information Services Agency (DISA) communications support; annual maintenance and licensing requirements; supplies, equipment, Hardware/Software; and support contracts for Information Technology services, Defense Agencies Initiative (DAI) system integration, and Chief Financial Officer (CFO) Act compliance efforts. 

In addition, this PE provides funding in support of the Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) and Small Business Technology Transfer (STTR) programs, in accordance with Public Law 111-251 (Small Business Reauthorization Act) and Small Business Technology Transfer Program Reauthorization Act. Within the PE, an annual set-aside contribution totaling approximately $400,000 is provided to the DoD's Commercialization Pilot Program, as directed by the Department's Office of Small Business Programs (OSBP).
</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>56.269</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>55.454</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>54.232</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>54.232</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>56.269</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>55.454</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>56.024</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>56.024</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>1.792</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>1.792</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>Program Changes</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>1.868</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>1.868</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>Other Program Changes</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.074</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.074</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>Economic Adjustments</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>-0.150</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-0.150</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                    </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                    <r2:SummaryExplanation>Specific changes to the FY 2014 program (net change of $1.792 Million from the previous PB) are outlined below:

Program Changes ($1.868 Million):  This program change supports the Department’s Better Buying Power (BBP) initiative through the introduction of the Defense Innovation Marketplace.  This application is designed to enhance two-way communications between the Department and the Industrial base, improving DoD awareness of current efforts and help identify gaps within the Acquisition community.  This application will apply advanced search capabilities, Business Intelligence and visualization tools to aid understanding and analysis among user communities.  Program funding provides for development efforts and licensing requirements.

Other Program Changes ($0.074 Million):  Funding increase reflects the Department’s realignment of funds from the Defense Information Systems Agency (DISA) to customer organizations for the increase in DISN Subscription Services (DSS) rates and reimbursable programs.

Economic Adjustments (-$0.150 Million):  Funding reduction reflects the Department’s revised economic assumptions related to civilian personnel pay raise rates.
</r2:SummaryExplanation>
                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:ProjectList>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Defense Technical Information Center</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>48.499</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>49.216</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>48.401</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>48.971</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>48.971</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>48.524</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>47.223</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>47.823</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>49.122</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>DTIC leads the DoD scientific and technical information (STINFO) program, and is responsible for developing, coordinating and enabling a strong STINFO program for the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering (ASD(R&amp;E)) and the DoD Scientific &amp; Technical (S&amp;T) enterprise.  In this role, DTIC sets policy for scientific and technical information (STI) exchanges for the research and engineering community.  DTIC’s aim is to maximize the availability and use of technical information and products resulting from Defense-funded technical activities while ensuring restrictions that national security, export control, and intellectual property rights are safeguarded.

It is DoD policy to establish and maintain a coordinated and comprehensive program to document the results and outcome of DoD-sponsored and performed research and engineering (R&amp;E) and studies, and to provide access to those efforts in an effective manner, in order to make efficient use of the investment that taxpayers have previously made in research and engineering.  In the 21st Century, supporting the S&amp;T and RDT&amp;E communities requires that DTIC integrate, more than ever, our collections with databases, information links, utilizing the latest information technology, whether in-house or outside of our Department, regardless of the source. DTIC, as the central source for DoD-funded current and completed research, brings efficiencies to the Department as users can gather information from many sources with one search.  DTIC’s customers, from the individual researcher to the acquisition professional, can quickly fuse information into the most complete picture needed in a matter of minutes to hours; not days to months. DTIC accomplishes its mission to provide critical scientific, technical and related program information by performing the activities described in the three core integrated functions below:

- COLLABORATION.  DTIC provides the technology tools to promote collaboration, integration and innovation, in real time, throughout the DoD enterprise and with its partners.  DoD looks to DTIC to forge the linkages connecting diverse communities of interest to the critical research data repository maintained within DTIC.  By sharing knowledge easily and securely, the DoD S&amp;T community (to include the service laboratories, Combatant Commands (COCOMs), Federally Funded Research and Development Centers (FFRDCs), and industry/academia) can accelerate innovation in technologies that benefits the warfighter.  To avoid duplication of efforts and increase information sharing, DTIC partners with DoD and other federal government organizations to provide access to information resources and tools.

- RESEARCH SUPPORT AND LIBRARY REPOSITORY.  DTIC provides the STI community the authoritative source of S&amp;T information.  DTIC’s repository contains over 4 Million records, to include Strategic Planning, budget, S&amp;T current work, work-in-progress, and completed work (such as Technical Reports and studies).  R&amp;D investments and the resulting outcomes are also available in the collection.  DTIC is charged by the Department to collect, categorize, and preserve this critical S&amp;T information.  In addition, DTIC ensures the proper protection of the material, based on its dissemination limitations (public, DoD and government only, etc.).  The repository facilitates DoD in reusing research in which it already invested its money--leveraging prior research to maximize the impact of R&amp;D dollars.

- WEB SERVICES AND SITE HOSTING.  DTIC develops customized information solutions and hosts applications that support DoD Components.  At present, DTIC hosts more than 70 public, limited and classified web-based information systems.  The jointly developed applications improve acquisition decision-making, increase collaborative research and development efforts, facilitate business processes, and provide improved support for the warfighter.  This budget request directly supports applications operated by DTIC on behalf of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Research &amp; Engineering (ASD(R&amp;E)).  Other DoD components are supported on a cost reimbursable basis; key customers include:  Joint Chief of Staff (JCS), Office of the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) (OUSD(C)), and the Combatant Commands.  Notable web-hosting customers include the Federal Voter Assistance Program (FVAP), providing voter access to U.S. military and civilians around the world; the OSD-Comptroller’s R-2 application, a Department-wide effort to standardize appropriated budget information for submission to Congress; and Science Mathematics and Research for Transformation (SMART) Scholarship for Service Program, providing scholarships to colleges and universities in an effort to recruit, develop and retain the next generation of personnel in the science, mathematics and research fields for DoD.
</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Defense Technical Information Center</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>49.216</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>- Implemented additional features and content to the Defense Innovation Marketplace; initiated first annual data call to industry on Independent Research and Development (IR&amp;D) investments; placed data online for DoD Program Managers and Program Executive Offices to use.
- Developed and launched the DoD Research and Engineering (R&amp;E) Portal (DoDTechSpace) pilot – a gateway to all DTIC online products and services; provides access to and capability for registered users to update a central profile.
- Initiated first annual data call for the Unified R&amp;E Database (URED), a continuous reporting tool that captures project purpose and status for thousands of active DoD R&amp;E; created an online database for use by OSD, Program Managers, scientists and engineers.
- Designed a new database combining DTIC Technical Reports and information from the Information Analysis Center (IAC) generated Total Electronic Migration Systems (TEMS). 
- Continued to improve user registration tools, enhancing ease of access for DoD staff, federal government employees and their contractors.
- Updated DoD Scientific and Technical Information Program (STIP) Instructions in collaboration with DoD agencies and services; provided advice and guidance to DoD activities on policy interpretation and implementation.
- Increased outreach to Combatant Commands, providing research of access controlled and classified resources and offering customized training and reference support for military exercises.
- Continued to implement business intelligence tools for budget analysis for OSD Comptroller.
- Expanded outreach to new customer segments within ASD(R&amp;E), DoD Laboratories, acquisition functions, industry, and the broader RDT&amp;E community.
- Coordinated access to DoD S&amp;T information and collaborative tools for DTIC registered users with approved mobile devices.
- Prepared for the implementation of the new government-wide Controlled Unclassified Information (CUI) markings.
- Continued implementation and integration of Defense Agencies Initiative (DAI) system upgrades, functional enhancements, software updates, and business process changes throughout both the DTIC enterprise and partnering organizations.
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>48.401</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>- Continue critical enhancements on the DoD Research and Engineering (R&amp;E) Portal (DoDTechSpace) gateway, which will provide central, federated search capabilities across all DTIC online products and services including (but not limited to) Technical Reports, DoDTechipedia, URED, and IR&amp;D. 
-- This developmental effort will leverage available technology as a means to merge information resources from multiple sources, connecting disparate databases to create useful information products for DTIC registered users. 
-- When complete, these efforts will result in the synthesis and visualization of key technical information for DTIC stakeholders, offering a complete, interconnected picture of relevant technical reports, budgetary and program information, Laboratory and industry subject matter experts, Science &amp; Technology Integrated Priority Lists (STIPLs), all tied together with agile open search and collaboration capabilities.
- Implement additional features and content to the Defense Innovation Marketplace by adding new sources of data, such as small business information, to enable DoD to examine the state of industry R&amp;D in one federated search. 
-- Create search interfaces for industry metrics and program offices to learn about industry R&amp;D for planning for where DoD should target expenditures. 
-- Expand annual data call to industry on IR&amp;D investments and place data online for use by DoD Program Managers and Program Executive Offices.
-- Establish web-based information exchanges for 2 (or more) of 14 Communities of Interest (COIs)
- Expand the Unified R&amp;E Database (URED) as a continuous data call collection tool; enhance the online database for use by OSD, Program Managers, scientists and engineers.
- Continue the multi-year effort to restructure the DTIC workforce to meet technical challenges.
- Continue to expand the capabilities of the reporting and analysis visualization tool for the unclassified/limited user community and implement a reporting and analysis visualization tool for the classified user community.
- Update DoD Scientific and Technical Information Program (STIP) Instructions in collaboration with DoD agencies and Services; provide advice and guidance to DoD activities on policy interpretation and implementation.
- Continue outreach to Combatant Commands, providing research of access controlled and classified resources and offering customized training and reference support for military exercises.
- Continue to implement Business Intelligence tools for budget analysis for OSD Comptroller.
- Begin a pilot program to implement the new government-wide Controlled Unclassified Information (CUI) markings, which will impact the creation, handling, and storage of all unclassified sensitive information.
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>48.971</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>48.971</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>- Enrich the DoD R&amp;E Portal (DoDTechSpace) with the integration of all DoD S&amp;T resources.
-- Expand and enhance search and analytic capabilities.
- Expand Virtual Industry Day for COIs through Defense Innovation Marketplace, supporting Better Buying Power initiatives.
-- Field analysis and visualization tools to increase understanding of Independent Research and Development (IR&amp;D) data.
-- Expand information exchange features to enhance the “Marketplace” as an alternative to DoD and industry face-to-face technical exchange meetings, reducing travel costs while improving outcomes.
- Combine key technical information from multiple sources for use and analysis.
- Create full-text search with field-based queries to assist user navigation of information.
- Feature visualization and geo-location data presentations.
- Exploit opportunities to develop emerging semantic search technologies.
- Increase access and improve security for industry and federal communities through smart card user identification; e.g., the PIV (Personal Identity Verification) card.
- Design an Information Architecture and governance model using modern techniques; map relationships, identify information gaps, provide most relevant, complete and actionable information.
- Enhance virtualization of DTIC information technology (IT) systems in compliance with the Federal Data Center Consolidation Initiative (FDCCI), and prepare for the cloud.
- Host limited access peer-reviewed journals for DoD labs supporting real-time discovery of technical breakthroughs.
- Expand work with COCOMs and DoD Laboratories to build communities of interest (COI).
- Merge best features of commercial products to provide powerful tools with an intuitive interface.
- Push vendor product enhancements to DoD users.
- Provide SIPRNET users access to unclassified collections.
- Increase dynamic repository of user maintained information (Wikis, Blogs, COIs).
- Identify and evaluate tools to improve access to S&amp;T information for Combatant Commands.
- Extend use of XML for data submission.
- Expand scope of Unified Research &amp; Engineering tool to reduce independent data calls
- Continued implementation and integration of Defense Agencies Initiative (DAI) system upgrades, functional enhancements, software updates, and business process changes throughout both the DTIC enterprise and partnering organizations.
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>Collaboration
1) New Registered Users
2) Total Active Users

Research Support and Library Repository
1) Total Scientific and Technical Information (STI) Collected (Technical Reports (TRs), Unified R&amp;E Database (URED), Independent Research and Development (IR&amp;D), and TEMS (Total Electronic Migration System)
2) Total STI Disseminated (TRs, Digitization Requests, IR&amp;D Usage, National Defense Industrial Association (NDIA), TEMS downloads, and IAC Web Inquiries)
3) Total Records in four databases (TR, URED, IR&amp;D, and TEMS)

Web Services and Site Hosting
1) Web Page Requests and Total Requests for each sponsored site
2) Total Web Page Requests by customer hosted sites
</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>002</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Information Analysis Centers</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>9.291</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>7.053</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>7.053</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.053</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.053</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>7.053</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>7.053</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>7.053</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>7.053</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>DoD Information Analysis Centers (IACs) serve as a vital resource in providing timely, relevant information directly to users when and where it is needed. IACs serve as a bridge between the Warfighter and the Acquisition/Research community, providing essential technical analysis and data support to a diverse customer base, to include the Combatant Commands (COCOMs), the Office of the Secretary of Defense, Defense Agencies, and the Military Services. IACs actively partner and collaborate with Defense Research &amp; Engineering focus groups and communities of interest in areas of specialized fields or specific technologies. IACs, established under DoD Instruction 3200.14, create and maintain comprehensive knowledge analysis centers that include historical, technical, scientific, and other data and information collected worldwide. They are staffed with scientists, engineers and information specialists to provide research and analysis to customers with diverse, complex and challenging requirements. IAC operations directly support the warfighter, and play an ongoing and critical role in solving key COCOM operational issues such as cyber security, improvised explosive device (IED) defeat and helicopter survivability. The IAC Program Management Office at DTIC performs contract acquisition, management, and operational support for IAC contract operations and the technical information that is generated as a result of research and studies conducted. In a time of shrinking budgets and increasing responsibility, IACs are a valuable resource for accessing Scientific and Technical Information culled from efforts to solve new and historic challenges.  Direct IAC customer support activities, such as Technical Area Task (TAT) order processing, Basic Center Operations (BCO) support, Defense Finance and Accounting Service (DFAS) activities, contracting/acquisition related activities, etc., are funded in part through partnerships with the Defense Research &amp; Engineering community and the annual collection of customer reimbursements for shared direct costs, in accordance with the IAC Reimbursable Review Board (IRRB) recommendations, with OSD-COMPT and Office of General Counsel concurrence. This represents the maximum cost-sharing with IAC customers allowable, per guidance from the OSD Office of General Counsel. Annual IAC efforts and accomplishments are dependent on the level of participation and collaboration by the R&amp;E community at large.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Information Analysis Centers</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>7.053</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>- Contributed to OASD(R&amp;E)’s four imperatives, while enhancing IAC partnership with OASD(R&amp;E) on areas of common interest through participation in focus groups, communities of interest, and other Reliance 21 initiatives.
- Provided administrative oversight and basic core contract operations for DoD IACs to collect, analyze, synthesize and disseminate worldwide Scientific and Technical Information (STI) in support of DoD's critical technologies and the warfighter.
- Refined business processes, improving efficiency within the Program and maximizing value-per-dollar for our customers by providing innovative approaches, streamlined processes and alignment with new policies.
- Established multiple award contract processes that the Deputy Director for Defense Procurement and Acquisition Policy called “best practices for the Department.”
- Provided in-depth analysis services and created STI products, in response to anticipated and real-time needs of the operational and technical community.
- Responded to technical inquiries and provided in-depth S&amp;T analysis; created and provided STI results via IAC websites; captured STI products from new/on-going analysis tasks; and supported the exchange of information among members of the operational and technical communities.
- For example, authored handbook on the impact of “green” technology on system reliability, leveraging decades of reliability expertise to identify best practices in maximizing effectiveness and minimizing risk of implementing renewable energy technologies.
- Continued executing acquisition strategy for Basic Center Operations (BCO) contracts for the entire scope of the IAC Program, as well as new scope areas of emerging importance to the Department.
- Awarded Cyber Security and Information Systems IAC contract.
- Gained PEO approval of acquisition strategy, and released draft Request for Proposals, for Homeland Defense Technical Area Task (TAT) Indefinite Delivery Indefinite Quantity (IDIQ).
- Managed and supported TATs ordered by the DoD and non-DoD customers, including all 9 Combatant Commands; provided program strategy and ensured alignment with Department goals/direction.
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>7.053</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>- Provide administrative oversight and basic core contract operations for DoD IACs to collect, analyze, synthesize and disseminate worldwide Scientific and Technical Information (STI) in support of DoD's critical technologies and the warfighter.
- Respond to technical inquiries and provide in-depth S&amp;T analysis; create and provide STI results via IAC websites; capture STI products from new/on-going analysis tasks; and support the exchange of information among members of the operational and technical communities.
- Continue executing acquisition strategy for BCO contracts for the IAC Program.
- Award small business set-aside contract for Homeland Defense and Security BCO.
- Continue transition to new IAC Program contract structure utilizing Indefinite Delivery Indefinite Quantity (IDIQ) Multiple Award contracts.
- Manage and support Technical Area Tasks (TATs) ordered by the DoD and non-DoD customers; provide program strategy and ensure alignment with Department goals/direction.
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>7.053</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>7.053</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>- Support the DTIC mission to provide technical information to DoD
- Provide administrative oversight and basic core contract operations for DoD IACs to collect, analyze, synthesize and disseminate worldwide Scientific and Technical Information (STI) in support of DoD's critical technologies and the warfighter.
- Respond to technical inquiries and provide in-depth S&amp;T analysis; create and provide STI results via IAC websites; capture STI products from new/on-going analysis tasks; and support the exchange of information among members of the operational and technical communities.
- Complete IAC Program restructuring to achieve the following objectives:
-- Create and sustain a focus on the Better Buying Power initiatives to improve affordability, productivity, and standardization within defense acquisition programs.
-- Expand scope to cover areas of emerging importance for the DoD (including Energetics, Autonomous Systems, Biometrics, Alternative Energy, and medical research).
-- Increase participation of small business in supporting exchanges of technical and operational information across the DoD.
-- Expand the industrial base – from single vendors to multiple vendors in each technical focus area, lowering cost and improving quality through enhanced competition.
- Award small business set-aside contract for Defense Systems Basic Center Operations (BCO), as well as multiple award IDIQ contracts for Homeland Defense and Security Technical Area Tasks (TATs) and Defense Systems TATs.
- Manage and support TATs ordered by the DoD and non-DoD customers; provide program strategy and ensure alignment with Department goals/direction.
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>Number of:
-IAC web inquiries
-IAC technical inquiries
-STI documents added to IAC collection
-STI documents generated by Technical Area Task (TAT) activities
-Training or meeting events, and number of attendees

Amount of funding:
-Provided by external customer requesting IAC technical analysis
-Provided by external customers purchasing IAC information products

Customer satisfaction regarding:
-IAC products and technical inquiry support
-IAC TATs and training Documents uploaded to DTIC’s online repository
</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                </r2:ProjectList>
            </r2:ProgramElement>
        </r2:R2Exhibit>
    </r2:R2ExhibitList>
</jb:JustificationBook>