<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jb:JustificationBook xmlns:jb="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/jb" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
    <jb:Title>Justification Book</jb:Title>
    <jb:BudgetYear>2014</jb:BudgetYear>
    <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
    <jb:SubmissionDate>2013-04</jb:SubmissionDate>
    <jb:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Security Service</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
    <jb:AppropriationCode>0400</jb:AppropriationCode>
    <jb:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</jb:AppropriationName>
    <jb:CoverPage/>
    <jb:ExternalDocuments>
        <jb:SupplementalDocList>
            <jb:SupplementalDoc>
                <jb:Title>R-1</jb:Title>
                <jb:FileName>R-1 22 mar 2013.pdf</jb:FileName>
            </jb:SupplementalDoc>
        </jb:SupplementalDocList>
    </jb:ExternalDocuments>
    <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        <jb:ForceEvenPages>true</jb:ForceEvenPages>
        <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>
        <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>
        <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>
        <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>
    </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
    <r2:R2ExhibitList xmlns:r2="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/r2" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
        <r2:R2Exhibit monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElement>
                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0604130V</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Enterprise Security System </r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                <r2:R1LineItemNumber>182</r2:R1LineItemNumber>
                <r2:BudgetYear>2014</r2:BudgetYear>
                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                <r2:SubmissionDate>2013-04</r2:SubmissionDate>
                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Security Service</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>7</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Operational Systems Development</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                    <r2:AllPriorYears>79.560</r2:AllPriorYears>
                    <r2:PriorYear>6.206</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>8.866</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.552</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.552</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>6.963</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>6.897</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>6.405</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>6.501</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Defense Security Service (DSS) oversees the protection of the nation's most critical technological and information assets, administers the National Industrial Security Program (NISP) on behalf of the Department of Defense and 25 other Federal agencies.  In this capacity, DSS is responsible for providing security oversight, counterintelligence coverage and support to almost 10,000 cleared companies (comprising over 13,500 + industrial facilities and about 1.2 million cleared contractors), and accreditation of more than 14,000 classified information technology systems in the NISP.  DSS also serves as the functional manager responsible for the execution and maintenance of DoD security training.  In support of this mission, DSS provides security education, training, and professionalization services for DoD and industry under the NISP.

The Defense Security Service manages the Enterprise Security System (ESS) to provide an effective, real-time, security support capability for the Military Departments, DoD Agencies, the NISP, and other Federal Agencies.  In compliance with the Expanded Electronic Government, President’s Management Agenda, and the DoD Enterprise Architecture Framework, ESS is the unified offering of security mission systems which facilitate and automate improved national investigative and adjudicative standards, streamline security processes, and increase DoD community collaboration.
</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>6.206</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>8.866</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>6.523</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>6.523</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                        <r2:PriorYear>6.206</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>8.866</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.552</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.552</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>1.029</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>1.029</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                <r2:Title>One-Time Increase</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Funding>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>1.029</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>1.029</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:Funding>
                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                    </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:ProjectList>
                    <r2:Project>
                        <r2:ProjectNumber>000</r2:ProjectNumber>
                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Enterprise Security System</r2:ProjectTitle>
                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>79.560</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>6.206</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>8.866</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.552</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.552</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>6.963</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>6.897</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>6.405</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>6.501</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Defense Security Service (DSS) oversees the protection of the nation's most critical technological and information assets, administers the National Industrial Security Program (NISP) on behalf of the Department of Defense and 25 other Federal agencies.  In this capacity, DSS is responsible for providing security oversight, counterintelligence coverage and support to almost 10,000 cleared companies (comprising over 13,500 + industrial facilities and about 1.2 million cleared contractors), and accreditation of more than 14,000 classified information technology systems in the NISP.  DSS also serves as the functional manager responsible for the execution and maintenance of DoD security training.  In support of this mission, DSS provides security education, training, and professionalization services for DoD and industry under the NISP.

The Defense Security Service manages the Enterprise Security System (ESS) to provide an effective, real-time, security support capability for the Military Departments, DoD Agencies, the NISP, and other Federal Agencies.  In compliance with the Expanded Electronic Government, President’s Management Agenda, and the DoD Enterprise Architecture Framework, ESS is the unified offering of security mission systems which facilitate and automate improved national investigative and adjudicative standards, streamline security processes, and increase DoD community collaboration.

The DSS Mission Information Technology (IT) systems provide service critical to the major DSS mission areas for Industrial Security Oversight and Security Education.  DSS performs this critical function through operation of its production mission systems to include the Industrial Security Facilities Database (ISFD), the DSS Gateway, and the Security Training Education and Professionalization Portal (STEPP).  RDT&amp;E for DSS mission systems primarily includes pre-planned product improvements to the applications, researching and improving assured information sharing, better posturing systems and networks against vulnerabilities, ensuring self-defense of systems and networks, and safeguarding data at all stages which are necessary for the DSS to increase efficiencies by providing web-based systems to manage certification and accreditation activities. These IT systems are as follows:   

Office of Designated Approving Authority (ODAA) Business Management System (OBMS).  The OBMS will automate the approval and certification process of cleared industry’s classified information processing security plans and operations.  This will increase mission efficiency by providing a web-based system to manage certification and accreditation activities, provide improved reporting capabilities to support DSS and industry with better metrics, improve the accreditation timeliness and accuracy and reduce the number of unaccredited systems by providing automated notifications to DSS and industry.  

Open Source Corporate Management Information System (OSCMIS).  OSCMIS is a Web-based Federal workforce management, workflow, and administrative software suite with more than 50 applications and tools to manage human resource, training, security, acquisition and related functions. The DSS OSCMIS project will deliver direct improvements to information management and functional business processes to effectively manage the agency's Manpower, Human Resources, Training, Security, and Continuity of Operation Plan (COOP) functions.

Industrial Security Facilities Database (ISFD).  ISFD is the main DSS mission system that tracks and executes the National Industrial Security Program for DoD and 24 other Federal Executive Agencies of cleared industrial security facilities.  The ISFD provide users with a nationwide perspective on National Industrial Security Program related facilities, as well as facilities under DSS oversight in the DoD conventional AA&amp;E program. ISFD data also provides source data for the DoD Joint Personnel Adjudicative System (JPAS) and the Facility Verification Request (FVR) application.

Field Operations System (FOS).  The FOS will be the next generation enterprise capability, replacing the Industrial Security Facility Database (ISFD).  Additionally, FOS will provide seamless integration of other DSS systems and applications, such as eFCL, OBMS, DD-254, and Mobile Workforce Applications.  FOS will provide DSS with a comprehensive enhanced capability to manage its entire mission portfolio.  FOS will improve information sharing and collaboration, providing timely and accurate data for decision-making in the hands of field representatives.  The system will provide agency-wide metrics to measure and improve agency performance in providing security oversight and the protection of national security.  The system will be developed in an iterative fashion in accordance with the Business Transformation Agency (BTA) Business Capability Lifecycle (BCL).

DD 254.  The Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) requires that a DD Form 254 be incorporated in each classified contract, and the National Industrial Security Operating Manual (NISPOM)(4-103a) requires that a DD 254 be issued by the government with each Invitation for Bid, Request for Proposal, or Request for Quote. The DD Form 254 provides to the contractor (or a subcontractor) the security requirements and the classification guidance that would be necessary to perform on a classified contract. Contract Security Classification Specification required by DoD 5220.22-4, Industrial Security Regulation and the National Industrial Security Program Operating Manual (NISPOM) is to develop a federated system for the oversight and management of providing classified information access and guidance required for the performance on classified contracts. The DD 254, an underlying business processes, is critical to ensure access to our Nation’s classified information is properly safeguarded.

Mobile Workforce Applications (MWA).  The global DSS industrial security and oversight mission requires field representatives to audit remote contract facilities and information systems that process classified information. By incorporating mobile technologies into daily operations, the workforce has access to relevant and timely information, critical in ensuring security oversight decision-making.  

National Industrial Security Program (NISP) Control Access and Information Security System (NCAISS) formerly known as Identity Management (IdM).  NCAISS is required for compliance with Department of Defense (DoD) Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Program Management Office and Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Networks and Information Integration (ASD-NII), Joint Task Force for Global Networks Operations (JTF-GNO) Communications Tasking Order (CTO) 06-02, CTO 07-015, and Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Memo 11-11 (M-11-11), directing accelerated use of PKI across the enterprise.  This initiative is designed to enable multiple DSS business systems to have service-accessibility that is controlled through PKI-compliant single sign-on authentication.  Expand use of the IdM Solution across the DSS enterprise to provide CAC-based authentication for business support applications and evaluate the NCAISS investment to support the SIPRNet and JWICS domains, provide enhanced identity and access control analytics. It will also incorporate any remaining DSS operated application into the DSS NCAISS solution.

</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:Title>Systems Enhancement</r2:Title>
                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>6.206</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>1. ODAA Business Management System (OBMS).  OBMS achieved its Initial Operational Capability (IOC) with development still continuing of the system in order to achieve Full Operational Capability (FOC) in FY2013.

2. Open Source Corporate Management Information System (OSCMIS).  Started configuration and customization of OSCMIS Phase 1 which consists of the manpower, training, and personnel modules.  

3. Industrial Security Facilities Database (ISFD).   Document requirements for further enhancements and additional capabilities for ISFD.  The work will be completed and implemented in FY2013.    
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:Funding>8.866</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text>1. ODAA Business Management System (OBMS). Deliver the Full Operational Capability (FOC) by deploying the final solution to the Defense Industrial Base (DIB) customers under the NISP. Completely modernizes the manual DSS security oversight and protection mission by automating the submission and management of System Security Plans (SSP) and Certification and Accreditation (C&amp;A) documentation.  This automation will allow DSS to more effectively oversee classified information in the hands of industry, improving mitigation and response to new and emerging threats to our cleared Industrial Base. Further additional capabilities beyond FOC will also be developed and implemented in FY2013/2014 timeframe.

2. Open Source Corporate Management Information System (OSCMIS).  Complete configuration and customization of OSCMIS Phase 1 which consists of the manpower, training, and personnel modules.  Develop and implement Phase 2 configuration and customization which consists of the Security and Continuity of Operations Planning (COOP) modules.  

3. Field Operations System (FOS).  Complete the functional and technical requirements, and develop the first functional prototype for the core system. 

4. DD 254.  Complete the functional and technical requirements, and develop and implement the system.  

5. Mobile Workforce Applications (MWA).  Research technical capabilities to implement mobile technologies to improve the efficacy of the DSS mission.  Complete the functional and technical requirements, and test prototypes.  
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:Funding>7.552</r2:Funding>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:Funding>7.552</r2:Funding>
                                            <r2:Text> 
1. Field Operations System (FOS). Continue development of FOS and implement the Full Operational Capability (FOC) of FOS by the end of the fiscal year.  

2. Mobile Workforce Applications (MWA).  Develop and deploy various solutions based on the prototypes researched in FY2013 in order to fulfill this capability.  

3. National Industrial Security Program (NISP) Control Access and Information Security System (NCAISS).  Accomplished migration from the IdM to its replacement since Oracle will no longer support the Sun IdM product in 2014. This will be a major upgrade to the IdM program. Once existing applications are interfaced with NCAISS and are transitioned; work on incorporating other DSS’s applications to the new platform will continue and be completed in FY2014.
</r2:Text>
                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>DSS will award a new Development Blanket Purchase Agreement (BPA) in Fiscal Year 2013 which will allow development of new applications, enhancement of other applications, and perform system integration with COTS and GOTS solutions and technology. These efforts will be issued as Task Orders under this BPA and will significantly reduce the lead time in contract award process and reduce overhead contract cost, improve technical solutions and deployments, and deliver more effective and efficient automation projects for DSS and the NISP community. </r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                            <r2:PerformanceMetrics>N/A

</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:R3Exhibit>
                            <r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                                <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                    <r2:Name>Product Development</r2:Name>
                                    <r2:Remarks>Specific Task Orders to be issued on DSS Development BPA are TBD.  </r2:Remarks>
                                    <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                            <r2:Name>Enterprise Security System</r2:Name>
                                            <r2:ContractMethod>C</r2:ContractMethod>
                                            <r2:ContractType>BPA</r2:ContractType>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>SAIC, Northrop Grumman, EDS</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Herndon, VA and Columbia, MD</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                <r2:TotalPreviousYears>79.560</r2:TotalPreviousYears>
                                                <r2:PriorYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>6.206</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:PriorYear>
                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:Amount>8.866</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:Amount>7.552</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                    <r2:Amount>7.552</r2:Amount>
                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                                <r2:TargetValue>Continuing</r2:TargetValue>
                                            </r2:Cost>
                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                    </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                            </r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                        </r2:R3Exhibit>
                        <r2:R4Exhibit>
                            <r2:ScheduleProfile>
                                <r2:ImageFileName>RDOC RealLast Page Chartnnn12 march 2013X.jpg</r2:ImageFileName>
                            </r2:ScheduleProfile>
                        </r2:R4Exhibit>
                    </r2:Project>
                </r2:ProjectList>
            </r2:ProgramElement>
        </r2:R2Exhibit>
    </r2:R2ExhibitList>
</jb:JustificationBook>